<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<root>

<totalfound>87</totalfound>

<totalsearched>3815492</totalsearched>

<document>

<rank>1</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A model of resource management in small cells with dynamic traffic and backhaul constraints]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bernal-Mor, Elena;  Pla, Vicent;  Martinez-Bauset, Jorge;  Pacheco-Paramo, Diego]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[During the last years, the volume of data-traffic carried by mobile cellular networks has experienced a major growth and progress. The current networks?? features are not enough to face this development paradigm and the novel concept of small cells has emerged to increase the network capacity. However, the deployment of small cells introduces several technical challenges such as the cross-tier interference between the macrocell and the small cells or the use of the land-line to send the backhaul data. In this paper, an analytical model is proposed to study the impact of the resource management on the small cell performance when the characteristics of the traffic vary dynamically over time. This model is applied in order to find the admission control policy which maximizes the throughput of the small cell users depending on the backhaul capacity variations and the interference produced by the users connected to the macrocell.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582775]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582775]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582775&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582775]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>2</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Analysis of Capacity and Error Ratio in 3GPP LTE Systems using Signal Flow Graph Models]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Chen, Yuan;  Walke, Bernhard]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A novel analytical framework is presented to evaluate capacity and error ratio of different protocol layers in 3GPP LTE systems. Signal flow graphs are used to model various aspects: On PHY layer, association of user terminal to a radio access point, probabilistic radio channel states, adaptive modulation and coding, overhead in LTE radio frame, turbo coded M-QAM block error rate, and Chase combining are taken into account. On MAC layer, hybrid-ARQ, resource assignment failure, and feedback misdetection are accounted for. On RLC layer, segmentation, selective repeat - ARQ, feedback loss, and timer for upcoming feedback are considered.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582819]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582819]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582819&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582819]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>3</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Cloud Services in Mobile Environments ?? The IU-ATC UK-India Mobile Cloud Proxy Function]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Oredope, Adetola;  McConnell, Aaron;  Peoples, Cathryn;  Singh, Reena;  Gonsalves, Timothy A.;  Moessner, Klaus;  Parr, Gerard P.]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Mobile networks currently play a key role in the evolution of the Internet due to exponential increase in demand for Internet-enabled mobile devices and applications. This has led to various demands to re-think basic designs of the current Internet architecture, investigating new and innovative ways in which key functionalities such as end-to-end connectivity, mobility, security, cloud services and future requirements can be added to its foundational core design. In this paper, we investigate, propose and design a functional element, known as the mobile cloud proxy, that enables the seamless integration and extension of core cloud services on the public Internet into mobile networks. The mobile cloud proxy function addresses current limitations in the deployment of cloud services in mobile networks tackling limitations such as dynamic resource allocation, transport protocols, application caching and security. This is achieved by leveraging advances in software-defined radios (SDRs) and networks (SDNs) to dynamically interface key functions within the mobile and Internet domains. We also present some early benchmarking results that feed into the development of the mobile cloud proxy to enable efficient use of resources for cloud based services such as social TV and crop imaging in mobile environments. The benchmarking experiments were carried out within the IU-ATC India-UK research project over a live international testbed which spans across a number of universities in the UK and India. Index Terms ?? Mobile, cloud, LTE, cloud proxy, social TV.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582831]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582831]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582831&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582831]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>4</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Coordinated Multi-point Joint Transmission with Partial Channel Information Feedback]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Makki, Behrooz;  Li, Jingya;  Eriksson, Thomas;  Svensson, Tommy]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper studies the data transmission efficiency of a coordinated multi-point (CoMP) network in the presence of partial channel state information (CSI). The system throughput is obtained in the case where the base stations are provided with a quantized channel phase information. Assuming slow-fading channels, discussions about the optimal quantization boundaries and adaptive power allocation are presented. Moreover, we demonstrate the equivalency of the quantized CSI scheme with a hybrid automatic repeat request protocol, in terms of throughput. Considerable performance improvement is observed with even a single bit feedback per user.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582782]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582782]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582782&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582782]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>5</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Downlink Ergodie System Capacity and RAU Placement in Cooperative Distributed Antenna Systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Yang, Xiaqing;  Zhao, Xinsheng]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Remote Antenna Unit (RAU) location in Distributed Antenna Systems (DAS) will influence the system capacity of wireless network. In this paper, the downlink ergodic system capacity for cooperative distributed antenna systems with multiple antennas RAUs in a composite fading channel was analyzed and an calculation algorithm was proposed for optimal placement of RAUs in cooperative distributed wireless network. Numerical results had verified correctness of analytical results of downlink ergodie system capacity and also showed that RAU location add a flexible factor for the spectrum efficiency enhancement. Index Tenns ?? System Capacity, RAU Location, Cooperative, Distributed Antenna Systems.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582807]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582807]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582807&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582807]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>6</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Distributed Mechanisms for Providing Complex Mobile Web Service]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[AlShahwan, Feda;  Carrez, Francois]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Simple mobile Web services can be provided directly from one device acting as a server. For more complex services, some of the execution tasks can be distributed to stationary devices or the execution tasks of the server and service logic can be migrated completely to another mobile host. Our approach goes beyond that and allows the partial distribution of the execution tasks and the service logic to other mobile hosts. An Extended Mobile Host Complex Web service Framework (EMHCWF) for providing complex Web services is defined. A Proof-of-concept demonstration is carried out to declare the feasibility of the framework and the running experimental tests examine the best suitable case scenario for partial distribution. Index Terms ?? Decomposing mobile Web services, distributed mobile Web service provision, RESTful-based mobile Web services, orchestrating mobile Web services.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582792]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582792]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582792&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582792]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>7</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Effective Service Capacity Analysis of Interference-Limited Multi-Carrier Wireless Systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Weyres, Marco;  Gross, James]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A good utilization of a wireless network while still ensuring QoS-constraints for all users is a hard challenge for service providers. Especially for admission control or handover decisions it is important to have a good approximation of the possible rate a user can achieve with respect to QoS parameters like delay or outage probabilities. Since fourth generation cellular networks utilize a frequency reuse of one, especially terminals at the cell edge suffer from inter-cell interference. In order to provide them with rates that guarantee specific QoS parameters without reserving too much resources, a good prediction of their possible rates is needed. Unfortunately, the prediction of the rates in an interference-limited cell is a complex and hard problem. Hence, it is a common way to simplify calculations by treating interference as additional noise in the used system models. In this paper we derive closed-form solutions for the delay distribution of interference-limited cells with respect to an OFDMA and a round robin scheduling approach. These distributions can be used to predict the possible rates of users given their average received transmitter gains, interferer gains and their QoS-constraints in a very accurate way. We validate our derivations and show that a simplification by treating interference as noise leads to an underestimation of rates which lowers the cell throughput. Furthermore, we show that due to the resulting equations, there is no way to derive the rates for interference limited cells in a linear way from easier solutions given by noise-limited cells.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582799]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582799]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582799&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582799]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>8</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Effect of Forward Error Correction Codes on the Performance of LDS-OFDM]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Razavi, Razieh;  Imran, Muhammad Ali;  Xiao, Pei;  Tafazolli, Rahim]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, selection criteria of Forward Error Correction (FEC) codes, in particular, the convolutional codes are evaluated for a novel air interface scheme, called Low Density Signature Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiple Access (LDS-OFDM). In this regard, the mutual information transfer characteristics of turbo Multiuser Detector (MUD) are investigated using Extrinsic Information Transfer (EXIT) charts. LDS-OFDM uses Low Density Signature structure for spreading the data symbols in frequency domain. This technique benefits from frequency diversity in addition to its ability of supporting parallel data streams more than the number of subcarriers (overloaded condition). The turbo MUD couples the data symbols?? detector of LDS scheme with users?? FEC decoders through the message passing principle. Index Terms ?? Low density signature, Multiuser detection, Iterative decoding.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582779]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582779]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582779&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582779]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>9</rank>

<title><![CDATA[GREEN-T (Green Terminals for Next Generation Wireless Systems): Survey and Progress]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Mumtaz, Shahid;  Radwan, Ayman;  Gomes, Alvaro;  Rodriguez, Jonathan]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[One of the biggest impediments of the future wireless communication systems is the need to reduce the energy consumption of mobile devices, which depend on batteries for their operations. GREEN-T will be the vehicle for tackling the problem of high energy requirement of beyond 3G mobile terminals, by dedicating its efforts towards saving energy on the mobile side, and especially addressing the energy dissipation for communication-related functions. This paper presents the initial progress of the GREEN-T project.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582752]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582752]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582752&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582752]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>10</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Excite CP wave for a Quad-unit]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Chang, The-Nan;  Lin, Jyun-Ming]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A circularly polarized 2x2 quad-unit antenna is presented. The quad-unit is excited by a square patch on a ground plane. Two square holes are cut on the ground plane and are located underneath one opposite corner of the fed-patch. Axial-ratio bandwidth of 11.5% centered at 5.5 GHz is achieved by adjusting the relative positions of the fed- patch, the apertures, and the quad-unit. Index Terms ?? Quad-unit, circular polarization, wide band]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582797]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582797]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582797&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582797]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>11</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Fractional Fourier Transform Modulation for Multiple Input Multiple Output Multicarrier Systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Anoh, K.O.O.;  Abd-Alhameed, R.A.;  Jones, S.M.R.;  Noras, J.M.;  Ghazaany, T.;  Dama, Y.A.S.]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A study of the Fractional Fourier Transform (FrFT) and wavelet packet transform (WPT) modulation schemes for Multiple Input Multiple Output (MIMO) multicarrier systems is presented. The implementation involves using the FrFT and WPT as the baseband multiplexing kernel, for multicarrier modulation. Using the Alamouti diversity technique a study of FrFT- and WPTMIMO multicarrier systems is studied. At first, we report consistent theoretical and simulated results with those in the original Alamouti work. Then, the scheme is implemented for WPT-MIMO and FrFT-MIMO cases with up to 2x2 receiver diversity. It will be shown that the diversity gain for FrFT is less than the diversity gain for WPT-MIMO modulation. Consequently, it would cost more transmit power to drive FrFT as a baseband multicarrier kernel than the WPT in MIMO systems. Keywords - Multiple Input Multiple Output (MIMO); Fractional Fourier Transform (FrFT); Wavelet Packet Transform (WPT); OFDM; Alamouti Space Time Block Coding (A-STBC).]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582837]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582837]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582837&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582837]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>12</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Network-Turbo-Coding based Cooperation with Distributed Space-Time Block Codes]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Chen, Bin;  Flanagan, Mark F.]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we propose a scheme to improve the performance of turbo-coded two-user cooperative uplink transmission. In the proposed scheme, each user transmits its partner??s second parity frame in addition to its own, using a network coded combination which is further protected by a space-time block code (STBC). The proposed system is simulated in slow and fast fading environments. Numerical simulation results indicate that for slow fading, the proposed scheme can yield up to 20% increase in data throughput compared to the traditional distributed turbo coding (DTC), while simultaneously providing a gain of 0.6dB in bit error rate (BER). This latter gain rises to approximately 2dB when a fast fading environment is considered.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582794]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582794]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582794&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582794]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>13</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Comparison of Three Vertical Refractivity Profiles In The Gulf Region]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[AbouAlmal, A.;  Abd-Alhameed, R.A.;  Hussaini, A.S.;  Ghazaany, T.;  Sharon, Z.;  Jones, S.M.R.;  Rodriguez, J.]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, a set of local radiosonde meteorological data, from 1990 to 2005, have been used to statistically analyze the refractivity gradient, DeltaN, at the lowest 65 m, 100 m and 1 km of the atmosphere above the surface of the Earth in the Gulf region. These three levels are the reference atmospheric layers in which the refractivity gradients have been evaluated by the ITU-R Recommendations P.453-10 and P.452-12.The vertical variations of the refractivity profile aredisplayed through the cumulative distributions of the refractivity gradients at the targeted levels. The obtained results are compared for the three layers and also compared with the estimated values in the ITU maps and tables when available. Index Terms ?? Atmospheric refraction, Refractivity gradient.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582835]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582835]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582835&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582835]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>14</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Implementing a Superwideband Codec for Smartphone VoIP Services]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Davies, Martyn;  Elwood, Dean;  Politis, Christos]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The growing popularity of Voice over IP (VoIP) services has allowed a number of important enhancements to basic voice services, including wideband codecs (coderdecoders) that allow higher fidelity audio to be efficiently transmitted. In addition, widespread use of smartphones has created an environment where such services can be rapidly adopted. This paper describes the implementation of Google??s iSAC wideband codec in an Apple Smartphone, as part of a commercial VoIP client created by Voxygen1. In addition, the paper summarizes some recent trends in the implementation of wideband codecs. Keywords ?? VoIP; wideband; mobile; speech; quality]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582791]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582791]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582791&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582791]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>15</rank>

<title><![CDATA[An energy efficient cooperative approach for anonymous wireless communications]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Sucasas, Victor;  Palacios, Raul;  Marques, Hugo;  Rodriguez, Jonathan;  Tafazolli, Rahim;  Granelli, Fabrizio]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The inherent characteristics of wireless communications pose great challenges to ensure anonymity during information exchange. When improving anonymity, it is also important to minimize the energy consumption of the proposed solution, since it is a fundamental requirement to prolong the network lifetime. To balance anonymity and energy consumption, this paper introduces a cooperative approach where selected nodes are formed into pairs to exchange both real and fake data before forwarding them to the Base Station (BS). The selection criterion of node pairs is based on a cross-layer method that considers the transmission rate, the traffic pattern and the intermodal distance to guarantee anonymity with minimum energy consumption. Thus, this prevents the attacker from inferring confidential information of the wireless communication system and saves energy at the network nodes. Comprehensive computer-based simulations were undertaken and the simulation results verify a noticeable energy saving in comparison with a not cooperative approach. Index Terms ?? Wireless, Anonymity, Energy Efficiency.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582769]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582769]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582769&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582769]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>16</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Intra-cell Overlay Opportunistic Spectrum Sharing By Employing 1-bit Feedback Beamforming]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Hou, Jiancao;  Ma, Yi;  Tafazolli, Rahim]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper aims to investigate an intra-cell overlay opportunistic spectrum sharing scheme by employing 1-bit feedback beamforming. The work of interests is that base station broadcasts independent signal messages to two relay stations (RS-1 and RS-2). RS-2 decodes the signal messages in subcell 2 and attempts to share the spectrum of sub-cell 1 for its own transmission. For this reason, RS-2 makes a deal with RS-1 in sub-cell 1 to help RS-1 send its signal messages. As presented in the paper, by employing 1-bit feedback transmit beamforming, RS-2 can further improve RS-1??s achievable rate and automatically eliminate the interference from RS-2 to subcell 1. Meanwhile, the achievable sum-rate upper bound of RS-2 is also analyzed.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582767]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582767]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582767&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582767]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>17</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Frequency Synchronization Performance of Algebraic Space Time Coded OFDM System within Correlated Channel]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bannour, Ahmed;  Sun, Yichuang]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This work studies the correlation effect on a new Algebraic Carrier Frequency Offset (CFO) estimation technique for multi-input multi-output (MIMO) orthogonal frequency divisionmultiplexing (OFDM) systems employing Algebraic Space Time Coding (ASTC), in quasi-static correlated Rayleigh frequency-selective fading channels. The technique uses a preamble and is thus especially suitable for burst mode communication. The preamble consists of orthogonal training sequences simultaneously transmitted from the various transmit antennas. Index Terms ?? Carrier frequency offset (CFO), channel estimation, frequency offset estimation, multiple-input multiple-output (MIMO), orthogonal frequency-division multiplexing (OFDM), Algebraic Space Time Coding (ASTC).]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582755]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582755]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582755&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582755]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>18</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Higher Order Horizontal Sectorisation Gains For a Real 3GPP/HSPA+ Network]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Joyce, Robert;  Zhang, Li]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents results from extensive simulation and real world deployment of higher order horizontal sectorisation (3, 6, 9, 12 and 15 sectors) when applied to a 3G/HSPA+ network in order to determine the downlink capacity gains available from this technique. Simulation results are presented for homogenous networks based upon a 3GPP HSPA/LTE network model in order to find the theoretical downlink capacity gains from higher order horizontal sectorisation and the optimum horizontal antenna beamwidth to maximise capacity without significantly reducing coverage and other network Key Performance Indicators. Further simulations have also been performed to ascertain the potential gain seen for Telefonica UK??s Central London 3G/HSPA+ network and these results have also been verified using live network field results from the deployment of six sector sites into Telefonica UK??s 3G/HSPA+ network. All results suggest that the gain is very much dependent on traffic location, but simulations and results from live network deployment of higher order sectorisation do verify that in the densest traffic locations higher order sectorisation does indeed provide a significant downlink capacity gain.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582764]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582764]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582764&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582764]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>19</rank>

<title><![CDATA[WHERE2 Location Aided Communications]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Dammann, Armin;  Agapiou, George;  Bastos, Joaquim;  Brunelk, Loic;  Garcia, Mariano;  Guillet, Julien;  Ma, Yi;  Ma, Junjie;  Nielsen, Jimmy J.;  Ping, Li;  Raulefs, Ronald;  Rodriguez, Jonathan;  Slock, Dirk;  Yang, Du;  Yi, Na]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents an overview of preliminary results of investigations within the WHERE2 Project [1] on identifying promising avenues for location aided enhancements to wireless communication systems. The wide ranging contributions are organized according to the following targeted systems: cellular networks, mobile ad hoc networks (MANETs) and cognitive radio. Location based approaches are found to alleviate significant signaling overhead in various forms of modern communication paradigms that are very information hungry in terms of channel state information at the transmitter(s). And this at a reasonable cost given the ubiquitous availability of location information in recent wireless standards or smart phones. Location tracking furthermore opens the new perspective of slow fading prediction.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582827]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582827]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582827&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582827]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>20</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Distributed Joint Source-Channel-Network Coding Exploiting Source Correlation for Multiple Access Relay Channel]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Zhou, Xiaobo;  Lim, Azman Osman;  Anwar, Khoirul;  Matsumoto, Tad]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we consider the problem of transmitting correlated binary sources over multiple access relay channel (MARC). The network consists of two sources communicating with the same destination with the assistance of a single relay. The source sequences are independently channel encoded and broadcasted to the relay and the destination. After successfully receiving the information sequences from the two sources, the relay generates joint channel-network coded sequence and forwards it to the destination. A joint source-channel-network (JSCN) decoding technique is proposed to fully exploit the correlation between the sources, as well as the benefit of network coding. Furthermore, the achievable rate region and the theoretical limits of this system are derived by combining the Shannon and source coding with side information theorems. Simulation results show that, by exploiting the source correlation, our proposed technique achieves significant performance gain, compared with the case that the correlation knowledge is not exploited.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582778]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582778]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582778&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582778]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>21</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Multi-antenna OFDM channel feedback compression exploiting sparsity]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Wild, Thorsten;  Hoek, Cornelis;  Herzog, Guenther;  Koppenborg, Johannes]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In order to enable advanced downlink multiantenna techniques, like MU-MIMO or Network MIMO, accurate channel knowledge at the transmitter is required. In order to save scarce uplink resources, the feedback has to be compressed. This paper provides a practical channel feedback compression technique which exploits the sparse nature of radio channels and removes redundant and irrelevant information. It introduces a novel path detection algorithm by modifying the existing orthogonal matching pursuit algorithm. Furthermore it presents efficient practical bit loading techniques. Channel aging effects can be efficiently handled by prediction, as shown in this paper. The prediction integrates very well into the presented feedback compression framework. For application to existing radio propagation channel compression, measurement results are discussed, dealing with the question how sparse the actual channel is.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582753]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582753]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582753&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582753]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>22</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Performance analysis of Dual-hop Multi-relaying System over Rayleigh plus Log-normal Fading Channel]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[An, John F.;  Huang, Hsin-Yin;  Huang, Shih-Hsin]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Up-to-date the log-normal fading effect is still not fully studied for the relaying system because its underlying statistics generally does not lead to a closed-form expression. In this paper, we proposed an analytical frame work for the performance analysis of dual-hop multi-relaying over indoor Rayleigh plus log-normal (composite) fading channel, where the selected relaying link has end-to-end power constraint. Thus, we first derive a closed-form expression of outage probability under conditioned constraint that relaying end-to-end power has much larger signal-to-noise (SNR) level ( 1 chi ) relative to the targeted threshold (chiT ) ;chi &#x003E;&#x003E; chi T 1 , then investigate the bit-error-rate (BER) performance, with a variety of shadowing standard deviations. The closed-form expressions allow rapid calculation of system performances in terms of the shadowing standard deviation, relative end-to-end relaying SNR and a number of relay nodes. This was not possible previously. Numerical analyses, in comparison with the asymptotic results from accurate solutions with non-closed form, demonstrated that our proposed scheme provides a simple and efficient approach to evaluate the impact of the shadowing effect and thus analytical optimization and relaying output power margin becomes feasible in real system design applications. Keywords ?? Rayleigh fading, log-normal fading, dual-hop multi-relaying, outage probability, log-normal standard deviation.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582754]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582754]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582754&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582754]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>23</rank>

<title><![CDATA[LTE Uplink Extension in TV White Spaces]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Lopez-Benitez, Miguel;  Moessner, Klaus]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Dynamic Spectrum Access (DSA)/Cognitive Radio (CR) represents a promising and versatile concept to improve the efficiency of spectrum exploitation by allowing unlicensed users to opportunistically access underutilised licensed bands, provided that no harmful interference is caused to the legitimate (licensed) users of the spectrum. This revolutionary spectrum access paradigm can be exploited not only to deploy new radio systems and technologies in the already allocated spectrum, but also to increase the capacity of existing systems. A good example of this application is the extension of Long Term Evolution (LTE) cellular systems in TeleVision (TV) white spaces (i.e., TV channels not used in a certain region), which has received significant attention. Most of the existing studies, however, have focused on the extension of the LTE downlink component. By contrast, this work complements previous studies by considering the LTE uplink component in TV white spaces. By means of system-level simulations, this work analyses the conditions under which such coexistence is feasible and the underlying implications.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582805]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582805]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582805&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582805]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>24</rank>

<title><![CDATA[An Improved Inter-cell Interference Coordination (ICIC) for OFDMA multi-cell systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Kosta, Chrysovalantis;  Hunt, Bernard;  Quddus, Atta U.;  Tafazolli, Rahim]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we propose an improved Inter-Cell Interference Coordination (ICIC) for emerging multi-cell wireless systems. The ICIC provided in this paper gives a proper inter-cell resource allocation by employing the concept of interference avoidance and describes the inter-relationship of all base stations in a holistic way. We use a semi-centralized ICIC scheme which divides the global optimum problem into a multicell and multi-user problem. Our performance metrics are the aggregate sector throughput and the critical throughput of a multi-cell system. The critical throughput is defined as the 5th percentile of the aggregate user throughput. Simulation results confirm the increased effectiveness of the proposed ICIC in both metrics over a number of state-of-the-art interference avoidance schemes. Keywords - component; Inter-cell RRM; Semi-centralized RRM; Linear/Binary Optimization; Inter-Cell Interference Coordination.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582757]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582757]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582757&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582757]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>25</rank>

<title><![CDATA[The Time-Domain Enhanced Inter-Cell Interference Coordination in Heterogeneous Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Zhang, Deliang;  Kang, Shaoli;  Peng, Ying;  Wang, Yingmin;  Sun, Zhili]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In order to enhance the cell coverage performance and achieve the higher spectral efficiency, 3GPP studied the new network deployment of Heterogeneous Networks (HetNets) for LTE-Advanced and has completed relevant work items [1]. In cochannel HetNet, Macros and low power nodes (LPNs), such as Femto, Pico and Relay, are deployed with overlapped coverage. For Macro/Pico scenarios, the Cell Range Expansion (CRE) scheme is utilized to offload heavy traffic from Macro cells [2]. However, due to imbalanced transmitting power, the interference between two layers of nodes is challenging, mainly Pico UEs suffer a severe DL interference. The time-domain enhanced inter-cell interference coordination (eICIC) method is one of the key solutions standardized in 3GPP [3-6], while proper design of almost blank subframes (ABS) pattern is left to implementation. In this paper, a novel configuration scheme is proposed for ABS pattern, particularly applied in TD-LTE-Advanced [7]. Evaluation results show that with the proper configuration of ABS pattern, a minimum 16% gain on throughput can be achieved for Pico. Although resource reduction can affect the throughput of Macros, the average system performance remains increasing under the scenarios of one Pico per Macro cell. Keywords ?? Heterogeneous Networks, Cell Range Expansion, eICIC]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582768]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582768]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582768&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582768]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>26</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Energy Efficient Base Station Placement and Operation in Mobile Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Komnakos, Dimitris;  Rouskas, Angelos;  Gotsis, Antonis]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Optimal planning and management of resources for reducing operational costs of energy consumption and the equivalent environmental footprint in mobile communication networks have gathered increasing interest in the recent research literature. In this paper, we deal with the problem of base station placement and planning in a mobile network and propose a practical algorithm for achieving the above goal of energy consumption minimization. Usage cases of this algorithm are investigated via a simulation campaign, where the results are compared with the optimum solution derived by means of exhaustive search. Our evaluation depicts that the proposed approach exhibits a near-optimum performance under all scenarios of interest examined. Keywords ?? energy efficiency; network design; wireless networks; green communications]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582788]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582788]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582788&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582788]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>27</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Energy Efficiency Analysis for LTE Macro-Femto HetNets]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Saeed, Arsalan;  Akbari, Amir;  Dianati, Mehrdad;  Imran, Muhammad Ali]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents a simulation based energy consumption analysis of a heterogeneous network (HetNet) consisting of Long Term Evolution (LTE) macro-cells and LTE femto-cells. Two potential areas of energy savings are evaluated, namely, sleep modes and spectrum assignment. Sleep modes are demonstrated with practical component level power models, resulting considerable energy savings. Three spectrum allocation scenarios are considered: A) macro and femto nodes with frequency reuse 1 (no coordination), B) macro and femto nodes with frequency reuse 2, and dedicated femto channel with reuse 1, C) reduced bandwidth macro and femto nodes with frequency reuse 2, and dedicated femto channel with reuse 1. The three mentioned scenarios are also compared against an ideal case, i.e. when nodes experience no interference. Our analysis indicate that static partitioning of spectrum is highly energy inefficient and calls for a need to develop dynamic frequency domain intercell interference coordination techniques for HetNets. Index Terms ?? Femto Access Points, Energy Efficiency, Evolved Packet Core.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582808]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582808]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582808&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582808]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>28</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Capacity of a Cellular Network with D2D Links]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ferrante, Steven;  Zhang, Qian;  Raghothaman, Balaji]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Cellular controlled direct UE to UE (User Equipment) communications represent a rich area for research and development that includes topics such as public safety, new social applications, as well as enhancing cellular coverage and capacity. Much of the work is motivated by the growth in wireless data demand, and the expected explosion of new uses of cellular technology. Our study extends the traditional cellular topology to enable direct path links (DPLs) between UEs for local discovery and communication, referred to as device-to-device communication. Local traffic offloading can be used for social networking, wireless gaming, machine type communication, as well as for public safety. We present system throughput results using Monte Carlo simulation techniques for a system which enables the DPLs. Our results indicate that the mean system capacity could be improved by more than 200% by using direct path UE communications as an enhancement to traditional cellular systems, such as LTE. Index Terms?? LTE, D2D communications, Capacity, Local traffic offload, MIMO]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582762]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582762]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582762&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582762]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>29</rank>

<title><![CDATA[MIMO Broadcast and Interference Channels with Location based Partial CSIT]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Slock, Dirk]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Multiple antennas facilitate the coexistence of multiple users in wireless communications, leading to spatial multiplexing and spatial division and to significant system capacity increase. However, this comes at the cost of very precise channel state information at the transmitters (CSIT). We advocate the use of channel propagation models to transform location information into (possibly incomplete) CSIT. We investigate the resulting multi-user sum rate from a DoF (Degree of Freedom, high SNR rate prelog, spatial multiplexing factor) point of view. For singlecell multi-user communications, we argue for a revival of SDMA (Spatial Division Multiple Access). In the MIMO case, the receive antennas can suppress the Non Line of Sight (NLoS) channel components to transform the MIMO channel into a MISO LoS channel, allowing the CSIT to be limited to LoS information. For the multi-cell problem, we consider the feasibility of interference aligment in the case of reduced rank MIMO channels. We then focus on the LoS components. Whereas in general MIMO multicell coordinated beamforming, the transmitters require global CSIT due to the coupling between transmit and receive filters, in the LoS case decoupling arises, permitting location based transmit beamforming. We also discuss the transceiver design based on Partial LoS CSIT by essentially maximizing a weighted sum rate at finite SNR and finite Ricean factor.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582828]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582828]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582828&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582828]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>30</rank>

<title><![CDATA[An Integrated Platform for Source Detection, Identification and Localization with Applications to Cognitive-Radio]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Dagres, Ioannis;  Polydoros, Andreas;  Denkovski, Daniel;  Rakovic, Valentin;  Atanasovski, Vladimir;  Gavrilovska, Liljana;  Cichon, Krzysztof;  Kliks, Adrian;  Baban, Shaswar;  Holland, Oliver]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The creation of an integrated statistical-inference platform is proposed within the context of the Acropolis Network of Excellence. This platform will address aspects related to source detection, identification and localization, techniques useful in wireless-network coexistence and opportunistic spectral access. Its purpose is to integrate algorithms related to these topics under a common framework. The integration of such algorithms and the adoption of a common simulation/experimentation platform for assessing all related research will therefore be the main target of this project. The present paper is a first step of this effort, where all related algorithmic solutions available within Acropolis are presented and compared with the state of the art. The architecture of an existing experimental platform already employed for assessing some of the proposed solutions is also described. Index Terms ?? Detection, Identification, Localization.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582833]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582833]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582833&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582833]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>31</rank>

<title><![CDATA[How to Test IoT-based Services before Deploying them into Real World]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Reetz, Eike Steffen;  Kuemper, Daniel;  Moessner, Klaus;  Toenjes, Ralf]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Efficient testing of Internet of Things (IoT)-based services suffers from the underlying heterogeneous nature of IoT resources and hinders the process of rapid service creation and deployment. Real world effects, based on the behaviour of IoT-based services, tend to prevent the straight forward execution within the productive environment. Current solutions for testbeds, involving physical or virtual IoT resources, appear to require intense capacities for time and resources. This paper describes a new approach for testing IoT-based service build on a code insertion methodology, which can be derived from the semantic description of the IoT-based service. The proposed IoT resource emulation interface is described from the semantic, architectural and implementation perspective. The paper compares its applicability and efficiency with classical approaches and expose high emulation capabilities while minimising the testing effort. Index Terms ?? functional testing; model-based testing; stream X-Machine; semantic test derivation]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582811]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582811]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582811&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582811]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>32</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Indoor TDOA Mobile Positioning with Clock Drift and Its Cram??er-Rao Bound]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[He, Ziming;  Ma, Yi;  Tafazolli, Rahim]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The paper presents a time-difference-of-arrival (TDOA) position estimation algorithm for indoor positioning in the present of clock drift in a mobile terminal. Then, a new Cram??er-Rao bound is derived as a benchmark of the algorithm. The simulation results show that an acceptable positioning accuracy can be achieved when at least five access points in wireless local area networks are involved in positioning. Moreover, when the clock drift or the TDOA is considerably large, the proposed algorithm outperforms the algorithm without considering the clock drift. Index Terms ?? Positioning, time-difference-of-arrival (TDOA), clock error, clock drift, Cram??er-Rao bound (CRB)]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582826]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582826]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582826&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582826]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>33</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A DCO Gain Estimation Algorithm for Digital Phase Locked Loops]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Li, Jing;  Hagelauer, Richard;  Mayer, Thomas;  Tertinek, Stefan;  Wicpalek, Christian;  Neurauter, Burkhard]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[An adaptive DCO (Digital Controlled Oscillator) gain tracking algorithm for an ADPLL (All Digital Phase Locked Loops), which is working as a frequency synthesizer, is presented in this paper. By using this DCO gain real-time tracking method, the requirement of DCO linearity and the complexity of the circuits can be highly decreased. The result shows that with introducing a small amount of training signal the actual DCO gain can be accurately estimated in short time with a fine resolution and the EVM (Error Vector Magnitude) performance is improved significantly. Index Terms ?? DCO Gain Estimation, All Digital Phase Locked Loops, Adaptive Tracking]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582773]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582773]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582773&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582773]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>34</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Directional Hidden Markov Model for Indoor Tracking of Mobile Users and Realistic Case Study]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Nielsen, Jimmy Jessen;  Amiot, Nicolas;  Madsen, Tatiana K.]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Indoors, mobile users tend to exhibit some level of determinism in their movement patterns during a day, for example when arriving to their office, going for coffee, going for lunch break, picking up print outs, etc. In this work we exploit this determinism to improve the accuracy of indoor localization systems. We consider two Hidden Markov Model (HMM) based filtering algorithms that use previous observations to estimate a user??s most likely movement trajectory, given a sequence of inaccurate location coordinates. The proposed Directional HMM algorithm is able to learn user habits by discriminating between different movement directions when populating the state transition probability matrix from training data. The proposed algorithm is compared to a Standard HMM algorithm that does not distinguish different movement directions. Evaluation results for a simple test scenario with two oppositely intersecting trajectories demonstrated a significant improvement of location accuracy with the Directional HMM algorithm. Further results for a scenario with realistic simulation based movement trajectories also showed improvements for 60% of the cases, however only if the HMM models are trained with usually unknown true trajectories. When trained with inaccurate location estimations, the HMM based algorithms showed no benefit compared to just using the localization system.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582825]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582825]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582825&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582825]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>35</rank>

<title><![CDATA[P-CSMA: A Priority-Based CSMA Protocol for Multi-Hop Linear Wireless Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Buratti, Chiara;  Verdone, Roberto]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we consider a multi-hop wireless network, where a source transmits data to a destination node, through a route composed of multiple relays which are randomly distributed over a line. Priority-based Carrier-Sense Multiple Access (P-CSMA), a novel Medium Access Control (MAC) protocol, is proposed. According to the protocol, when accessing the radio channel different levels of priority are assigned to nodes, depending on their positions in the route: nodes closer to the destination have higher priority with respect to those closer to the source. The priority in the access to the channel is managed by assigning to nodes different durations of the sensing phase. This mechanism speeds up the transmission of packets which are already in the route, making the transmission flow more efficient. Results show that P-CSMA outperforms existing contention-basedMAC protocols, like p-persistent CSMA and Slotted ALOHA. A mathematical model to derive the performance in terms of packet success probability and average throughput is also provided. The model represents an effective tool for the performance analysis of multi-hop CSMA-based wireless networks, when accounting for interference, due to the hidden terminal node problem.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582822]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582822]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582822&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582822]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>36</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Economic Evaluation of Rural Broadband and Machine-to-Machine Deployments in TV Whitespaces]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Mackenzie, Richard;  Groendalen, Ole;  Lehne, Per H.]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents a business case analysis for two scenarios that could be deployed in TV whitespaces: one scenario looks at providing broadband to rural areas, the other looks at providing the infrastructure for a machine-to-machine network. Both business cases would provide a positive net present value over a ten year period using the assumed values for revenue and costs. The risk for both business cases is identified using a sensitivity analysis for some of the key assumed values. The key values for both business cases would be the number of customers and the average revenue per customer. This paper also describes some of the other key issues that must be satisfied before a network operator could consider deploying either of these scenarios.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582789]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582789]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582789&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582789]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>37</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A DS-UWB Radar System With a Short Correlation Processing Time]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Lee, Youngpo;  Shim, Jeongyoon;  Lee, Youngseok;  Lee, Jaewoo;  Yoon, Seokho]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[3]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we propose a direct sequence ultra wideband (DS-UWB) radar system which estimates a distance between the radar and an object with a short correlation processing time. Unlike conventional DS-UWB radar systems using multiple variable length pseudo noise (PN) sequences, the proposed radar employs a short-length PN sequence reducing the correlation processing time by virtue of correlation accumulation which averages out the noise in the correlator outputs. Numerical results show that the proposed DS-UWB radar estimates the distance with a shorter correlation processing time while providing a better estimation performance compared with the conventional DS-UWB radar systems.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582787]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582787]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582787&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582787]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>38</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Network Coding for Vertical Handoffs Between LTE and IEEE 802.11n: An Energy Perspective]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bassoli, Riccardo;  Marques, Hugo;  Rodriguez, Jonathan;  Vahid, Seiamak;  Tafazolli, Rahim]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Wireless networks are evolving into a unique heterogeneous scenario. Moreover, mobile terminals with multiple wireless interfaces have the ability to roam between different access networks. Allowing seamless and efficient vertical handoffs is becoming a key requirement for future wireless environments. We discuss the application of recent kind of network codes called batched sparse (BATS) codes on HARD vertical handoffs between LTE and IEEE 802.11n to reduce packet loss and to increase performances. The first part of our analysis demonstrates a reduction of packet loss by applying network coding. However, the second part shows that the redundancy of the codes increases the energy per bit consumed by mobile terminals. Index Terms ?? Network coding, LTE, IEEE 802.11n, vertical handoffs, energy consumption.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582771]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582771]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582771&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582771]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>39</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Power Gain of Large Multi-User and Multi-Antenna Systems under Adaptive ZF Transmission]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Yue, Dian-Wu;  Sun, Yichuang]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we investigate adaptive zero-forcing (ZF) transmission for multi-user multi-antenna (MUMA) systems in fading environments. We assume that the number of antennas at the base station (BS) is greater than the number of users with each having single antenna, and power control can be done at the transmitter(s) as channel condition changes. Under constraints of individual rates and maximum transmit powers, we adopt the optimal transmit strategy of minimizing the average total transmit power (ATTP). We derive and give closed-form ATTP expressions under short-term rate constraints for real-time communications. When the individual maximum transmit powers are allowed to be infinite, we analyze deeply relationship among the ATTP, the numbers of BS antennas and users in order to get an insight into the power benefit provided by the MUMA system over a single-user and single-antenna (SUSA) system. Our theoretical analysis shows that a large MUMA system can obtain stable and satisfying performance by dynamically changing the number of antennas at the BS. Moreover, we present a simple adaptive transmission scheme with trinary power control satisfying short-term rate constraints. Index Terms ?? Average total transmit power, multi-user, multiantenna, zero-forcing, very large MIMO.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582772]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582772]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582772&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582772]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>40</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Planning Future Cellular Networks: A Generic Framework for Performance Quantification]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Imran, Ali;  Yaacoub, Elias;  Dawy, Zaher;  Abu-Dayya, Adnan]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The new pressing expectations from emerging cellular systems such as energy efficiency, heterogeneity of cell sizes and base station types, focus shift to capacity from coverage, and demand for homogeneity of service provided in the coverage area, have increased the need for intelligent and optimal cellular system planning more than ever. While large number of works in literature have focused on various aspects of cell planning for legacy and emerging cellular systems, a common strategy to take into account these new born requirements by formulating them as function of underlying planning parameters, is missing so far, making the research on planning next generation cellular system sporadic. In this paper we address this problem and present a novel framework that can facilitate holistic planning of future cellular system by embodying these requirements through a unified and interrelated set of metrics to reflect the key performance indicators. These metrics can be used to quantify performance of cellular system plan in terms of major deployment parameters of interest. We use an extensive set of numerical results to demonstrate the effectiveness of proposed framework. These results also provide useful insights into the key trade offs involved in planning of emerging cellular networks and thus can facilitate future research in this area. Index Terms ?? Holistic Cell planning; Performance Quantification; Capacity; Quality of Service; Energy Efficiency]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582804]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582804]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582804&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582804]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>41</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Random-based Fair Allocation Algorithm with Fuzzy Comprehensive Evaluation for Single Carrier Multi-Relay Cooperative Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Eghbali, H.;  Abualhaol, I.;  Muhaidat, S.;  Iraqi, Y.]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we investigate a novel random selection strategy for dual-hop Single-Carrier Frequency-Domain Equalization (SC-FDE) in cooperative systems with multiple relays and amplify-and-forward relaying employing fuzzy comprehensive evaluation-based algorithm. We address the problem of optimal resource allocation for SC-FDE minimum mean square error (MMSE) receivers. In particular, the relays cooperate according to contribution factors which are the result of the fuzzy comprehensive evaluation algorithm. The fuzzy algorithm takes into consideration different fuzzy factors, namely, norm-based selection ratio (NBSR), instantaneous capacity-based selection ratio (CBSR), singular value based selection ratio (SVSR), and equalizer output signal quality-based selection ratio (EQSR) strategies, which are motivated by minimizing the instantaneous error rate. Different sub-channels are further associated with uniform random distribution where the thresholds of the uniform random variables are associated with the contribution factors (evaluated through the fuzzy algorithm). Our novel Random fair allocation fuzzy comprehensive evaluation-based (RFCE) strategy proves superior SER performance as well as improved diversity gain which is achieved by randomizing the allocation. The employed fuzzy algorithm further improves the performance by assigning partial weights to different participating fuzzy factors.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582813]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582813]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582813&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582813]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>42</rank>

<title><![CDATA[MIMO Wavelet Multicarrier System Using Feedback Circuit]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Asif, R.;  Hussaini, A.S.;  Abd-Alhameed, R.A.;  Elfergani, I.T.E.;  Jones, S.M.R.;  Noras, J.M.;  Ghazaany, T.;  Rodriguez, J.]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this work we have studied the performance of MIMO-DWT based multicarrier system using the feedback circuit from the receiver to the transmitter to understand the channel state information (CSI) and to create a steering matrix in order to constructively combine the received signal at the receiver which provides the advantage of keeping the burden of processing at the transmitter which has more power and less constraints. Index Terms ?? MIMO wavelet, Beamforming, Wavelet multicarrier system, Closed Loop.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582836]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582836]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582836&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582836]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>43</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Cognitive Spectrum Portfolio Optimisation, Approaches and Exploitation]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Karla, Ingo;  Bito, Janos;  Bochow, Bernd;  Celentano, Ulrico;  Csurgai-Horvath, Laszlo;  Groensund, Pael;  Lopez-Benitez, Miguel;  Samano-Robles, Ramiro]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A major challenge for cooperative cognitive radio networks is the creation and optimisation of a suitable spectrum portfolio, utilised by the radio nodes in the process of dynamic spectrum management. This paper presents several optimisation approaches for spectrum portfolios. Their characteristics are discussed regarding a variety of different scenarios, and it is shown how different approaches can complement each other to optimise the overall spectrum management, in particular considering spectrum portfolio optimisation under mobility and QoS constraints. Special consideration of upcoming TV whitespace communication use cases is shown in this discussion. Index Terms ?? Spectrum portfolio, dynamic spectrum management, TV white space, self-organising networks, quality of service, mobility.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582830]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582830]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582830&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582830]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>44</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Opportunistic Space Time Code for Four-relay Network]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Abu-Hudrouss, Ammar M.;  Burr, Alister G.]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper investigates the use of opportunistic Space Time codes with a decode and forward protocol in cooperative networks. CRC code is applied on the message at the source. At each relay, only the correctly received message block is retransmitted. We demonstrate that this cooperative protocol prevents propagation of error and optimizes the diversity order depending on the channel status and available transmit power. Index Terms ?? Distributed Space Time codes; Virtual MIMO; QOSTBC; STBC.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582795]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582795]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582795&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582795]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>45</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Packet Transmission for Multiservice Cognitive Radio Networks with Finite Buffer Capacity]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Sibomana, Louis;  Zepernick, Hans-Juergen;  Tran, Hung;  Ngoga, Said Rutabayiro]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we analyze the secondary network transmission given a packet timeout threshold and a target bit error rate (BER) in a downlink multiservice spectrum sharing cognitive radio network (CRN). Under the joint constraint of primary user (PU) outage probability and secondary user (SU) peak transmit power, the adaptive transmit power policy of the SU transmitter (SU-Tx) is obtained. The throughput is maximized by transmitting to the secondary receiver (SU-Rx) having the best channel condition. We maintain fairness with a minimum resource guarantee assigned to each packet of a class of service. Accordingly, the average packet transmission time is determined. In addition, employing an M/G/1/B queueing model, the packet blocking probability is given to develop expressions of the average throughput and packet loss probability for the secondary class of service. Moreover, the quality of experience (QoE) is evaluated based on the relationship between the packet loss probability and mean opinion score (MOS). The results show that the secondary network achieves the stable transmission quality and minimizes packet loss when the number of SU-Rx becomes large.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582803]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582803]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582803&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582803]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>46</rank>

<title><![CDATA[First Iteration Policies for Admission Control in Multiaccess Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Pacheco-Paramo, Diego;  Martinez-Bauset, Jorge;  Pla, Vicent;  Bernal-Mor, Elena]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This work explores approximate methods to solve Markov decision processes for large systems through Policy iteration. Two methods, one using an embedded discrete time Markov chain and the other using time scale separation, are defined and compared with the solution obtained using traditional Policy iteration. First step solutions are found and compared for a radio resource management problem with two radio access technologies and two service types. The approaches proposed considerably reduce the computational cost while closely approximate the optimal solution. The solutions are extended by increasing the number of steps of policy iteration and results show that it is possible to reach the performance of the optimal policy when several steps are required reducing the computational cost.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582785]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582785]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582785&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582785]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>47</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On the Energy Efficiency of MIMO Channels in Correlated Rayleigh Fading Environment]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Jiang, Jing;  Dianati, Mehrdad;  Imran, Muhammad Ali;  Tafazolli, Rahim]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper investigates the energy efficiency (EE) performance for multiple-input multiple-output (MIMO) systems in correlated Rayleigh fading environment. Taking into account a realistic power model, we derive a closed-form upper bound for the system EE as a function of SE, which shows a good accuracy for a wide range of SE values, in the presence of spatial fading correlation at both the transmitter and the receiver sides. The upper bound helps the system explicitly track the influence of SE on EE and the effects of spatial correlation. Results demonstrate that given a fixed number of transmit and receive antennas, there exists a certain region of SE that corresponds to better EE performance. Results also indicate that when the circuit power dominates EE, EE is more tolerant to the spatial fading correlation; in contrast, when the transmit power becomes more dominant, EE is more sensitive to the changes of correlation coefficient.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582806]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582806]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582806&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582806]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>48</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Finding Partially Link-Disjoint Paths in Wireless Sensor Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Seymour, Zachary;  Kar, Dulal]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Routing in wireless sensor networks provides an interesting problem distinct from typical network routing. Due to features such as omnidirectional antennas, finite battery power, and wireless multicast, new shortest path algorithms must be developed to accommodate the benefits and disadvantages of using these networks. We propose a technique for finding partially linkdisjoint paths in wireless ad-hoc networks. Our primary result is an algorithm for producing such paths. This algorithm adapts existing node- and link-disjoint path algorithms to reuse nodeto- node links. By successively removing the link with the lowest energy cost from the path, we can iteratively build a partially link-disjoint path. Our results show that this technique achieves significant energy savings over other node-disjoint or fully linkdisjoint routing algorithms. These findings seem to indicate that, while removal of this link may detract from short-term energy savings, overall energy savings are increased in the long-term. In addition, we present alternative link-removal techniques and their potential applications and usefulness. Finally, we address some potential issues with these types of paths and their utility in the greater problem of ad-hoc network routing. These algorithms provide an alternative to traditional disjoint path algorithms for wireless ad-hoc networks and attempt to address the problems that arise from using partially disjoint paths.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582751]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582751]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582751&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582751]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>49</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Coordinated Dynamic Antenna Tilt &amp; Scheduling in a Central London LTE Network]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Joyce, Robert;  Zhang, Li;  Barker, David]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The aim of this paper is to examine the benefits of rapid dynamic tilting antennas when applied to a deployed 4G/Long Term Evolution (LTE) cellular network. Earlier work has shown benefits from this novel Self Organising Network (SON) technique when applied to simple small scale homogeneous network configurations however this paper evaluates the technique on a real Central London 4G/LTE network with non-ideal site placement. The potential network performance improvement of this technique when applied to an LTE network employing Round Robin, Maximum C/I and Proportional Fair downlink scheduling is evaluated using a Monte Carlo WCDMA/LTE Macro Network Simulator. The results suggest significant performance and capacity gains of approximately 25% are possible for a real LTE network configuration and align well to those found for the homogeneous network case.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582759]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582759]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582759&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582759]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>50</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Mutual Information Based Packet Scheduling for Linearly Precoded Multiuser MIMO Systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Xiao, Pei;  Lin, Zihuai;  Wu, Yi]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we present a novel Mutual Information (MI) based spatial frequency domain packet scheduling for downlink Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiple Access (OFDMA) multiuser MIMO systems. The proposed scheduler is designed to exploit the available multiuser diversity in time, frequency and spatial domains. The analysis model is based on the generalized 3GPP LTE downlink transmission for which two Spatial Division Multiplexing (SDM) multiuser MIMO schemes are investigated: Single User (SU) and Multi-user (MU) MIMO schemes. The results show that the proposed MU-MIMO scheduler is a more realistic solution and provides fairness among users for the system under consideration.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582780]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582780]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582780&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582780]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>51</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Antenna Pattern Shift Keying Modulation for MIMO Channels]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ramirez-Gutierrez, Raymundo;  Zhang, Li;  Elmirghani, Jaafar]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Antenna pattern shift keying (APSK) modulation is a low-complexity scheme for multiple antenna wireless systems. In this paper, APSK modulation is introduced to convey information jointly by a general phase modulation, the indices of transmitter antennas and antenna beam patterns to improve the spectral efficiency and reliability while keeping the detection simple. The idea behind this transmission technique is to map the bit vector corresponding to one symbol in three information carrying blocks: the first block determines the active antenna indices, the second maps to the antenna beam patterns and the third block maps to the conventional amplitude/phase modulation (APM) symbols. APSK modulation combines two novel schemes: generalized phase spatial shift keying (GPSSK) modulation which exploits the antenna indices and the other scheme called antenna beam pattern modulation (ABPM) which uses the beam patterns to carry information. The receiver estimates these three blocks which are used to de-map the signal. The performance of this method is evaluated in terms of bit error rate (BER) and throughput.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582818]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582818]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582818&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582818]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>52</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Spectrum Utilization Efficiency Analysis in Cognitive Radio Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Tang, Wuchen;  Imran, Muhammad Ali;  Tafazolli, Rahim]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In cognitive radio network, secondary (unlicensed) users (SUs) are allowed to utilize the licensed spectrum when it is not used by the primary (licensed) users (PUs). Because of the dynamic nature of cognitive radio network, the activities of SUs such as ??how long to sense?? and ??how long to transmit?? significantly affect both the service quality of the cognitive radio networks and protection to PUs. In this work, we formulate and analyze spectrum utilization efficiency problem in the cognitive radio network with various periodic frame structure of SU, which consists of sensing and data transmission slots. Energy detection is considered for spectrum sensing algorithm. To achieve higher spectrum utilization efficiency, the optimal sensing and data transmission length are investigated and found numerically. The simulation results are presented to verify the our analysis and to evaluate the interference to the PU which should be controlled into tolerable level. Index Terms ?? Cognitive radio network; spectrum utilization efficiency; spectrum sensing; energy detection; frame structure.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582776]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582776]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582776&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582776]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>53</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Study of the TDOA Assisted RSSD Localization with UWB in Real Indoor Environment]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Gerok, Waldemar;  Peissig, Juergen;  Kaiser, Thomas]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper localization with Ultra-Wideband (UWB) technology based on fingerprinting approach using Received Signal Strength Difference (RSSD) is studied. Localization is assisted with single Time Difference of Arrival (TDOA) measurement. Position estimation is done using real measurement data. Index Terms ?? Localization, UWB, RSS, RSSD, TDOA]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582821]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582821]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582821&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582821]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>54</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Low complexity MIMO Order and Transmit Antenna Subset Selection in Correlated Channels]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Schneider, Christian;  Iqbal, Naveed;  Thomae, Reiner S.]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Within the field of link adaption for spatial multiplexing MIMO transmissions we focus on adaptive swichting of the number of active RF modules and followed by optimized antenna subset selection (AS). This contribution proposes a approximated analytical solution for the selection of the MIMO order (MOS) depending on the full channel matrix and the signal-to-noise ratio. If the number of selected transmit antenna is lower then number of the available transmit antennas an antenna subset selection takes place to maximize the channel capacity. Here we propose different low complex approaches based on the pairwise antenna correlations and receive signal-tonoise ratio. The results of our performance evaluation highlight that the proposed techniques have no or very minor performance degradation but significantly reduced complexity compared to optimal and suboptimal solutions known from literature. Keywords ?? Link adaptation, MIMO order selection, antenna subset selection, multiple inputs multiple outputs (MIMO), spatial multiplexing, capacity maximization, correlation]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582820]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582820]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582820&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582820]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>55</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Energy-Efficient Resource Allocation Techniques for Battery Management with Energy Harvesting Nodes: a Practical Approach]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Rubio, Javier;  Pascual-Iserte, Antonio;  Payaro, Miquel]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper addresses the problem of resource allocation in a broadcast scenario with frequency selective channels where the terminals are considered to be batterypowered devices provided with energy harvesting capabilities. Models for the energy consumption of the RF and decoding stages are discussed and included in the design of the proposed resource allocation policies. The allocation is performed discretely over subcarrier, bit loading, and power by means of practical greedy-like algorithms and considering energy-related constraints in order to increase the duration of the batteries and, thus, the network lifetime. Simulation results show that not only the usage of battery is improved when compared with other traditional allocation policies, but also the average bit-rate is enhanced.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582777]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582777]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582777&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582777]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>56</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A New Scheduling Method for Enhanced Quality of Experience in LTE Systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Seyedebrahimi, Mirghiasaldin;  Peng, Xiao-Hong;  Harrison, Rob]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper a new approach to the resource allocation and scheduling mechanism that reflects the effect of user??s Quality of Experience is presented. The proposed scheduling algorithm is examined in the context of 3GPP Long Term Evolution (LTE) system. Pause Intensity (PI) as an objective and no-reference quality assessment metric is employed to represent user??s satisfaction in the scheduler of eNodeB. PI is in fact a measurement of discontinuity in the service. The performance of the scheduling method proposed is compared with two extreme cases: maxCI and Round Robin scheduling schemes which correspond to the efficiency and fairness oriented mechanisms, respectively. Our work reveals that the proposed method is able to perform between fairness and efficiency requirements, in favor of higher satisfaction for the users to the desired level. Index Terms ?? Scheduling, link adaptation, Long Term Evolution (LTE), pause intensity (PI)]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582814]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582814]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582814&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582814]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>57</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Study of Cyclic Delay Diversity for Single Frequency Network using DRM Standard]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Savaux, Vincent;  Djoko-Kouam, Moise;  Skrzypczak, Alexandre]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Abstract?This paper presents a study of cyclic delay diversity (CDD) for a single frequency network (SFN) using digital radio mondiale (DRM) standard. Flat fading over the bandwidth can entirely disrupt the signal during several orthogonal frequency division multiplexing (OFDM) symbols. In such conditions, chan- nel encoding can only partially recover the sent information. In order to overcome this problem, CDD articially increases the frequency selectivity of the channel by adding a phase to the signal at the emitter side. We describe the principle in the case of two transmit antennas, and for a more complete network model, where three values of phase shifting are considered. We measure the gain provided by CDD for one process on one hand and in average on the other hand. In order to complete the study, we show the effect of the increase of frequency selectivity on the channel estimation performance. Index Terms - ?COFDM, delay diversity, single frequency net- work, digital radio mondiale.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582763]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582763]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582763&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582763]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>58</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Probabilistic Algorithm for Secret Matrix Share Size Reduction]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Pfluegel, Eckhard;  Panaousis, Emmanouil;  Politis, Christos]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Secret sharing is an important tool in cryptography and has many applications for wireless networks. This paper is motivated by the need for space-efficient secret sharing schemes. We first propose a simple probabilistic algorithm which can be used, prior to secret sharing, in order to split a given secret into public and private data. The public data can be made openly available, and any specific secret sharing method can be used in order to share the private data. We then show that, combined with a previously published space-efficient single secret sharing method, this yields a novel probabilistic matrix-based online multi-secret sharing method with small expected share size. In particular, compared with other matrix-based approaches, our scheme is of similar expected computational cost but smaller share size. Finally, we report on an implementation of our method and evaluate its performance. Our algorithm could be useful to design efficient secret sharing applications for wireless networks, in particular mobile ad-hoc networks, in areas such as secure routing, data transmission or key management. Index Terms ?? Space-Efficient Multi-Secret Sharing, Probabilistic Algorithms]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582801]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582801]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582801&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582801]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>59</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Dual Analysis of the Capacity of Spectrum Sharing Cognitive Radio with MRC under Nakagami-m Fading]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Oni, Phillip Babatunde;  Ajibesin, Adeyemi A.;  Duan, Ruifeng;  Elmusrati, Mohammed]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this study, the maximum achievable information transmission rate of spectrum sharing cognitive radio with maximal ratio combining (MRC) antenna diversity technique is investigated when the channel between the secondary transmitter and the primary receiver, and that between the secondary transmitter and secondary receiver suffer Nakagami-m fading. With an assumption that both channels encounter Nakagami-m fading and the transmission of the secondary transmitter is subject to average interference power constraint, the approximated expressions for analyzing the effective capacity and the ergodic capacity of cognitive radio users with MRC are presented. The two capacity models are compared. In the case of effective capacity, it is shown that different applications or users with different quality of service (QoS) requirements can be supported in cognitive radio, and when the delay QoS decreases, the effective capacity approaches the ergodic capacity. Keywords ?? cognitve radio, effective capacity, ergodic capacity, Nakagami, maximal ratio combining]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582756]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582756]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582756&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582756]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>60</rank>

<title><![CDATA[TCP-based Multi Parallel Links Exploiting Packet Re-routing Mechanisms in Diverse Channel Condition]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Anggadjaja, Erwin;  McLoughlin, Ian;  Premkumar, A.B.]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper takes into account different characteristics of TCP-based MIMO sub-channels, including bit error rate (BER) and data rate, in addition to exploiting these differences by implementing sub-channel re-routing methods to improve overall goodput. We show that even simple packet routing mechanisms can provide an overall performance improvement when MIMO sub-channels have unequal error rate. Two scenario models are created: the first one is called a dual parallel-link scenario model where two nodes communicate over two wireless sub-channels, and the second scenario is a more interesting model named the quad-parallel independent link model (Quad-PILM). Simulation are derived for both models, enhanced with two novel switching methods SWS and PLD and two retry scenarios set up: RDL and RRL, in which showing how re-transmissions will be carried out. We investigate the system in the light of goodput under various channel differences. Based on our analysis, we determine the degree of improvement of our proposed models, and show that these techniques may be advantageous for multiple antenna systems. Index Terms ?? Channel difference, MIMO sub-channels, packet re-routing, switching methods.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582761]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582761]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582761&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582761]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>61</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Cellular Automata Approach towards Self Organisation in Wireless Cellular Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Aliu, Osianoh Glenn;  Mehta, Mahima;  Evans, Barry G.]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper gives an introduction to a key tool that can help provide various self organised solutions in wireless cellu- lar networks. We begin by describing the need for self organised networks and the challenges associated with it. An introduction to cellular automata theory is then given with an easy to follow example. We provide an analysis of such solutions and discuss its stability and convergence criterion. Finally, we formulate a specific problem for Inter-Cell Interference Coordination (ICIC), describing how the cellular automata approach can be applied to achieve ICIC. In addition, we discuss the prospective use case of applying cellular automata in achieving energy efficiency in heterogeneous networks. This paper will serve as a guide for anyone willing to develop self organising solutions in wireless cellular networks.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582810]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582810]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582810&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582810]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>62</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Performance Evaluation of Reduced Power Inter-cell Interference Coordination for Downlink in LTE-Advanced Heterogeneous Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Morimoto, Akihito;  Miki, Nobuhiko;  Okumura, Yukihiko]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In Long-Term Evolution (LTE)-Advanced, heterogeneous networks are important to improve further the system throughput per unit area. In heterogeneous network deployment, low power nodes such as picocells are overlaid onto macrocells. In the downlink, the combined usage of inter-cell interference coordination (ICIC) that reduces the severe interference from macrocells and cell range expansion (CRE) that increases the offloading effect to picocells is very effective in improving the throughput performance. This paper investigates the impact of the reduction in the transmission power and the restrictions on the modulation scheme when using ICIC, which reduces the transmission power from the macrocell (referred to as reduced power (RP)-ICIC), on the user throughput performance. Simulation results show that the user throughput employing RP-ICIC is not sensitive to the protected subframe ratio compared to that employing ICIC, which stops the transmission from the macrocells (referred to as zero power (ZP)-ICIC), even if the modulation scheme is restricted to only QPSK in the protected subframes. This indicates that RP-ICIC is more robust than ZP-ICIC for a non-optimum protected subframe ratio. Keywords ?? LTE-Advanced, heterogeneous network, inter-cell interference coordination, cell range expansion]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582802]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582802]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582802&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582802]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>63</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Performance Evaluation Metric for Cooperative Sensing in Heterogeneous Radio Environments]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Akram, Tahir;  Esemann, Tim;  Hellbrueck, Horst]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Spectrum sensing is a major task for wireless devices in order to improve coexistence among them in heterogeneous radio environments. Wireless communication includes at least two partners: transmitter and receiver. Therefore, cooperation between partners can improve the performance of spectrum sensing by reducing effort, improving sensing result or a combination of both. An optimal cooperative sensing scheme is a first step to achieve complete awareness of the radio environment for wireless devices. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first theoretical work performed in order to understand the problem of developing optimal cooperative sensing schemes for heterogeneous radio environments for multiple users and single channel. We analyze the problem and perform analytical work which results in a cooperative sensing model. The model comprises sensing schedule, data fusion rules, PU??s traffic pattern, and detection performance of the sensing device. A new performance evaluation metric is introduced for optimum spectrum sensing in heterogeneous radio environments. An evaluation of available exemplary cooperative sensing schemes shows that none provides optimality in all scenarios. Index Terms ?? Cooperative MAC; Performance Evaluation Metric; Spectrum Sensing; Heterogeneous Radio Environment]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582770]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582770]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582770&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582770]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>64</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On Capacity and Bounds for the Gaussian CZIC and CBZIC with Linear Coded Approximation]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Patel, Aaqib;  del Aguila, Fernando Reategui;  Khan, Zafar Ali;  Imran, Muhammad Ali;  Merchant, S.N.;  Desai, U.B.;  Tafazolli, Rahim]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we study the Gaussian Cognitive Zinterference channel (GCZIC) and its multiuser extension the Gaussian Cognitive Broadcast Z-interference channel (GCBZIC). We review some known capacity results and bounds for the GCZIC for various levels of interference. We derive a new improved inner bound for the GCZIC under conditions which intersect with those for which the capacity is not known. Then we derive the capacity results and bounds for the GCBZIC when the broadcast component of the channel is a degraded broadcast channel. Index Terms ?? Gaussian Cognitive Interference channels, Z-Interference Channels, Degraded Broadcast Z-Interference Channels, Linear Coded Approximation.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582809]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582809]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582809&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582809]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>65</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Novel Spectrum Sensing Scheme for Dynamic PU Traffic Environments]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Shim, Jeongyoon;  Lee, Youngpo;  Lee, Youngseok;  Yoon, Seokho]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Exploiting the cyclostationarity of the primary user (PU) signals, we propose a novel spectrum sensing scheme for cognitive radio (CR) systems in dynamic PU traffic environments where PUs might randomly depart or arrive during the sensing period. First, the spectrum sensing problem is modeled as a binary hypothesis testing problem and the corresponding generalized likelihood ratio (GLR) is developed. Then, a test statistic for spectrum sensing is derived by obtaining an estimate of spectral autocoherence function of the PU signal and then applying it to the GLR. Numerical results show that the proposed cyclostationarity approach provides a significant improvement in spectrum sensing performance over the conventional energy detection approach in dynamic PU traffic environments.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582786]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582786]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582786&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582786]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>66</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On the Clock Offset Estimation in an Improved IEEE 1588 Synchronization Scheme]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Peng, Jinlin;  Zhang, Li;  McLernon, Des]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[IEEE 1588 specifies a dedicated protocol, the precision time protocol (PTP) for clock synchronization in a networked measurement and control system. It plays an important role in the packet-based network synchronization mechanism. However, the performance of the conventional IEEE 1588 synchronization algorithm is affected by the asymmetric link and random delay problems. This paper proposes an improved IEEE 1588 based synchronization scheme by utilizing additional packets with different sizes to overcome these problems, without adding hardware or overheads. Based on the proposed scheme, this paper derives the maximum likelihood estimators (MLEs) of the clock offset and analyzes the corresponding Cramer-Rao lower bounds (CRLBs) for both Gaussian and exponential random delay models. The performance of the proposed estimator is evaluated in two scenarios with different random delay distribution. The impact of the size of the transmitted packets is studied by simulation. The results show that the proposed scheme and estimators can successfully overcome the detrimental effect of the asymmetric link and random delay problems. The synchronization accuracy of the proposed scheme significantly outperforms both the conventional IEEE 1588 scheme and an existing method in terms of clock offset bias error without the need of extra hardware.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582783]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582783]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582783&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582783]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>67</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Anchor-less Self-Positioning in Rectangular Room Based on Sectorized Narrowband Antennas]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Arambasic, Igor;  Casajus Quiros, Javier;  Raos, Ivana;  Raspopoulos, Marios;  Stavrou, Stavros]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A system for anchor-less self-positioning and simultaneous 2D estimation of rectangular room dimensions is proposed. The system is based on narrowband transceiver capable of simultaneous transmission and reception. The transmission is generated at omnidirectional antenna, while eight sectorized antennas with 45deg apertures in horizontal are used for reception. The full duplex property enables measurements of spatially discriminated channel impulse response (CIR) at the same place where the signal is originated. Hence, by using radar approach, the presence of walls and corners can be evaluated based on round trip time (RTT) measurements. The novel contribution of this paper includes position estimation confidence indicator defined as instantaneous received power of the CIR??s strongest element. Additionally, it is assumed that a transceiver is a part of an ??intelligent?? mobile robot platform capable of moving, updating its position, and keeping track of past positions along with the corresponding measurement data. We propose a new mobility model, focused on efficient exploration of an unknown environment by moving towards the walls according to the corresponding confidence indicators values. Simulations inside narrowband synthetic test environment are performed and the performances of localization and room dimension estimates, as a function of number of observations, are evaluated. Index Terms ?? full duplex antennas, channel impulse response, indoor, mapping, mobility model, radar approach estimation, ray tracing, rectangular rooms, round trip time, simultaneous localization and mapping, sectorized narrowband antennas, selfpositioning, spatial CIR discrimination, transceiver localization]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582829]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582829]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582829&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582829]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>68</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Priority and Buffer Based Admission Control in Relay-enhanced LTE-A systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Tesema, Fasil;  Granelli, Fabrizio;  Vitiello, Federica;  Redana, Simone]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Relay Nodes (RNs) introduction is one of the main features of LTE-Advanced (LTE-A) with the aim of enhancing network coverage and capacity at cell-edge. However, a proper admission control scheme is required to increase the total number of admitted users in the system. This work proposes the implementation and evaluation of three types of admission control schemes taking into account the optimal resource partitioning between RNs and DeNB. The first scheme bases the admission and rejection of users on the resources?? availability. The second scheme adds an admission control algorithm based on users?? priorities. Finally, the third scheme introduces a dynamic buffer in order to utilize the free resources during the empty arrival periods and to further improve the performance. Performance analysis of the proposed admission control algorithms for different download bit rates and file size is performed through simulations. The optimal buffer configuration that minimizes the probability of unhappy users is determined. Keywords ?? Relay; LTE-Advanced; Admission Control; Relay Node.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582758]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582758]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582758&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582758]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>69</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Spatio-Temporal Model for Role Assignment in Wireless Sensor Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ibrahim, Alia;  Carrez, Francois;  Moessner, Klaus]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Wireless Sensor Networks (WSNs) are receiving increasing interest because of their role for data collection and processing in pervasive computing. While most research in the field of WSNs is more considered with resource constraint problems of the network like energy consumption and limited capabilities, there is a need for a higher level modeling of the network to allow the best use of the network [1]. Most of the work for semantic modeling of WSNs does not consider the temporal aspect of node??s operation. Time is considered as an external index of the state of the network, and mostly the snapshot model for time representation is used, which limits the reasoning capabilities of these networks. This paper proposes a spatio-temporal model for WSNs to enable reasoning about anytime, anywhere sensor??s actions. We use the Basic Formal Ontology (BFO) as a framework for our model as it provides a structure for representing the dynamic features of reality in two ontologies for continuants and occurrence, as for the semantic representation of sensor nodes, the W3C Semantic Sensor Network (SSN) provides concepts for describing and connecting sensor nodes with their measurement technique and observation. Index Terms ?? Wireless sensor network, role assignment, ontology, spatio-temporal representation.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582817]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582817]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582817&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582817]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>70</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Performance Analysis of Antenna Selection Algorithms in Spatial Modulation Systems with Imperfect CSIR]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Rajashekar, Rakshith;  Hari, K.V.S.;  Giridhar, K.;  Hanzo, L.]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Two antenna selection algorithms, namely the Euclidean Distance optimized Antenna Selection (EDAS) and Capacity Optimized Antenna Selection (COAS) are studied in the context of Spatial Modulation (SM) systems operating with the aid of imperfect Channel State Information at the Receiver (CSIR). The Symbol Error Rate (SER) performance of these schemes is compared to that of the conventional MIMO (CMIMO) system employing transmit antenna selection. It was observed that the SM system employing antenna selection attains significant Signal-to-Noise Ratio (SNR) gains compared to the C-MIMO system employing antenna selection, especially in the low to moderate SNR regime. Furthermore, we propose a lowcomplexity iterative data-detection/channel-estimation algorithm for the SM system operating with imperfect CSIR that offers an almost identical SER performance as that of the SM system operating with perfect CSIR. Index Terms ?? Spatial modulation, antenna selection, limited feedback, diversity, and capacity.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582824]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582824]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582824&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582824]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>71</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Reduced Complexity Interference Avoidance Scheme Based on User Grouping in Dense Cellular Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Awad, Juan F.;  Imran, Muhammad A.;  Tafazolli, Rahim]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In current day dense cellular networks, inter-cell interference presents a real obstacle to achieving high data rates and it severely limits users?? performance with the vulnerable users being the worst affected. In this paper, we propose an intercell interference avoidance scheme for the downlink of multicell OFDM systems. Using this scheme, we endeavor to reduce the interference on vulnerable users caused when transmitting to ??healthy?? users in order to improve the vulnerable users?? performance with minimal impact on the total system throughput. We first start by grouping the users into two groups based on various performance criteria then we introduce a performance metric which is dependent on these criteria. Furthermore, resource allocation techniques favoring the vulnerable users are proposed. We propose a subcarrier allocation technique that prohibits the subcarrier sharing between vulnerable users. Then, based on the previously introduced metric, a weight calculation method for the power control of the weighted sum rate maximization problem is proposed. The effectiveness of the proposed scheme is verified through simulations where it is shown that, with negligible degradation in total system throughput, as little as 2.6%, the proposed scheme is able to improve the spectral efficiency of the worst 20% of users by up to 22% and also increase the fairness, especially in dense cellular systems. Index Terms ?? Interference avoidance, inter-cell interference coordination, critical users, user grouping, resource allocation, weight calculation.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582784]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582784]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582784&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582784]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>72</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Hybrid Approach for Radio Access Technology Selection in Heterogeneous Wireless Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[El Helou, Melhem;  Lahoud, Samer;  Ibrahim, Marc;  Khawam, Kinda]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In heterogeneous wireless networks, different radio access technologies are integrated and may be jointly managed. To optimize composite network performance and capacity, Common Radio Resource Management (CRRM) mechanisms need to be defined. This paper tackles the access technology selection ?? a key CRRM functionality ?? and proposes a hybrid decision framework to dynamically integrate operator objectives and user preferences. Mobile users make their selection decision based on their needs and preferences as well as on the cost and QoS information signaled by the network. Appropriate decisional information should then be derived so that the network better utilizes its radio resources, while mobile users maximize their own utility. We thus present two tuning policies, namely the staircase and the slope tuning policies, to dynamically modulate this information. Simulation results illustrate the gain from using our tuning policies in comparison with a static one: they lead to better network performance, larger operator gain and higher user satisfaction. Index Terms ?? Radio access technology selection, heterogeneous wireless networks, hybrid decision-making approach.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582798]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582798]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582798&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582798]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>73</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Stable Throughput of an Interweave Cognitive Radio System Employing SR-ARQ Protocol]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Agrawal, Gaurav;  Banerjee, Adrish]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we mathematically analyze stable throughput for an interweave cognitive radio system employing Selective Repeat-Automatic Repeat Request (SR-ARQ) protocol. We model the cognitive link and primary link as interacting queue systems and perform stability analysis of an equivalent dominant system for the case of interacting queues with Loynes?? stability criteria. Based on the studies, we derive optimal power allocation schemes for two links.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582815]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582815]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582815&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582815]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>74</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Near-Optimum Detection for Use in Closed-Loop Distributed Space Time Coding with Asynchronous Transmission and Selection of Two Dual-Antenna Relays]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Qaja, Walid;  Elazreg, Abdulghani;  Chambers, Jonathon]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We consider amplify-and-forward (AF) type cooperative wireless relay networks employing single bit closed-loop extended orthogonal space-time block coding (CL EO-STBC) over two selected cooperating relay nodes. Selection is performed from a set of NR available relay nodes each equipped with two antennas and outer convolutive coding is used to improve performance. A near-optimum detection scheme is used at the destination node for overcoming the effects of imperfect synchronization among selected relay nodes. End-to-end simulation results show that the employed detection scheme can effectively eliminate the interference components induced by asynchronism with low detection complexity. Furthermore, the one-bit feedback scheme and relay selection technique can enhance the overall system performance and outperform previous feedback methods.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582800]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582800]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582800&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582800]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>75</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Cross-layer architecture for DVB-S2 Broadband Satellite systems with QoS support]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Rendon-Morales, Elizabeth;  Mata-Diaz, Jorge;  Munoz, Jose L.]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we propose an architecture to provide Quality of Service (QoS) guarantees for DVB-S2 broadband satellite systems. The proposed architecture provides low complexity on its implementation and can seamlessly inter-operate with terrestrial IP networks. The solution is designed in compliance with the ETSI-BSM-QoS framework and provides a detailed design at the Satellite Independent- Satellite Dependent (SI-SD) layers in order to provide QoS guarantees by means of traffic priorities. Particularly, at the SI layers several mechanism are defined to deal with QoS differentiation based on the DiffServ framework. Conversely, at the SD layers the application of different DVB-S2 channel adaptations are assumed. The proposed architecture is evaluated using the NS-2 simulator. The key results show that the implementation of this architecture, enables to keep control of the satellite system load while guaranteeing the QoS levels for the high priority traffic classes even though bandwidth variations due to rain events are experienced.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582766]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582766]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582766&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582766]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>76</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On the Selection of Guard Period and Cyclic Prefix for Beyond 4G TDD Radio Access Network]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Laehetkangas, Eeva;  Pajukoski, Kari;  Berardinelli, Gilberto;  Tavares, Fernando;  Tiirola, Esa;  Harjula, Ilkka;  Mogensen, Preben;  Raaf, Bernhard]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In parallel with ongoing standardization of third generation partnership project (3GPP) Long Term Evolution ?? Advanced (LTE-A), also referred as 4G, the discussion on next generation beyond 4G (B4G) radio access technologies is already active. Purpose of B4G system, expected to be available in 2020, is to cope with the exponential increase of mobile data traffic. In this paper we analyze the feasibility of LTE-A and wireless local area network (WLAN) physical frames against B4G requirements and discuss how the B4G environment, radio channel properties and evolved component technology affect the design of the physical layer frame. We analyze the B4G physical subframe numerology including aspects such as time division duplex (TDD) switching time and cyclic prefix (CP) duration. The proposed numerology allows to design a B4G-optimized TDD physical subframe structure which further enables reaching the very tight physical layer round trip time (RTT) requirements. Index Terms ?? Beyond 4G, TDD, OFDM, cyclic prefix, guard period, frame structure]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582760]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582760]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582760&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582760]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>77</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A New Personalized Agriculture Advisory System]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Jhunjhunwala, Ashok;  Umadikar, Jayalakshmi;  Prashant, Suma]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The Indo-UK Advanced Technology Centre of Excellence in Next Generation Networks, Systems and Services (IUATC) is trying to address the future challenges identified by the UK Government under the Digital Economy Theme and the Department of Science and Technology in India. One such area in rural India where Information and Communication Technologies (ICT) networks can have a major impact is Agriculture. This paper presents a new approach to building an Agricultural Advisory System aimed at bridging the information gaps that exist between farmers and extension workers and agricultural scientists in a country like India. It demonstrates the power of two-way mobile phones today, which when combined with innovative methods could provide services to farmers that could not even be envisaged till yesterday. The customized and personalized advisory becomes especially important in the Indian context, where 52% of the population depends on agriculture but generates merely 13.9% of its Gross Domestic Product (GDP). With fragmented landholdings, the number of independent farmers has risen to 88 million with near-stagnant productivity. Growth-acceleration is possible only with customized advisory. India currently has a 900 million strong mobile phone subscriber base largely operating over voice oriented 2G GSM (Global System for Mobile Communications) and GPRS (General Packet Radio Service) networks. With ever increasing rural mobile penetration, personalized agricultural advisory is a distinct possibility. The paper presents an innovative technology development effort, analyses the technological challenges faced as well as discusses the feedback obtained from early fieldimplementation and focuses on what needs to be done in future to scale such systems. Index Terms ????????? Mobile telephony applications, Agriculture Advisory System, Call Centre, Dashboard for farmers, Interactive Voice Response System]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582823]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582823]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582823&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582823]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>78</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Optimal Threshold of Welch??s Periodogram for Sensing OFDM Signals at Low SNR Levels]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Wang, Nan;  Gao, Yue]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Spectrum sensing is one of the key technologies to realize dynamic spectrum access in cognitive radio systems, especially being able to reliably detect primary user signal in low signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) levels. In this paper, a new optimal threshold setting algorithm based on the conventional Welch??s energy detection algorithm is proposed to achieve an efficient trade-off between the detection probability and false alarm probability for OFDM signals at the low SNR levels. The proposed optimal threshold algorithm in the Welch??s method demonstrates a better spectrum sensing performance at the low SNR levels. The relationship between the spectrum utilization and optimal threshold is derived. The effect of spectrum utilization on the performance of spectrum sensing is also analyzed.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582816]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582816]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582816&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582816]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>79</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Context-Aware Decision Making Framework for Cognitive and Coexisting Networking Environments]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Triantafyllopoulou, Dionysia;  Moessner, Klaus;  Kliks, Adrian;  Bogucka, Hanna;  Zalonis, Andreas;  Dagres, Ioannis;  Dimitriou, Nikos;  Polydoros, Andreas]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[One of the major challenges in cognitive and cooperative communication systems that support advanced coexistence technologies for radio resource usage optimization is efficient decision making. However, the high dynamicity of such communication environments, in conjunction with the existence of an increasing amount of diverse context information, result in decision making becoming a non-trivial issue. In this paper, we present a novel decision making framework for modern wireless communication environments. More specifically, the different steps of the decision making cycle and the role they play in the decision making process are presented, while the different fragments that constitute the notion of context, as well as their role and the way they interact with and influence the decision making steps are described in detail. Moreover, two case-studies, on interference management in heterogeneous networks and noise-robust and energy-efficient sensing, respectively, are presented, highlighting their compliance with the described decision making framework. Keywords ?? context, decision making, enforcement, learning, solution filtering]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582812]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582812]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582812&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582812]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>80</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Neighbour and network discovery in cognitive radio networks: research activities and results in the ACROPOLIS Network of Excellence]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[De Nardis, Luca;  Di Benedetto, Maria-Gabriella;  Rakovic, Valentin;  Atanasovski, Vladimir;  Gavrilovska, Liljana;  Holland, Oliver;  Akhtar, Auon;  Aghvami, Hamid;  Tassetto, Dimitri;  Bovelli, Sergio;  Stavroulaki, Vera;  Kritikou, Yiouli;  Bantouna, Aimilia;  Demestichas, Panagiotis;  Romaszko, Sylwia]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Cognitive radio networks operation relies on the capability to gather information about the surrounding environment, as regards both internal network status (presence and capabilities of other devices belonging to the same network) and external systems potentially coexisting with the cognitive network. In particular, retrieving information at the local level is a function required to all wireless networks, and goes under the name of neighbour discovery. Under this aspect, cognitive networks make no exception. Similarly, cognitive networks share with traditional wireless networks the necessity of a function for retrieving and exchanging information on a network wide scale, referred to in the following as network discovery. The definition of efficient neighbour and network discovery strategies for cognitive networks, taking into account their specific characteristics, is one of the goals of the research activities undergoing within the framework of the ACROPOLIS NoE. In this work, neighbour and network discovery solutions currently under investigation within the ACROPOLIS joint research activities are presented, and future research lines are identified. The paper first presents algorithms and results on neighbour discovery and Medium Access Control, and moves then to network wide protocols by presenting the work carried out in ACROPOLIS on routing for underlay cognitive networks. The paper provides then an overview on the common simulation platform developed within ACROPOLIS to investigate neighbour and network discovery, and finally discusses future research directions on such topics. Index Terms ?? Cognitive radio, neighbour discovery, network discovery]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582832]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582832]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582832&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582832]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>81</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On Semi-Static Interference Coordination under Proportional Fair Scheduling in LTE Systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Parruca, Donald;  Grysla, Marius;  Zhou, Han;  Naghibi, Farshad;  Petrova, Marina;  Maehoenen, Petri;  Gross, James]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we consider the design of semi-static inter-cell interference coordination schemes for LTE networks. In this approach, base stations coordinate the power settings per resource block over long time spans such as seconds. In order to optimize the power settings, one needs to employ models which predict the rate of terminals over the next coordination period under the usage of a given power setting. However, these models are typically quite simple and neglect the impact from fading as well as from dynamic resource allocation performed at the base stations on a millisecond basis. Ignoring such properties of OFDMA networks leads therefore to suboptimal transmit power settings. In this paper, we study the impact from a precise rate prediction model that accurately accounts for fading and dynamic resource allocation. On the down-side, this more precise model leads to a much more involved optimization problem to be solved once per coordination period. We propose two different heuristic methods to deal with this problem. Especially the usage of genetic algorithm results to be promising to counteract the complexity increase. We then study the overall system performance and find precise rate prediction models to be essential for semi-static interference coordination as they provide significant performance improvements in comparison to approaches with simpler models.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582790]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582790]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582790&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582790]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>82</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Survey on Media Independent Handover (MIH) Approaches in Heterogeneous Wireless Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Khattab, Omar;  Alani, Omar]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[One challenge of wireless networks integration is to provide ubiquitous wireless access abilities seamless handover for mobile communication devices between the different types of technologies (3GPP and non-3GPP), such as GSM (Global System for Mobile Communication), Wireless Fidelity (Wi-Fi), Worldwide Interoperability for Microwave Access (WiMAX), Universal Mobile Telecommunications System (UMTS) and Long Term Evolution (LTE). This challenge is critical as Mobile Users (MUs) are becoming increasingly demanding for services regardless of the technological complexities associated with it. To fulfill these requirements for seamless Vertical Handover (VHO) the Media Independent Handover IEEE 802.21 (MIH) which was produced by IEEE group as mechanism to provide seamless VHO between the aforementioned technologies which requires mobility management protocols, such as Mobile IPv4 (MIPv4) or Mobile IPv6 (MIPv6) to complement its work . Various VHO approaches have been proposed in the literature applied in conjunction with MIPv4 and MIPv6 under MIH, using empirical work real environment, testbed, simulation tools and analytical medoling. In this paper, we survey the VHO approaches proposed in the literature and classify them into two categories based on mobility management protocols (MIPv4 and MIPv6) for which we compare their performances and characteristics. Finally, through this survey, we conclude that MIPv4 under MIH is expected to continue in the future. Keywords ?? Vertical Handover (VHO), Media Independent Handover (MIH), Heterogeneous Wireless Networks.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582796]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582796]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582796&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582796]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>83</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Modified Small PIFA Frequency Tunable Antenna]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Elfergani, I.T.E.;  Hussaini, Abubakar Sadiq;  Abd-Alhameed, R.A.;  Abusitta, M.M.;  Rodriguez, Jonathan]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents a physically compact, frequency tunable antenna design for use in mobile terminals. The full operating bandwidth is between 1750 MHz and 2400 MHz with good impedance match in the entire tuning range to meet the coverage requirements of the DCS, PCS, UMTS and WLAN bands . The antenna bandwidth is is realized by loading the embedded resonant slot of a PIFA, with a varactor diode, with an equivalent capacitance range of 0.5 pF to 2.5 pF. Index Terms ?? PIFA antenna; Tunable antenna; Varactor.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582834]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582834]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582834&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582834]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>84</rank>

<title><![CDATA[LTE-A Mobile Relay Handling: Architecture Aspects]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Krendzel, Andrey]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Relaying is one of the new key features that has been defined for LTE-Advanced (3GPP Rel?? 10) in order to improve to and extend the coverage area among other advantages. In the 3GPP Technical Report [1] some architecture alternatives were considered for a case when relay becomes a part of the fixed access network. It is concluded in the report that the architecture based on proxy S1/X2 has more benefits in compare with other alternatives and has to be selected as the baseline architecture to support a fixed relay node. This paper reviews, outlines and sums up the main network architecture aspects for mobile relay handling. Taking into account that mobile relay support has additional requirements such as the group mobility, persistent IP connectivity during handover, etc. the other alternatives considered in [1] could bring more advantages. For this reason, we re-analyze relay architectures presented in [1] aiming to clarify the basic differences and distinguish between the architecture alternatives in the context of relay mobility support. Further to this comparative analysis we review latency budget of handover procedures for different architectures. As a result of the study we conclude that the architecture with a full L3 relay (transparent for Donor eNB) is more appropriate than other architecture alternatives for enabling mobile relay. Keywords ?? Mobile Relay, LTE-A, network architecture, group mobility, handover]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582765]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582765]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582765&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582765]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>85</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Performance Evaluation of the GCR Block ACK Mechanism in IEEE 802.11aa Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Li, Qihao;  Jiao, Lei;  Li, Frank Y.]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The growing demand for multimedia services has gradually made video streams major traffic sources in the Internet. This trend introduces higher demand for IEEE 802.11 wireless networks since such wireless networks are intrinsically inefficient to carry video streams. As a solution to improve system efficiency, a new standard, 802.11aa, is developed by introducing the Groupcast with Retries (GCR) scheme, one of the most important features in this amendment. In this paper, we analyse the throughput performance of the GCR scheme for one of the transmission mechanisms in 802.11aa networks based on a Markov model. Numerical results demonstrate that the successful retransmission probability will be reduced with a larger number of receiving terminals; but it can be increased by reducing the transmission block size. Furthermore, the system throughput can also be improved by configuring the size of the initial transmission block.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582793]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582793]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582793&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582793]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>86</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Increasing Uplink Data Rates in HSPA by the Application of Two Scrambling Codes]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Langowski, Adrian;  Bakowski, Krzysztof;  Wesolowski, Krzysztof]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The paper presents the studies on the application of two scrambling codes for the data and control channels in HSUPA, aiming at increasing the uplink data rates. Appropriate physical channels power offsets selection and equalization can result in a link throughput gain of up to 28% as compared with the standard HSUPA transmission. Intensive HSUPA link level simulations have been performed to investigate optimization of the ratios of traffic to pilot channel powers and to measure parameters of the transmitted signal such as the peak-to-average power ratio and the cubic metric. The selected simulation results are presented in this paper. Index Terms ?? scrambling codes, HSUPA, link level simulation.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582774]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582774]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582774&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582774]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>87</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Generic Efficient FG-SPA Implementation Framework based on the best Linear Canonical Message Representation in MSE Sense]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Prochazka, Pavel;  Sykora, Jan]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference (EW), Proceedings of the 2013 19th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6582749]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2013]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper focuses an implementing issue of the sum-product algorithm on factor graphs (FG-SPA) for a general system. The goal is to propose a message representation and corresponding update rules for both discretely and continuously valued variables with an acceptable exactness-complexity tradeoff that is applicable in a wide class of scenarios. We propose the update rules for a generic class of linear message representations with orthogonal canonical kernels. The proposed update rule design is combined with an already known message parameterization based on the Karhunen-Loeve Transform (KLT) of the message. This combination of the proposed generic update rules with the KLT-message representation forms a generic implementation framework of the FG-SPA applicable whenever the KLT is defined. This framework preserves the properties of the KLT-message representation that is the best linear approximation in the MSE sense. A particular example on a joint detection and phase estimation is shown to verify the proposed framework and to show its advantages against a conventional solution.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3498-6]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6582781]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6582781]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6582781&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6582781]]></pdf>

</document>

</root>
