<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<root>

<totalfound>107</totalfound>

<totalsearched>3815492</totalsearched>

<document>

<rank>1</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A kernel methods approach to reducing handover occurrences within LTE]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Sinclair, Neil;  Harle, David;  Glover, Ian A.;  Atkinson, Robert C.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Department of EEE, University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, UK]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Equations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Femtocells]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Kernel]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Macrocell networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Neurons]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents a kernel-based approach to indoor-outdoor handover management for 4G femtocells. It is a necessary but difficult task to perform seamless handover from indoor femtocells to outdoor macrocells whilst maintaining call continuity. This paper describes a machine learning algorithm to operate in conjunction with 4G handover triggering mechanisms to reduce the rate of unnecessary handovers between femtocells and macrocells. The results of this algorithm show that handovers can be reduced by 65% by detecting where unnecessary handovers are likely to occur and minimising them. By reducing the number of unnecessary handovers, the system resources efficiency may be improved as a result of the potential reduction in signalling exchange taking place which in turn reduces bandwidth usage, the power used by both the femtocell and the mobile terminal and, the level of signal processing necessary.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216844]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216844]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216844&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216844]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>2</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Channel switching-aware optimal reconfiguration in Cognitive Radio Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Arkoulis, Stamatios;  Anifantis, Evangelos;  Karyotis, Vasileios;  Papavassiliou, Symeon;  Mitrou, Nikolaos]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[School of Electrical and Computer Engineering, National Technical University of Athens (NTUA), 15780, Greece]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Availability]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Spread spectrum communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Switches]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Secondary users in Cognitive Radio networks (CRNs) require intelligent reconfiguration mechanisms, in order to respond promptly and limit properly additional and escalating system adaptations triggered by the interweaved primary network activity. In this work, we focus on the Joint Channel Assignment and Routing (JCAR) problem in CRNs and especially on the optimal reconfiguration of secondary networks by mainly taking into account the underlying spectrum switching distance parameter. We formulate the JCAR and network reconfiguration problems as mixed integer linear programs, addressing fairness as well. The proposed formulation addresses the trade-off between low reconfiguration cost and flow demand satisfaction. Through analysis and simulations we demonstrate the operation and effectiveness of the proposed mechanisms. The obtained numerical results indicate and quantify the underlying reconfiguration trade-off, while demonstrating the benefits achieved by the proposed solutions.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216875]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216875]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216875&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216875]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>3</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Admission control for LTE-Advanced relay systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Vitiello, Federica;  Redana, Simone;  Hamalainen, Jyri]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Nokia Siemens Networks, St.-Martin-Str. 76, 81541, Munich, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Admission control]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bit rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Computer architecture]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Streaming media]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Relaying is a feature proposed for the LTE-Advanced (LTE-A) system with the aim of enhancing both network coverage and capacity at cell-edge or in heavily shadowed areas. The LTE-A radio frame structure, while properly designed for the presence of relay nodes, needs to be adequately configured to guarantee the QoS of the ongoing sessions and the fulfillment of the accepted sessions. This paper contributes with an admission control algorithm which leverages the knowledge of the available resources on the specific link and an appropriate resource sharing policies to admit or reject a connection request of new users. Supported by a simulation study, we show that our algorithm improves the performance of the whole cellular system in terms of number of admitted users and blocking probability.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216849]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216849]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216849&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216849]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>4</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Calibrated broadband ray tracing for the simulation of wave propagation in mm and sub-mm wave indoor communication channels]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Priebe, Sebastian;  Jacob, Martin;  Kurner, Thomas]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Institut f&#x00FC;r Nachrichtentechnik, Technische Universit&#x00E4;t Braunschweig, Schleinitzstra&#x00DF;e 22, 38106, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Accuracy]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Broadband communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Calibration]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Frequency domain analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Ray tracing]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[10]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Due to the extremely high bandwidths of mm and sub-mm wave communication systems, conventional ray tracing can only be applied limitedly to simulate the wave propagation behavior in indoor environments. In this paper, a broadband ray tracing approach is presented that takes into account the propagation conditions at multiple frequency points within the simulated band instead of one discrete frequency only. The simulation of channels in the time as well as in the frequency domain are considered. Additionally, the impact of the Fourier transformation on the shapes of the power delay profiles and on the temporal channel characteristics is investigated. Moreover, a novel broadband calibration approach is introduced that utilizes not only the temporal, but also the spatial channel information, namely angle of arrival and angle of departure. Performance and accuracy of the calibration algorithm are demonstrated using the example of channel measurements recorded in an indoor environment at 300 GHz. A significant accuracy improvement of the ray tracing simulations is achieved.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216862]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216862]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216862&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216862]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>5</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Rate adaptive resource allocation with fairness control for OFDMA networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Rodrigues, Emanuel B.;  Casadevall, Fernando]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Department of Signal Theory and Communications (TSC), Technical University of Catalonia (UPC), Jordi Girona St., 1-3, PO Box 08034, Campus Nord, building D4-111, Barcelona, Spain]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Adaptive systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Heuristic algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Indexes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quality of service]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The use of opportunistic radio resource allocation techniques in order to efficiently manage the resources generates a low fairness among the users in a cellular system due to uneven Quality of Service (QoS) distribution. Some classic rate adaptive policies tried to tackle this problem for OFDMA systems by proposing solutions to maximize capacity, maximize fairness, or find a static trade-off between these two objectives. This work generalizes these classic policies and propose a dynamic fairness/rate adaptive technique based on dynamic sub-carrier assignment and equal power allocation that considers a new fairness constraint in the optimization problem. By means of extensive system-level simulations, it is demonstrated that the proposed technique is able to provide an instantaneous (short-term) fairness control, which provides to the network operator the flexibility to operate on any desired trade-off point.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216808]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216808]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216808&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216808]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>6</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Non-linearly induced interference and its mitigation in cognitive wideband receivers]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Grimm, Michael;  Sharma, Rajesh Kumar;  Hein, Matthias;  Thoma, Reiner]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Electronic Measurement Research Lab, International Graduate School on Mobile Communications, Ilmenau University of Technology, P.O. Box 100 565, 98684, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Baseband]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Least squares approximation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Nonlinear distortion]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radio frequency]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Software defined radios are widely used as multi-mode and multi-band RF transceivers for modern communication systems, especially in cognitive radio. However, the design of flexible, cheap, and reconfigurable front-ends is a challenging task in terms of the RF transceiver electronics. Many requirements to the analogue components can be met by today's technologies, however, this may not always be practical except for measurements and prototyping. This paper addresses RF impairments in wideband cognitive radios, especially non-linear distortions in the receiver. Receiver non-linearities affect the reliability of spectrum sensing, a key issue in spectrum awareness. Here, the focus is on mitigation of non-linear distortions using &#x201C;Dirty RF&#x201D; techniques. We present experimental work studying the effects of non-linear distortions and analysing the performance of a typical wideband soft-ware-defined receiver. A feed-forward mitigation algorithm with an adaptive filter has been implemented and applied to real measurement data for cleaning the baseband spectrum of distortion products. The results obtained show that a significant suppression of distortion products can be achieved.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216854]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216854]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216854&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216854]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>7</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Terahertz communications technologies based on photonic and electronic approaches]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Nagatsuma, Tadao]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Graduate School of Engineering Science, Osaka University, Toyonaka 560-8531, Japan]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Detectors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optical transmitters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Photodiodes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Schottky diodes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents terahertz (THz) wireless communications technologies using photonics-based and electronics-based transmitters at 300-GHz bands. The photonics-based transmitter with a Schottky-barrier diode (SBD) detector has boosted a bit rate of the wireless transmission up to 24 Gbit/s. As for the electronics-based transmitter, a resonant-tunneling-diode (RTD) oscillator has been examined together with detectors using the RTD as well as the SBD to achieve a 2.5-Gbit/s transmission.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216864]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216864]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216864&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216864]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>8</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Fast and efficient transmit antenna selection algorithms in spatial multiplexing systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Zhou, Liang;  Ohashi, Yoji]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Fujitsu Laboratories Ltd., 4-1-1 Kamikodanaka, Nakahara-ku, Kawasaki-shi, Kanagawa 211-8588, Japan]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Algorithm design and analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Complexity theory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimized production technology]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receiving antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitting antennas]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we investigate fast and efficient transmit antenna selection algorithms for wireless spatial multiplexing (SM) systems. Fast antenna selection is practical important for adapting to changing environments. The conventional fast antenna selection algorithms such as incremental and decremental algorithms rely on different antenna configurations so as to reduce complexity. Motivated by finding a good submatrix, a fast and efficient transmit antenna selection algorithm is developed based on maximum-volume submatrix based search algorithm. The proposed algorithm essentially maximizes the channel capacity. Complexity analysis and simulation results show that our algorithm with lower complexity performs better than or equivalent to the suboptimal incremental and decremental algorithms for any scenarios.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216861]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216861]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216861&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216861]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>9</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Latency analysis of 3G network components]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Laner, Markus;  Svoboda, Philipp;  Rupp, Markus]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Vienna University of Technology, Austria]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Histograms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IP networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Modems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Synchronization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Latency in 3G wireless cellular networks is relatively high by design. Hence, optimizing latency will be the key task for improving quality of experience in future mobile networks. This work is a precise dissection of the delay contributions of each element in an operational HSPA cellular network, both in uplink and downlink. The deployed methodology is active probing combined with time-synchronized sensing nodes. The latter enable the tracing of packets on every interfaces along the data-path in a 3G network. Our results show that the major delays are introduced at the user terminal side. Interestingly, each network component shows a higher processing time for data in downlink than in uplink. Further, we assess latency increases carried by the use of legacy network equipment. For reproducibility of the results we provide models for the delay of each HSPA network component. Our findings enable (i) to estimate latencies in existing networks for simulations and network planning and, (ii) to identify reasonable starting points for research on latency reduction in future networks.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216847]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216847]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216847&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216847]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>10</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Iterative techniques for cooperative communications allowing intra-link errors- from the Slepian Wolf compression viewpoint (invited talk)]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Matsumoto, Tad;  Burr, Alister]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Japan Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (JAIST), 1-1 Asahidai, Nomi, Ishikawa, 923-1292 JAPAN]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Electronic mail]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Entropy]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Turbo codes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[2]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A goal of this invited talk is to provide the audience with the knowledge about the relationship between the relay systems and the Slepian-Wolf theorem for coding of correlated sources. As shown in Fig. 1, According to the Slepian-Wolf theorem, the achievable rate region is constituted as an unbounded polygon. The source information can be recovered only when the compressed rate pair falls into this area. For instance, if b<inf>1</inf> is compressed at the rate R<inf>1</inf> which equals to its entropy H(b<inf>1</inf>), then b2 can be compressed at the rate R<inf>2</inf> which is less than its entropy H(b<inf>2</inf>), but must be greater than their conditional entropy H(b<inf>2</inf>&#x2223;b<inf>1</inf>), or vise verse. Specifically, the pair of compression rates R<inf>1</inf> and R<inf>2</inf> satisfies three equations [1] R<inf>1</inf> &#x2265; H(b<inf>1</inf> &#x2223; b<inf>2</inf>), (1) R<inf>2</inf> &#x2265; H(b<inf>2</inf> &#x2223; b<inf>1</inf>), (2) R<inf>1</inf> + R<inf>2</inf> &#x2265; H(b<inf>1</inf>, b<inf>2</inf>). (3) According to the Slepian-Wolf theorem, by exploiting the correlation knowledge of the data streams at the destination, the distributed source coding can achieve the same compression rare as the optimum single encoder which compresses the sources jointly.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216880]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216880]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216880&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216880]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>11</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Intelligent transports systems based on UWB technologies]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Boukour, Fouzia Elbahhar;  Rivenq, Atika]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[IFSTTAR-LEOST Univ. Lille Nord de France, F-59000, France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Ultra wideband communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Ultra Wide Band (UWB) may offer very efficient solutions for various communication and localisation transport applications. We propose to use this technique to establish communication vehicle- to- vehicle and vehicle- to-infrastructure. In fact, compared to traditional carrier-based, Ultra-Wide Band (UWB), or carrier-less, systems implement new paradigms in terms of signal generation and reception. Thus, designing an UWB communication and localisation system requires understanding of how excess bandwidth and very low transmitted powers can be used jointly to provide a reliable radio link. UWB offers system transceiver potential for very simple implementations. Two approaches have emerged, which meet all the communication requirements: impulse and multi-band systems. The first system operates between 3.1 to 10.6 GHz in a single frequency band. The second one exploits the division of the bandwidth into sub-bands (each sub-band width being up to around 500 MHz wide). The present work is concerned in the second approach. So, we propose to use orthogonal functions called Modified Gegenbauer Functions (MGF) in UWB systems. Different scenarios are studied and compared in the scope of a system offering communication and location capabilities for subway trains. To evaluate the performance of the proposed communication system, the Bit Error Rate (BER) values are calculated and analyzed in the presence of multi-user interference, assuming asynchonous users. The performance of localisation system is evaluated in terms of localisation error. This study shows that Gegenbauer functions offer the performance required for our multi-band UWB communication and location transport systems.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216818]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216818]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216818&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216818]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>12</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Iterative rejection of adjacent channel interference for 802.11n WLANs]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Szulakiewicz, Pawel;  Kotrys, Robert;  Krasicki, Maciej;  Remlein, Piotr;  Stelter, Andrzej]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Wireless Communications, Pozna&#x0144; University of Technology, 3 Polanka St, Poland]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Modulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Silicon carbide]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Simulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Timing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents a method for rejecting the adjacent channel interference (ACI) between the 802.11 based OFDM channels. The proposed approach is based on a well known in the literature successive interference cancellation (SIC). In the paper, a simplified model of two neighboring OFDM channels is considered. Two wireless local area network (WLAN) users, asynchronous to each other, occupy the adjacent, non-overlapping 20 MHz channels. It is shown how the 40 MHz receiver, which has a sum of two arriving asynchronous 20 MHz OFDM signals, is able to reject the ACI in a few iterative steps. The capability to eliminate ACI is presented by means a of simulation. Some features of the ACI are also analyzed in the paper.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216839]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216839]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216839&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216839]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>13</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Making a blind date the guaranteed rendezvous in Cognitive Radio Ad Hoc Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Romaszko, Sylwia]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Institute for Networked Systems, RWTH Aachen University, Kackerstrasse 9, 52072, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Arrays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cognitive radio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Switches]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In Cognitive Radio Ad Hoc Networks (CRANs) a frequently changing environment and Primary Users (PUs) channel occupancy result in a need of the searching of common control channel (CCC) by Secondary Users (SUs) in order to be able to initiate a communication. A blind date or so-called rendezvous, required before an actual medium access, is therefore a new challenge, not encountered in single channel networks. Hence, new rendezvous protocols must be designed to handle this changeability of CCC in such a way that there is a guarantee that all nodes meet periodically in reasonable periods of time. Since pseudo-random solutions do not provide this guarantee, therefore, systematic approaches are needed, where, a.o., quorum systems (QSs) become popular, especially in power saving (PS) protocols. In this study, first we perform research on the element distribution in a period of a torus quorum system (tQS) in order to produce multiple quorums satisfying Rotation Closure Property in a single torus array. We also propose a novel distributed rendezvous (RDV) protocol for CRANs, tQS-RDV. We demonstrate that tQS-RDV guarantees RDV on at least two channels with a low number of available channels (r &#x2264; 4), and on at least four channels otherwise.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216872]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216872]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216872&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216872]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>14</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Low speed feedback for grassmannian beamforming in MIMO-OFDM with frequency selective channel]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Gutman, Igor;  Ezri, Doron;  Wulich, Dov]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Ben Gurion University of the Negev, Israel]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Array signal processing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vectors]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Multiple input multiple output (MIMO) precoding is an efficient scheme that may significantly enhance the communication link. Many precoding schemes require channel knowledge at the transmitter that is obtained, in non-reciprocal channels, through feedback from the receiver to the transmitter. Focusing on the natural fusion of orthogonal frequency division multiplexing (OFDM) and MIMO, we exploit the channel correlation in the frequency domain to reduce the required feedback data rate. The proposed feedback method tailors Huffman coding to an existing clustering method, and is employed here for the transmit beamforming. The method leads to a significant reduction in the required feedback data rate, and performs better than existing feedback techniques. The proposed method can be easily implemented in any existing or future protocol due to its low complexity.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216857]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216857]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216857&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216857]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>15</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Distributed beamforming using one bit of feedback: AWGN analysis]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Berbakov, Lazar;  Anton-Haro, Carles;  Matamoros, Javier]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Centre Tecnol&#x00F2;gic de Telecomunicacions de Catalunya (CTTC), Parc Mediterrani de la Tecnologia, Av. Carl Friedrich Gauss 7, 08860 Castelldefels, Spain]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Array signal processing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Convergence]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Noise]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Noise measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Synchronization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we analyze the impact of additive noise in the received signal strength (RSS) on the behavior of an iterative phase synchronization scheme for distributed beamforming. In particular, we derive an analytical expression which models the expected increase of the beamforming gain in such noisy scenarios. Furthermore, we show that noise prevents the algorithm from achieving full beamforming gain. We also assess, by means of computer simulations, the optimal number of RSS samples per iteration needed to attain the highest beamforming gain after convergence.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216858]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216858]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216858&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216858]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>16</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Signal shaping for unique-word OFDM by Selected Mapping]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Huber, Johannes B.;  Rettelbach, Jakob;  Seidl, Mathis;  Huemer, Mario]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Institute for Information Transmission, Universit&#x00E4;t Erlangen-N&#x00FC;rnberg, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Frequency domain analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Neodymium]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quadrature amplitude modulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time domain analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vectors]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Selected Mapping (SLM) is known to be a useful method to reduce the peak to average power ratio (PAPR) of OFDM transmit signals. In this paper, the performance of PAPR-reduction for UniqueWord (UW-) OFDM is investigated where in contrast to usual cyclic prefix (CP-) OFDM correlations between subcarrier data exist due to a complex number Reed-Solomon code along the subcarriers. It is shown that these correlations do not impair the positive properties of SLM for PAPR-reduction. Moreover, SLM is a general method for shaping of transmit signals generated in blocks in order to strengthen some desired signal features and e.g. may be applied to lower efficiently the average power of the redundant subcarriers in UW-OFDM. Furthermore, we show that SLM together with UW-OFDM is well suited for reducing the peak to minimum ratio (PMR) of the transmit signal as well. Analytic results are accompanied by simulation results.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216894]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216894]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216894&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216894]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>17</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Systematic design of Hierarchical Network Code mapper for butterfly network relaying]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Uricar, Tomas;  Sykora, Jan]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Czech Technical University in Prague, Czech Republic]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Algorithm design and analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Partitioning algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Systematics]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A majority of the research results on Wireless Network Coding (WNC) considers only a basic 2-Way Relay Channel (2-WRC) system scenario, where the Complementary Side Information (C-SI) is naturally available at both destinations. Although an extension of the WNC principles from the 2-WRC system to the butterfly network could seem relatively straightforward, several new unconventional phenomena of the WNC arise (and need to be considered). First of all, the unreliable transmission of the C-SI can be overcome by an increased cardinality of the relay output. This opens a question how a suitable Hierarchical Network Code (HNC) mapper could be designed for a given quality of the C-SI link (and source alphabet cardinality). In this paper we focus on this problem. We introduce a systematic approach to the design of a set of HNC mappers, respecting the amount of available C-SI. Observed capacity gains of this (extended cardinality) relaying pave the way for an adaptive butterfly network, where the achievable throughput can be maximized by a suitable choice of the HNC map at the relay.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216882]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216882]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216882&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216882]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>18</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Co-operative ITS - standardization]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Brakemeier, Achim]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Communication Protocols, GR/PAD, Daimler AG, Ulm, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Road safety]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Telecommunication standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vehicles]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[3]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Co-operative Systems for ITS are seen as an efficient way to further improve road safety and traffic efficiency. Many stakeholders must co-operate to start the deployment and the standardization is necessary. The European Commission issued the mandate M/453 to ETSI and CEN to further develop cooperative ITS in Europe.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216884]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216884]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216884&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216884]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>19</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Performance evaluations and a power management mechanism for Mobile WiMAX systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Dinh, Nga T.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Bell Labs Seoul, Korea]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The Mobile WiMAX (or IEEE 802.16e) standard defines a power saving mechanism (PSM), which operates using sleep- and awake-modes, to conserve power of a Mobile Station (MS) but at the expense of an increased service delay. This delay includes an access delay for the MS to transition from sleep- to wake- modes and a queuing delay that a queued packet in base station (BS) buffer has to wait. In addition to service delay, a PSM results in a packet loss if the number of packets in the queue is more than BS buffer size. Unfortunately, previous studies on Mobile WiMAX did not sufficiently consider queuing delay and packet loss. In addition, design of sleep- mode has to guarantee network quality- of- service (QoS) in terms of service delay and packet loss besides reducing power consumption. This paper derives analytical models for power consumption, service delay, and packet dropping probability, given as a function of sleep-mode parameters such as the initial sleep window T<inf>min</inf> and final sleep window T<inf>max</inf>. Furthermore, the paper proposes a power efficiency under QoS constraints (PEQC) mechanism to minimize consumed power of an MS under service delay and packet dropping probability constraints by findings jointly-optimal parameters T<inf>min</inf> and T<inf>max</inf>. Extensive simulations validate that the proposed numerical models are correct and that the PEQC mechanism sufficiently reduces MS's power consumption. In some cases, the PEQC mechanism can save up to 70% of consumed power compared to the original power saving mechanism in Mobile WiMAX.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216907]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216907]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216907&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216907]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>20</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Traffic based energy saving strategies for green cellular networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Morosi, Simone;  Del Re, Enrico;  Piunti, Pierpaolo]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Electronics and Telecommunications Department - University of Florence, Italy]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[GSM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Green products]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Numerical models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Power demand]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Switches]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The objective of the reduction of the energy consumption in the next years has led the scientific community to investigate the possible solution to be adopted in the cellular networks: therefore, a huge attention is currently dedicated to the green radio techniques since even the future business models of the mobile telecom operators will be deeply influenced by the trends which will be chosen today. In this paper, two adaptive algorithms which are based on traffic forecast and real-time measurements are proposed and compared with the goal of the optimal radio resources management.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216887]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216887]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216887&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216887]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>21</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Cell range extension in LTE in-band relays: Analysis of radio link, subframe allocation and protocol perfornance of FTP traffic model]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Rasheed, Anzil A;  Wager, Stefan]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Wireless Access Networks - Ericsson Research, Oy L M Ericsson Ab, Finland]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bit rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Gain]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[System performance]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Self backhauled in-band relays are an integral component of LTE-Advanced. In this paper, we have investigated the effect on user as well as system performance when UEs in the coverage edge between a macro Donor eNB (DeNB) and Relay Node (RN) are biased to select the RN as its serving cell. For the studied load point, our results indicate that relay deployment improves system capacity along with improved bit rates for cell-edge users. Introducing relay cell range extension enhances the offloading gain for macro users, thereby improving overall bit rates in the system. However, range extension with offsets beyond 6 dB degrades system capacity as well as bit rates; due to increased imbalance in DL received powers, higher protocol related latency in time-multiplexed multi-hop transmission etc. The highly detailed radio and protocol modeling in the simulator provides insight about the gains and challenges of range extension in possibly one of the most realistic simulation settings.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216867]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216867]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216867&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216867]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>22</rank>

<title><![CDATA[PAPR reduction in distributed amplify-and-forward type closed loop extended orthogonal space frequency block coding with one-bit group feedback for cooperative communications]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Eddaghel, M. M.;  Chambers, J. A.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Advanced Signal Processing Group, School of Electronic, Electrical and Systems Engineering, Loughborough University, Leicestershire, UK, LE11 3TU]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Iterative decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Peak to average power ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vectors]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Peak-to-average power ratio (PAPR) reduction in a distributed amplify-and-forward (AF) type cooperative system using a virtual multi-input multi-output orthogonal frequency division multiplexing (VMIMO-OFDM) system with an extended orthogonal space frequency block coding (EO-SFBC) transmission scheme is addressed. Oversampling, amplitude clipping and filtering at the source and/or relays is studied. The iterative amplitude reconstruction (IAR) decoding technique is used to overcome the harmful effects introduced by the clipping operation within the system. The end-to-end bit error rate (BER) simulations of the proposed system verify that clipping only at the source has the best performance compared with clipping at the relay nodes or clipping in both the source and relays. In addition, the system achieves full spatial diversity with only a small number of feedback bits by exploiting quantized one-bit group feedback, whilst limiting the source PAPR.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216826]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216826]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216826&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216826]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>23</rank>

<title><![CDATA[An adaptive cooperative downlink transmission scheme for wireless network with distributed antenna system]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Jianxin Liu;  Jijian Chen;  Xinsheng Zhao]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[National Mobile Communications Research Laboratory, Southeast University, Nanjing, Jiangsu, 210096, China]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Adaptive arrays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitting antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Multi-Cell MIMO Cooperative downlink transmitting can reduce the system interference and enhance capacity in cell edge. In this paper, wireless network with distributed antenna system (DAS) is discussed and the downlink ergodic capacity of radio signal intersection area in three remote antenna unit (RAU) scenario is investigated for problem observation. Then we propose an adaptive cooperative downlink transmission scheme to enhance system capacity. In this proposed scheme, large-scale fading information between MS and RAUs is employed to decide the most appropriate mode from three available modes named CT-1, CT-2, CT-3. Selection criterion is the ergodic capacity corresponding three transmission modes. Simulation results show that the proposed scheme can achieve high capacity and reduce the system interference significantly.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216825]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216825]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216825&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216825]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>24</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Board implementation and its performance for IR-UWB IEEE.802.15.4a from multiple ASIC chips]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Olonbayar, S.;  Kreiser, D.;  Martynenko, D.;  Fischer, G.;  Klymenko, O.;  Kraemer, R.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[IHP, Im Technologiepark 25, 15236 Frankfurt Oder, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Baseband]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Clocks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[One energy efficient way of ASIC implementation for the standard IEEE802.15.4a was considered in greater detail. The main focus was on developing a solution for short range communication based on impulse radio ultra wideband. The ASIC implementation is performed with the 250 nm SiGe technology from IHP, Germany. The current system consists of three chips: radio frequency frontend, digital baseband and an integrating analogue digital converter. All the chips were fabricated and designed at IHP. A non-coherent energy detection receiver was realised which collects energy over 16 ns in analogue fashion. The performance of the complete system was evaluated bringing the chips on a board. Our multiple ASIC approach was a necessary step towards a complete integration of the system into a single chip. This paper discusses the function of individual chips and their interaction on a board. The performance was assessed by frame error rates, approximate coverage and waveforms at certain points. Initial laboratory tests and measurements suggest that the implemented system can support wireless communications in a distance of up to five meters and consume reasonable power.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216819]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216819]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216819&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216819]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>25</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Energy optimization in cellular networks with micro-/pico-cells using Markov Decision Process]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Abbas, Ziaul Haq;  Li, Frank Y.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Department of Information and Communication Technology, University of Agder (UiA), N-4898 Grimstad, Norway]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Markov processes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Power demand]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Steady-state]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Switches]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitting antennas]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Power conservation of communication networks at the system level has received much attention due to the tremendous increase in the number of infrastructure equipment in recent years. In this paper, we propose a teletraffic-based optimization approach to minimize the power consumption of cellular networks with three micro- or pico-cells. When traffic load in the middle cell is sufficiently low, the cell can be switched off and its users will be covered by increasing the transmission power of one sector in each of the two neighboring cells. A Finite Markov Decision Process (FMDP) is constructed and analyzed in order to minimize network transmission power consumption. Numerical results demonstrate that minimized power consumption can be achieved using our FMDP model. The long-term power consumption can also be predicted.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216890]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216890]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216890&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216890]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>26</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Blind carrier frequency offset tracking based on multiuser interference cancellation in OFDMA uplink systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Fa, Rui;  Zhang, Li;  Ramirez-Gutierrez, Raymundo]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Department of Electrical Engineering and Electronics, The University of Liverpool, L69 3GJ, UK]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Complexity theory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Integrated circuits]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference cancellation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vectors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we propose a novel blind CFO tracking algorithm for the OFDMA uplink systems with the generalized carrier assignment scheme (GCAS). The proposed blind CFO tracking technique is built on a low complexity grouped minimum mean squared error based multi-stage interference cancellation (G-MMSE-MIC) scheme, which feeds decisions to drive the CFO tracking. The CFO tracking is implemented by using a bank of closed-loops to track the time-varying CFOs in the decision-directed (DD) mode without pilot tones. The simulation results demonstrate that the proposed blind CFOs tracking scheme performs well in the presence of time-varying CFOs with affordable complexity.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216822]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216822]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216822&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216822]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>27</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Efficient training of adaptive MIMO channel tracking algorithms]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Eitel, Emna;  Speidel, Joachim]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Institute of Telecommunications, University of Stuttgart, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Equations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Least squares approximation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Training]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, improved training schemes for adaptive decision-directed tracking filters are proposed and applied to time-varying flat fading MIMO channels. In case of periodic training with a limited amount of pilots, it is shown that a trade-off between investing pilots for good initialization and exclusive training of the algorithm leads to a lower BER and a higher spectral efficiency than conventional training. In [1], we introduced a novel aperiodic training scheme for the Kalman filter. We extend this scheme to the RLS and LMS algorithms and develop appropriate metrics for filter divergence detection for each algorithm. The metric thresholds are derived analytically. We show that the proposed training reduces the BER significantly. The impact of feedback delay caused by pilot request and transmission is also investigated. Simulation results show that pilot on request training outperforms periodic training even for large mean pilot delays.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216841]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216841]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216841&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216841]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>28</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Frequency domain channel measurements for wireless localization - practical considerations and effects of the measurement]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Dammes, Timo;  Endemann, Wolfgang;  Kays, Ruediger]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Communication Technology Institute, TU Dortmund University, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antenna measurements]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Calibration]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Frequency domain analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Noise]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Reflection]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transfer functions]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The measurement of wireless channels is a crucial step for realistic simulations of networks. Plenty of measurements and channel models have been published for communication applications. However, channel measurements for wireless localization focus on specific aspects like the exact representation of antenna distances by the path delays. Unfortunately, there are certain properties and effects of the measurement that complicate the correct extraction of the channel impulse response. Therefore, this paper deals with the well known method of frequency domain channel measurements with a focus on localization applications. We will give an overview over the general measurement system which is based on a vector network analyzer (VNA). The measurement parameters and methods necessary for the reconstruction of the impulse response with precise distance information will be presented. We will also reveal possible error sources of the measurement. For example, reflections and crosstalk result in several limitations of the impulse response. The influence of interfering networks and other man made distortions during the measurement will be estimated. We will show how the VNA based channel measurement can effectively be used for realistic simulations of localization algorithms.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216908]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216908]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216908&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216908]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>29</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Energy efficiency of HARQ-IR for two-way relay systems with network coding]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Choi, Jinho;  To, Duc]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[College of Engineering, Swansea University, UK]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Reliability]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[For a two-way wireless relay system, in which two end nodes (EN) exchange their messages with the aid of a relay node (RN), the notion of network coding can be exploited to improve throughput. In this paper, the hybrid automatic repeat request with incremental redundancy (HARQ-IR) is applied to a two-way wireless relay system with network coding for reliable transmissions and its energy efficiency is studied. Two approaches of facilitating network coding are proposed including analog network coding (ANC) and physical-layer network coding (PNC). Using the notion of energy delay tradeoff (EDT) as a tool to evaluate the degrees of energy efficiency, we can show that the PNC- can be more energy efficient than the ANC-based scheme. Numerical results confirm the advantage of relay-aided transmissions with PNC in terms of energy efficiency.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216881]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216881]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216881&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216881]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>30</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Security and smart metering]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Kaplantzis, Sophia;  Sekercioglu, Y. Ahmet]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Department of Electrical and Computer Systems Engineering, Monash University, Clayton 3800, Australia]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Logic gates]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Security]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Smart grids]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The &#x2018;smart grid&#x2019; is an upgrade of the existing 20th century electrical power grid, promoted to address the pressing issues of end-user energy monitoring, global warming, distributed power generation and emergency response. Smart grids are quickly spawning in Australia, Europe and North America. Security in smart grids is imperative to protect the functionality of their underlying networks, the data they communicate and the privacy of their customers. However, few research efforts have focussed on security in this area and solutions adopted from traditional ad-hoc networks are not suitable, as they would need to be fully integrated with the grid and its legacy systems before they can yield positive results. The purpose of this paper is dual; to review matters of smart grid security and to examine the effect of hacker attacks on smart grid network parameters. Through simulation we investigate how malicious activity targeting the routing layer of smart grid networks can interrupt network effectiveness.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216815]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216815]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216815&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216815]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>31</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Cooperative feeder links for relay enhanced networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Zirwas, Wolfgang;  Zeeshan, Umer;  Grieger, Michael]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Nokia Siemens Networks GmbH &amp; Co KG, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antenna measurements]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Floors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Heterogeneous networks are gaining more and more interest as one means to cope with the expected data rise in future mobile networks. The upgrade of cellular macro networks by placing relay nodes, as one option, has the benefit of avoiding any wired backhaul network, but has to be paid by lower performance compared to pico stations. In the ARTIST4G project we analyze options to get close to the performance of pico stations by using highly effective inband relaying. The goal is to maximize the performance of the donor eNB (DeNB) to RN links - i.e. of the feeder links - by a specifically adapted joint precoding coordinated multi-point (JP-CoMP) scheme to which we refer to as cooperative relaying (CoR). In this paper, the expected performance gains under ideal conditions will be assessed based on system level simulations and different measurements. A further focus is on the main enablers of any CoMP scheme, i.e. channel estimation and feedback techniques properly adapted taking the specific conditions of relay enhanced networks into account.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216868]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216868]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216868&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216868]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>32</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Multi-user data sharing using coordinator with network coding and layered transmission]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Mizutani, Keiichi;  Haustein, Thomas;  Sakaguchi, Kei]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Graduate School of Science and Engineering, Tokyo Institute of Technology, 2-12-1 Ookayama, Meguro, Japan, 152-8552]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Gain]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Phase shift keying]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Unicast]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, a data sharing system using a coordinator with layered transmission is proposed. We focus on secured data connections from all users to all users of the conferencing group. A typical example is secured group communication between a group of users e.g. a social group during a multi-user audio or video conference. Secured unicast scheme, secured broadcast scheme, and network coding scheme are considered for the data distribution scheme in downlink. The layered transmission can achieve improvement of the network throughput. In addition, the hierarchical modulation is introduced to improve the network throughput, and an effective region of the hierarchical modulation is shown. Finally, the network throughput of the secured unicast, the secured broadcast, and the network coding is compared, and we find that the network coding is the most effective scheme for the data sharing system using the coordinator with layered transmission.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216870]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216870]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216870&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216870]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>33</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Signal shaping for PMSE protection]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Kryszkiewicz, Pawel;  Kliks, Adrian;  Bogucka, Hanna]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Poznan University of Technology, Wireless Communications, 60-965, Poland]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Cognitive ratio has attracted a lot of research interest already for more than ten years, since it creates great possibilities for efficient spectrum utilization. However, the cognitive transmission assumes that the signal of the licensed users will be protected. In this work the dynamic protection methods of the primary users is considered, in particular the application of the cancellation carriers method combined with the windowing process is investigated in a non-contiguous multicarrier transmission. The novelty of this work is the derivation of the optimal number of subcarriers that have to be deactivated by the secondary user in order to keep the interference introduced to the primary user under the allowed threshold while providing the highest possible data rate to the cognitive radio.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216853]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216853]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216853&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216853]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>34</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A simple delay compensation system in software-defined Frequency Modulated Continuous (FMCW) radar]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Prasetiadi, Ananto E.;  Suksmono, Andriyan B.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Radio Communication and Microwave Lab., Institut Teknologi Bandung, Indonesia]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Chirp]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Computers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Frequency response]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Operating systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radar]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Implementation of Frequency Modulated Continuous Wave (FMCW) radar in software-defined radio hardware, such as Universal Software Radio Peripheral (USRP) device, could leads into a low cost, low power and reconfigurable radar. On the other hand, this kind of device introduces additional delay which disturbs the delay caused by object. Therefore, this problem leads into significant error in range determination. In this paper, a simple system is proposed to solve this problem, which employs constant signal transmitted before the FMCW signal. This system works successfully solving the additional delay problem.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216860]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216860]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216860&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216860]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>35</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Space-time multilevel coded modulation with iterative detection for multiple-antenna transmission]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Yi Wang;  Burr, Alister G.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Communications Research Group, Department of Electronics, University of York, UK]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Detectors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Equations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Iterative decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Modulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vectors]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We propose a novel space-time coded modulation approach for multi-antenna systems, namely space-time multilevel coded modulation with iterative decoding (ST-MLCM-ID), for the purpose of exploiting both multiplexing gain and multilevel coding gain. This scheme allows flexible selection of space-time mappings, signal constellations, and outer codes used on each level of the mapping, for each antenna. We introduce the concept of the space-time distorted bit-level extrinsic information transfer (STDBL-EXIT) function, derive the area properties of the STDBL-EXIT functions in information theoretic terms, and show a highly-efficient code design rule for ST-MLCM-ID. Simulations further demonstrate that by employing our rule based on the STDBL-EXIT function, ST-MLCM-ID is capable of achieving full convergence close to the theoretical limit, while also allowing sufficient flexibility in the choice of codes on each level of the space-time mapping of each antenna.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216896]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216896]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216896&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216896]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>36</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Theoretical analysis of the trade-off between efficiency and linearity of the high power amplifier in OFDM context]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Gouba, O. Abel;  Louet, Yves]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[IETR / SUPELEC, Campus de Rennes, Avenue de la Boulaie - CS 47601, F-35576 Cesson-Sevign&#x00E9; cedex, France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Linearity]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Peak to average power ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Predistortion]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Upper bound]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Power efficiency and linearity are key parameters of amplification systems but they cannot be achieved simultaneously. A perfect linearity is observed when the power efficiency is low and vice versa. In this paper, we first analyze through some theoretical expressions, the power efficiency and the linearity measured by the Error Vector Magnitude (EVM) metric. Then we propose an analytical trade-off that ensures a good linearity with reasonable efficiency by combining Peak-to-Average Power Ratio (PAPR) reduction and linearization. This analysis is carried out based on Solid State Power Amplifiers (SSPA) and Predistortion (PD) as linearization technique. We show that a trade-off can be achieved for a high distortionless PAPR reduction gain followed by an effective predistortion. Last but not least the most important is to avoid the amplifier saturation by setting the PAPR of the signal after PAPR reduction technique identical to the input back-off (IBO).]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216837]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216837]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216837&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216837]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>37</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Inter-cell interference coordination via multi-layer rate splitting scheme in heterogeneous networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Zhou, Guangxia;  Xu, Wen;  Bauch, Gerhard;  Berkmann, Jens]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Intel Mobile Communications, Am Campeon 10-12, D-85579, Neubiberg, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Iterative decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Phase shift keying]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A heterogeneous network consists of macro base stations and numerous pico base stations. Without efficient mitigation of interference between macro cells and pico cells, user equipments (UEs) at cell edge suffer from strong interference and their performance will be degraded. This paper investigates and evaluates the multi-layer rate splitting scheme in a realistic macro-pico network. Simulation results for two cell-edge UEs which endure interference show that the multi-layer rate splitting scheme can substantially improve the performance in terms of average throughput as well as cell-edge and peak throughput.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216811]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216811]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216811&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216811]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>38</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Extending constellation shaping by shell mapping method to reduce the peak and average power of space-time block coded OFDM systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Sterian, Corneliu Eugen D.;  Enescu, Andrei Alexandru]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Polytechnic University of Bucharest, Romania]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Block codes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Broadband antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Constellation diagram]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Peak to average power ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitting antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We extend our constellation shaping by shell mapping method of reducing the peak and average power of orthogonal frequency division multiplexing (OFDM) signals using quadrature-amplitude modulation (QAM) on all subcarriers from single transmit antenna systems to multiple transmit antennas systems. We consider space-time block codes that are designed for maximum antenna diversity and start from the observation that all the columns of the transmit matrix have the same power. The constellation shaping by shell mapping first groups the two-dimensional (2D) QAM symbols into rings; our main point is that we group length-L rings into a super-ring, where L is the number of rows of the transmit matrix. An OFDM frame has length N = L&#x00B7;Q. The super-rings are further grouped into shells, each shell being an ordered set of length-Q super-rings. To support the validity of our approach, we give illustrative examples for L = 2 and L = 4.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216899]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216899]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216899&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216899]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>39</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Downlink rate-guaranteed scheduling for multiuser OFDMA cellular systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Martyna, Jerzy]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science, Institute of Computer Science, Jagiellonian University, ul. Prof. S. &#x0141;ojasiewicza 6, 30-348 Cracow, Poland]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Heuristic algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Scheduling algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Orthogonal frequency division multiple access (OFDMA) systems are currently subject to considerable attention as a potential candidate for future generation cellular systems. To achieve proportional fairness among users while improving user satisfaction, we propose a novel optimization approach for packet scheduling in OFDMA-based cellular systems whereby the scheduler is designed not only based on the required rate bandwidth and fairness across users, but also based on optimization of the utilization performance over all the subbands. Moreover, our solution has been proposed for all the users in the downlink of a single-cell and multi-cell OFDMA system. Then, according to the solution obtained, a heuristic scheduling algorithm for practical use is proposed. Simulation results show that our algorithm can achieve 85% of the optimal solution.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216809]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216809]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216809&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216809]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>40</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Novel spectrum sharing algorithm for maximizing supported WiFi-like secondary users in TV white spaces]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Jankuloska, B.;  Atanasovski, V.;  Gavrilovska, L.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Information Technologies, Ss Cyril and Methodius University in Skopje, Macedonia]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Algorithm design and analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel allocation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Games]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[TV]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Spectrum underutilization and efficient spectrum allocation are one of the major challenges in wireless communications today. Cognitive radios represent devices that aim to enable reliable spectrum availability detection and efficient secondary spectrum access in a plethora of possible deployment scenarios. This paper proposes a novel joint power and channel allocation algorithm in a spectrum sharing system for WiFi-like secondary systems in TV white spaces. The method itself relies on the Nash Bargaining Solution (NBS) from game theory. The proposed algorithm maximizes the number of supported secondary users while jointly optimizing both power and channel allocation. The performance evaluations show that the introduction of the combined allocation method enhances the efficient available spectrum usage among secondary users. The paper also evaluates the average throughput per SU and network density effects on the performance of the proposed sharing algorithm.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216856]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216856]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216856&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216856]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>41</rank>

<title><![CDATA[An iterative and joint estimation of SNR and frequency selective channel for OFDM systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Savaux, Vincent;  Louet, Yves;  Djoko-Kouam, Moise;  Djoko-Kouam, Mo&#x00EF; se;  Skrzypczak, Alexandre]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[ECAM Rennes - Louis de Broglie, Campus de Ker Lann - Bruz, 35 091 Cedex 9, France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Convergence]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Covariance matrix]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper proposes an iterative method for a joint estimation of the signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) and the frequency selective transmission channel in OFDM systems. The noise variance is estimated using a pilot preamble scheme, with the minimum mean square error (MMSE) criterion which requires the channel estimation. The channel estimation uses the Linear MMSE (LMMSE) method which requires the noise variance estimation. As each estimator feeds the other one, an iterative algorithm is proposed. We prove that this algorithm converges for any non-null initialization value. Simulations show the validity of the method with a very low number of iterations for both SNR and channel estimation. We show that the number of pilot symbols in the preamble with respect to the performance of SNR estimation is improved compared to existing SNR estimation methods. Our approach also requires only one pilot symbol. Furthermore, for a given BER value, the SNR gap between perfect estimation and our proposed method is less than 0.5 dB.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216835]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216835]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216835&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216835]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>42</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Reinvestigation of 16-QAM BI-STCM-ID labellings: Point-wise distance spectrum approach]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Krasicki, Maciej]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Wireless Communications, Poznan University of Technology, 3 Polanka St, Poland]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Encoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Genetic algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Labeling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper contributes a new method to unveil properties of BI-STCM-ID (Bit-Interleaved Space-Time Coded Modulation with Iterative Decoding) labellings. It consists in computation of point-wise distance spectrum. Thanks to the proposed approach, it is shown that several labelling maps, found here by means of the genetic algorithm, are equivalent to each other and to the optimal ones, known from the literature. Although the optimal labellings of BI-STCM-ID appear to be completely random, the point-wise spectrum shows that they are quite even. Prior to demonstration of the proposed method in action, the most important facts about BI-STCM-ID are reviewed.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216914]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216914]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216914&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216914]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>43</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Performance evaluation of threshold-based TOA estimation techniques using IR-UWB indoor measurements]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Lei Yu;  Laaraiedh, Mohamed;  Avrillon, Stephane;  Uguen, Bernard;  Keignart, Julien;  Stephan, Julien]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Universit&#x00E9; de Rennes 1, IETR, Campus Beaulieu Bat 11D, 35042 France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antenna measurements]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Distance measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time of arrival estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Ultra-wide bandwidth (UWB) technology is a viable candidate for enabling accurate localization through time of arrival (TOA) based ranging techniques. These ranging techniques exploit the high time resolution of the UWB signals to estimate the TOA of the first signal path. Nevertheless, these techniques are facing the problem of proper multipath mitigation especially in harsh propagation environments in which the first path may not exist or it may not be the strongest. This paper presents a realistic comparison between the ranging performances of four threshold-based TOA estimation techniques using experimental data collected from an IR-UWB indoor propagation measurement campaign performed in an office building.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216910]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216910]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216910&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216910]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>44</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Network deployment and RRM strategies for green mobile communications]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Morosi, Simone;  Fanfani, Alessio;  Del Re, Enrico]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[University of Florence - CNIT, Via S. Marta 3, 50139, Italy]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Green products]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Power demand]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Switches]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Urban areas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The RRM strategies and the deployment guidelines to be adopted in a multi-layer heterogeneous mobile network with the goal of the optimization of the Area Power Consumption are presented in this paper: in the considered scenarios, several radio environments are considered, the coverage is guaranteed by different cell types, and the capacity and blockage probability are kept unaltered by the adoption of the green radio approaches with respect to basic configuration. The benefits in terms of energy savings are determined for all possible solutions: within this framework we compare alternative approaches, such as the macro-cell coverage and the strategies which resorts to a higher number of lower power micro-cells to cover the spot.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216888]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216888]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216888&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216888]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>45</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Adaptive MMSE channel estimation algorithms for MIMO systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Hesketh, Thomas;  de Lamare, Rodrigo C.;  Wales, Stephen]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Communications Research Group, Department of Electronics, University of York, YO10 5DD, United Kingdom]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Detectors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, two adaptive linear minimum mean-square error (MMSE) channel estimation algorithms for multiple-input multiple-output (MIMO) wireless communication systems are proposed. An adaptive recursive MMSE channel estimation algorithm is devised that computes the channel auto-correlation statistics and the noise variance required by the linear MMSE channel estimator without any prior knowledge. A low-complexity stochastic gradient-based MMSE channel estimation algorithm is also proposed for tracking time-varying MIMO channels. Simulation results show comparisons between the proposed algorithms, the linear least squares (LS) and the linear MMSE channel estimators, revealing that the proposed methods approach the performance of the linear MMSE estimator.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216840]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216840]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216840&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216840]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>46</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A cooperative multihop approach for energy efficient wireless content distribution]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Yaacoub, Elias;  Abu-Dayya, Adnan]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[QU Wireless Innovations Center (QUWIC), Qatar Science and Technology Park, Doha, Qatar]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Complexity theory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Energy consumption]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Minimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Strontium]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Cooperative content distribution for the purpose of energy minimization is investigated in the framework of multihop wireless networks. Mobile terminals cooperate to receive content of common interest from the base station and distribute it using multihop cooperative techniques. The problem is formulated as an integer linear program and an efficient suboptimal content distribution approach is presented. The proposed approach is shown to lead to significant energy savings compared to the non cooperative scenario. In addition, it is shown to reduce the total delay in the content distribution process and to release a significant portion of the base station bandwidth.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216829]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216829]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216829&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216829]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>47</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Energy efficient multicast data delivery using cooperative mobile clouds]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Karunakaran, Prasanth;  Bagheri, Hamidreza;  Katz, Marcos]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Centre for Wireless Communications, University of Oulu, Finland 90014]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Batteries]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Energy consumption]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Power demand]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Data reception over cellular and similar architectures is extremely power hungry, resulting in quick battery drain. In order to improve the quality of experience, the energy consumption has to be reduced. A mobile cloud, formed using cellular and short-range platforms of the mobiles is considered. It is shown that when all users of the cloud are accessing the same data, the mobile cloud can provide significant energy savings. Several practical strategies are developed for cooperation in a mobile cloud. The energy per bit of the strategies is analyzed using timeline diagrams and the average energy gains in a time varying data rate scenario are studied. The results provide useful insights into the possible operation of the strategies and shows that significant energy reductions are possible.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216878]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216878]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216878&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216878]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>48</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Network throughput and energy efficiency in MIMO femtocells]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Tri Minh Nguyen;  Shin, Hyundong;  Quek, Tony Q.S.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Electronics and Radio Engineering, Kyung Hee University, Seocheon-dong, Giheung-gu, Yongin-si, Gyeonggi-do 446-701, Korea]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Array signal processing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Femtocells]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Macrocell networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vectors]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Interference management in heterogeneous networks is an important issue that needs to be tackled in order to achieve the performance gains that these networks promise. In this paper, we consider a Poisson field of MIMO femtocell network with one single macrocell base station (MBS) and multiple femtocell access points (FAPs) which are randomly distributed according to a Poisson Point Process. Considering advanced MIMO techniques, we propose an opportunistic interference alignment (OIA) scheme in order to reduce intra and inter tier interference. Furthermore, we employ a random spectrum allocation above the OIA to &#x201C;thin&#x201D; the number of collision within the same spectrum. By applying stochastic geometry, we show the improvement on the performance of the network in terms of success probability, network throughput, and energy efficiency.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216902]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216902]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216902&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216902]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>49</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Extraction and characterization of location-dependent UWB radio features with practical implications for indoor positioning]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Uguen, B.;  Laaraiedh, M.;  Denis, B.;  Keignart, J.;  Stephan, J.;  Lostanlen, Y.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Universit&#x00E9; Rennes 1 - IETR (UMR 6164), av. du G&#x00E9;n&#x00E9;ral Leclerc, 35042, France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Buildings]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Feature extraction]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radio transmitters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[10]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper regards the exploitation of a time domain Ultra Wideband (UWB) channel measurement campaign, which was carried out in the [3:7]GHz band in a typical indoor office environment. Relevant location-dependent radio features are extracted out of the Channel Responses (CRs) observed at four synchronized receivers spatially disseminated in the building, for various transmitter locations. These metrics are subsequently analyzed from the perspective of localization. First of all, we consider correlations between the extracted radio features and environmental variables (e.g. transmitter coordinates, transmitter-to-receiver distances, channel obstruction conditions). The analysis also comprises interpretations based on deterministic predictions in the very environment, emphasizing local shadowing effects due to the presence of metallic pieces of furniture. Then statistical models are particularized according to geographic sub-areas (or serving access points). Based on the previous results, practical implications are finally drawn for context-aware solutions based on Time Of Arrival (TOA) estimation or Received Signal Strength Indicator (RSSI), aiming at the self-adaptation of positioning algorithms to their local operating conditions.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216820]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216820]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216820&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216820]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>50</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Design and optimization of combined constellation shaping and bit LDPC coded modulation using EXIT chart]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Arafa, Tarek;  Sauer-Greff, Wolfgang;  Urbansky, Ralph]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Institute of Communications Engineering, University of Kaiserslautern, Gottlieb-Daimler-Str., 67653, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Constellation diagram]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Iterative decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quadrature amplitude modulation]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The demand for reliable transmission with higher data rates in modern communication systems is growing rapidly. To meet this demand, multilevel modulation schemes have to be considered in combination with powerful forward error correction (FEC) codes. However, the use of uniform signal constellations can not achieve the capacity limit and a so-called shaping gain is still available. This gain can be obtained by employing non-equiprobable signal constellations. In this paper, we combine the shaping technique with low-density parity-check (LDPC) coded modulation schemes to approach the channel capacity. Furthermore, the concatenation of LDPC codes, constellation shaping techniques and mapping schemes is designed and optimized by using extrinsic information transfer (EXIT) charts. Simulation results show that the optimized systems can achieve a shaping gain up to 0.6 dB even for 64-QAM systems.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216912]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216912]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216912&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216912]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>51</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Performance of transmitter preprocessing assisted multi-carrier IDMA in frequency-selective channel for downlink communications]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Swaminathan, Shriram;  Srinivasan, Nithin;  Ravichandran, Sriram;  Ravichandran, Shruthi;  Nagaradjane, Prabagarane]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Context]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multiaccess communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multiuser detection]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vectors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this correspondence, we investigate and study the performance of multi-user transmitter preprocessing (MUTP) aided multi-carrier interleave division multiple access (MC-IDMA) systems in frequency-selective channels under perfect and imperfect channel state information (CSI) at the transmitter. The MUTP considered in this correspondence creates an orthogonal subspace to the interfering subspace that results in the complete elimination of multi-user interference (MUI) in the context of downlink (DL) communications. Further, this MUTP approach is compared with the conventional zero-forcing (ZF) MUTP and eigen based MUTP. Our simulation study shows that all the MUTP approaches results in the same performance in terms of achievable bit error rate (BER). Furthermore, MUTP aided MC-IDMA systems outperform MUTP aided MC-CDMA systems and MC-IDMA systems with multi-user detection (MUD).]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216824]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216824]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216824&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216824]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>52</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Up in the clouds: A taxonomical analysis of network management functionalities from a network as a service perspective]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Riggio, Roberto;  Kuklinski, Slawomir;  Rasheed, Tinku;  Andreatta, David;  Tacconi, David;  Antonelli, Fabio]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[CREATE-NET Research, Trento, Italy]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Communication system security]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Computer architecture]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Prototypes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Robustness]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Security]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The externalization of network control and maintenance tasks, enabled by the emerging Networking as a Service (NaaS) paradigm, is an appealing opportunity for large Telcos to expand their network management offering to SMEs. In this paper we propose an architecture for network control and management capable of efficiently supporting the NaaS paradigm. Our methodology is based on a set of orthogonal requirements that forms the platform to assess the admissibility of different network management functions in the remote management plane. Such assessments are realized based on the taxonomical evaluation of the management functions classified according to the requirements they impose on the remote management plane in terms of security and robustness. Experimental results obtained from a proof-of-concept implementation deployed over a large scale testbed composed of about 500 WiFi Access Points shows that the signaling traffic for a practical implementation supporting not trivial autonomic control loops is lower that 20 bytes/s for each node. Moreover, the latency to execute administrative actions is in most cases in the order of 70 ms.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216814]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216814]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216814&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216814]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>53</rank>

<title><![CDATA[sGSA: An SDMA-OFDMA scheduling solution]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Zubow, Anatolij;  Marotzke, Johannes;  Camps-Mur, Daniel;  Perez-Costa, Xavier]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Humboldt University Berlin, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Clustering algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Containers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multiaccess communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Future wireless networks need to address the predicted growth in mobile traffic volume, expected to have an explosive growth in the next five years mainly driven by video and web applications. Transmission schemes based on Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiple Access (OFDMA) combined with Space Division Multiple Access (SDMA) techniques are key promising technologies to increase current spectral efficiencies. A Joint SDMA-OFDMA system has to allocate resources in time, frequency and space dimensions to different mobile stations, resulting in a highly complex resource allocation problem. In this paper we take a comprehensive view at the complete SDMA-OFDMA scheduling challenge and propose a SDMA-OFDMA Greedy Scheduling Algorithm (sGSA) for WiMAX systems. The proposed solution considers feasibility constraints in order to allocate resources for multiple mobile stations on a per packet basis by using i) a cluster-based SDMA grouping algorithm and ii) a computationally efficient frame layout scheme which allocates multiple SDMA groups per frame according to their packet QoS utility. A performance evaluation of the proposed sGSA solution as compared to state of the art solutions is provided, based on a comprehensive WiMAX simulation tool.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216823]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216823]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216823&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216823]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>54</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Reduced complexity computation unit for a sphere decoding algorithm]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Wiegand, Till;  Paul, Steffen]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Institute of Electrodynamics and Microelectronics (ITEM), University of Bremen, Otto-Hahn-Allee, NW1, 28359, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Computational complexity]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Detectors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vectors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[MIMO detectors are one of the most complex parts within a wireless communication system. In particular, for high throughput communication standards, like the 3GPP Long Term Evolution, reduced complexity detectors, which achieve a good BER performance are of major interest. Sphere decoder algorithms are one kind of tree search algorithms, which offer a good complexity-performance trade-off. In this paper we introduce a novel computation unit for a sphere decoder algorithm, which achieves an identical behavior compared to a complex sphere decoder, in terms of the BER performance and the number of visited nodes, by a reduced computational complexity. This is achieved due to calculating the Partial Euclidean Distance of the real and the imaginary part of a partial symbol vector totally independently from each other. For example, the number of adders is reduced by about 46% and the signal propagation delay is cut down by one adder stage for the computation unit. Furthermore, the comparator elements of the minimum unit are reduced by 60% and the signal propagation delay is cut down by two comparator stages.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216842]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216842]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216842&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216842]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>55</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Coexistence Issues for Wireless Body Area Networks at 2.45 GHz]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Martelli, Flavia;  Verdone, Roberto]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[DEIS, University of Bologna, Italy]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.15 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multiaccess communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper deals with coexistence issues that may arise for Wireless Body Area Networks (WBANs) operating at the 2.45 GHz ISM band. Two different sources of interference are considered: IEEE 802.11 (Wi-Fi) and IEEE 802.15.4 (Zigbee). Firstly, these interfering networks are characterized both in the frequency and in the time domains. Then, the coexistence of a WBAN with these interfering systems is assessed. We consider a WBAN as composed of wearable nodes that communicate with an on-body coordinator and we evaluate the achievable performance for three different physical layers and two different Carrier Sense Multiple Access with Collision Avoidance algorithms.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216832]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216832]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216832&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216832]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>56</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Energy consumption analysis of geographic routing in WSNs with location error]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Popescu, A. M.;  Salman, N.;  Kemp, A. H.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[School of Electronic and Electrical Engineering, University of Leeds, Leeds, United Kingdom]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Accuracy]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Energy consumption]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Power demand]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Geographic routing is an attractive option for wireless sensor networks (WSNs) because of its low overhead and energy expenditure, but it is based on assumptions of accurate knowledge of location. Positioning systems are inevitably imprecise because of inexact measurements. Location errors lead to poor performance of geographic routing in terms of packet delivery ratio, but little attention has been given to the effect on power consumption. This paper presents a study of energy consumption in WSNs which make use of geographic routing by investigating scenarios that incorporate localization inaccuracies. As previous work makes use of simplistic random uniform error models, the present work considers a normally distributed position error. The routing behavior is evaluated for a variation of the standard deviation of position error between 10&#x2013;30 percent of the considered radio range. It is found that when there is location error, more energy consumption is spent per dropped packets because of increased numbers and received packets have increased energy expense due to the length of routes. Also, investigations shed light on the percentage of failures and the consequent energy consumption due to loss of connectivity, lack of forwarding options with progress, traffic congestion and location error. It is concluded that resilience to location error is imperative, but attention to node placement is also necessary.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216876]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216876]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216876&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216876]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>57</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Quantified user behavior in user-in-the-loop spatially and demand controlled cellular systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Schoenen, Rainer;  Bulu, Gurhan;  Mirtaheri, Amir;  Beitelmal, Tamer;  Yanikomeroglu, Halim]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Communication Networks (ComNets), Faculty 6, RWTH Aachen University, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Cellular phones]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Companies]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Educational institutions]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Indexes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Pricing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[User-centric services are a growing concern. While the digital society definitely needs better quality-of-experience (QoE) for the user, his applications on smart mobile devices will continue to raise traffic in mobile radio networks by 100% per annum. Future generations of access technologies are challenged by this and the old over provisioning approach will not hold anymore, especially during busy hours. Congestion will happen more and more often, leading to a much worse QoE for everyone involved. Increasing the supply side by better spectral efficiency of 5G radio networks cannot work on its own, if demand is increasing faster than supply.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216846]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216846]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216846&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216846]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>58</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Sum-rate maximization of coordinated direct and relay systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Fan Sun;  Popovski, Petar;  Thai, Chan Dai Truyen;  de Carvalho, Elisabeth]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Department of Electronic Systems, Faculty of Engineering and Science, Aalborg University, DK-9220, Denmark]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Array signal processing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Upper bound]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vectors]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Joint processing of multiple communication flows in wireless systems has given rise to a number of novel transmission techniques, notably the two-way relaying based on wireless network coding. Recently, a related set of techniques has emerged, termed coordinated direct and relay (CDR) transmissions, where the constellation of traffic flows is more general than the two-way. Regardless of the actual traffic flows, in a CDR scheme the relay has a central role in managing the interference and boosting the overall system performance. In this paper we investigate the novel transmission modes, based on amplify-and-forward, that arise when the relay is equipped with multiple antennas and can use beamforming. We focus on one representative traffic type, with one uplink and one downlink users and consider the achievable sum-rate maximization relay beamforming. The beamforming criterion leads to a non-convex problem and we introduce a low-complexity iterative solution, as well as derive a sum-rate upper performance bound. Numerical results demonstrate an obvious benefit from the usage of multiple antennas at the relay node.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216883]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216883]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216883&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216883]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>59</rank>

<title><![CDATA[PAPR reduction in MIMO OFDM using unitary matrix precoding]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ezri, Doron;  Tsodik, Genadiy]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Greenair Wireless, Ramat Gan, Israel]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Peak to average power ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitting antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vectors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[3]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Peak to Average Power Ratio (PAPR) plays an important role in orthogonal frequency division multiplexing (OFDM) systems, and therefore has been addressed extensively in the literature, resulting in diverse mitigation techniques. OFDM systems employing multiple transmit and receive antennas (MIMO) have received less attention. These have mostly been considered as an extension of OFDM and have been addressed by similar techniques. In this paper we propose a new approach to PAPR reduction in OFDM MIMO, which is based on precoding with general unitary matrices. We exploit the fact that in certain MIMO transmission schemes, the capacity is invariant to unitary matrix precoding, and reveal new degrees of freedom allowing the minimization of PAPR. We propose a new unitary matrix based selective mapping (SLM) technique that jointly precodes all transmit antennas. The proposed method exhibits significant PAPR reduction at low computational complexity.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216892]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216892]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216892&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216892]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>60</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Time-reversal against optimum precoder over frequency-selective channels]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ferrante, Guido Carlo]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Sapienza University of Rome, ITALY]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multipath channels]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time frequency analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A comparison between two optimum precoders for frequency-selective SISO channels under different assumptions on the receiver is drawn. The first design foresees a jointly optimized transceiver (optimum precoder and all-Rake receiver) while the second constrains the receiver to be minimum complex (1-Rake) and consequently uses the optimized precoder, that is, Time-Reversal. Assuming an 802.15.3a channel model, analytical results based on the description of the channel as a single Cox process are proposed for the latter case. Simulations provide performance comparison with the former design showing the maximum precoding gain gap and the minimum Rake complexity required by the optimum precoder for a performance improvement.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216817]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216817]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216817&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216817]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>61</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Adaptive allocation of Virtual Radio Resources over heterogeneous wireless networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Caeiro, Luisa;  Cardoso, Filipe D.;  Correia, Luis M.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[CESET/ESTSet&#x00FA;bal, Polytechnic Institute of Set&#x00FA;bal, Portugal]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Availability]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Contracts]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Rats]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Virtual Networks and cloud services are hot topics nowadays, being considered, together with the information centric approach, key elements for the Future Internet. In this paper, an adaptive radio resource allocation mechanism for virtual resources sharing a common heterogeneous wireless infrastructure is presented and evaluated. The Virtual Network Radio Resource Allocation (VRRA) strategy being proposed takes advantage of the set of shared resources available within a cluster of wireless resources from different Radio Access Technologies (RATs), optimising their utilisation in order to maintain the contracted capacity. Simulation results show that the introduction of VRRA allows supporting the minimum bandwidth requirement in a wireless cluster, composed of several physical base stations from different RATs. For the Virtual Network providing high data rates and guaranteed services as presented in this paper, the Virtual Network Operator Satisfaction Level can be improved by 40% with the introduction of VRRA mechanisms.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216905]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216905]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216905&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216905]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>62</rank>

<title><![CDATA[SNR thresholds to meet a given error rate with practical cooperative relaying]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Dorling, Kevin;  Valentin, Stefan]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[University of Calgary, Canada]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Encoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Error analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.15 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Compared to direct transmission, cooperative relaying can substantially decrease the receiver's Signal-to-Noise Ratio (SNR) threshold to reach a given error rate. These SNR gains can be utilized to improve the error rate, energy consumption, or spectral efficiency of a wireless network. Focusing on practical half-duplex relaying, we derive the outage probability for a simple combining scheme, called Frame Selection (FS). We show that FS experiences only a minor performance drop compared to Maximum Ratio Combining (MRC) but makes cooperation easy to implement at the link layer. In addition, we provide numerical examples of SNR thresholds that can immediately be applied to choose the transmit power and rate in IEEE 802.15-based cooperative Wireless Sensor Networks (WSNs).]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216871]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216871]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216871&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216871]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>63</rank>

<title><![CDATA[THz and IR signaling through fog scintillations]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Moeller, Lothar;  Su, Ke;  Barat, Robert B.;  Federici, John F.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Bell Labs / Alcatel-Lucent, Holmdel, NJ 07733, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Attenuation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Laser beams]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optical attenuators]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optical fiber communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We report Terahertz (THz) and Infrared (IR) free-space signaling through fog and analyze impairments in both links caused by local refraction index changes in the propagation paths. Both channels carry a payload of 2.5 Gb/s which is modulated on carriers at 625 GHz (THz signal) and 193 THz (IR signal). To study the impact of weather conditions on the link performance the beams are superposed and pass through the same fog cloud before they are simultaneously recorded and analyzed. Fog scintillations degrade the IR channel but do not measurably impact the THz signal. BER and power measurements describe the performance of the signals.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216863]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216863]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216863&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216863]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>64</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Reducing communication overhead by scheduling TCP transfers on mobile devices using wireless network performance maps]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Hojgaard-Hansen, Kim;  Madsen, Tatiana K.;  Schwefel, Hans-Peter]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Networks and Security Section, Aalborg University, Denmark]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Databases]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Performance evaluation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The performance of wireless communication networks has been shown to have a strong location dependence. Measuring the performance while having accurate location information available makes it possible to generate performance maps. In this paper we propose a framework for the generation and use of such performance maps. We demonstrate how the framework can be used to reduce the retransmissions and to better utilise network resources when performing TCP-based file downloads in vehicular M2M communication scenarios. The approach works on top of a standard TCP stack hence has to map identified transmission intervals to predicted TCP data volumes. The file download optimisation is evaluated using extensive simulations comparing the TCP scheduling approach to a normal transfer. The performance map is generated by capturing round-trip time measurements and a threshold approach for the mean value for a given area is used to decide if data should be transmitted or not. A simple TCP model and a more advanced model are compared in their ability to accurately forecast how much data to transmit in the selected regions. The results show that using an intelligent TCP data transfer scheduling there is a significant potential for improvement in reducing the communication overhead compared with an ordinary TCP transfer.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216812]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216812]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216812&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216812]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>65</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Some comments to application of Cognition principle in Wireless Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Kontorovich, Valeri]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Electric Engineering Department (Communications), CINVESTAV-IPN, Av. IPN No. 2508, C.P. 07360, M&#x00E9;xico D.F., M&#x00E9;xico]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Cognition]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Covariance matrix]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Demodulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multiaccess communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensors]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Most of the publications related to Cognitive Radio (CR) Wireless Networks are devoted mainly to Spectrum Sensing problems and Resource Allocation for Cognitive Users (SU). So far, there is a high grade of understanding on how to provide solutions for the above mentioned problems as well as for the problems related to them.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216873]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216873]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216873&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216873]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>66</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On the performance evaluation of CSMA/E2CA protocol with open loop ARF-based adaptive modulation and coding]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Martorell, Gabriel;  Riera-Palou, Felip;  Femenias, Guillem;  Barcelo, Jaume;  Bellalta, Boris]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Mobile Communications Group -University of the Balearic Islands (Spain)]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Collision avoidance]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Object detection]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless LAN]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Carrier sense multiple access with collision avoidance (CSHA/CA) has been the access protocol of choice for IEEE 802.11-based WLANs. In addition to channel sensing before transmission, the probability of a collision in these WLANs is typically reduced by the application of a binary exponential backoff (BEB) algorithm that randomizes the selection of the time slot in which a given station transmits. In a system without adaptive modulation and coding (AHC), the reduction in spectral efficiency caused by BEB is outweighed by the reduction in the number of collisions. In contrast, in systems using the ubiquitous auto rate fallback (ARF) AHC algorithm, which is unable to distinguish a collision from an erroneous transmission, the remaining collisions induce a dramatic drop in system performance. This degradation is caused by the utilization of low-rate transmission modes even when the channel conditions would permit the use of much higher-rate modes. In an attempt to further reduce the number of collisions, a variant of CSHA/CA, called enhanced collision avoidance (CSHA/E2CA), has been recently proposed. In this paper, a model approach to the performance evaluation of both BEB-based CSHA/CA and CSHA/E2CA, used in conjunction with ARF, is presented and validated. Results reveal the synergistic properties of the E2CA and ARF combination, as demonstrated by the superior goodput performance when compared against other strategies.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216904]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216904]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216904&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216904]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>67</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Low-complexity channel estimation for 3GPP LTE terminals]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Xiaojun Ma;  Wen Xu]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Hays AG, Sonnenstrasse 31, 80331 M&#x00FC;nchen, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Computational complexity]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Filtering algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Maximum likelihood estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The 3GPP Long Term Evolution (LTE) system provides higher data rates than ever previously achieved in mobile communications. To achieve high data rates, especially under critical fading channels, accurate channel estimation is necessary. This usually leads to high complexity of the receiver. Therefore, it is critical to reduce the computational complexity of the channel estimation algorithm for a practical implementation, while at the same time maintaining the high performance. In this paper, problems on reducing computational complexity of the MMSE-based channel estimation algorithm for 3GPP LTE terminals are systematically investigated, and a practical high-performance and low-complexity algorithm is then proposed. The performance and computational complexity of the proposed algorithm are evaluated and compared with commonly used channel estimation algorithms under realistic environments. For the 5 MHz 2&#x00D7;2 LTE system and for the same throughput, the performance loss of the proposed algorithm compared with the full-size MMSE algorithm is within 1 dB channel SNR, whereas its computational complexity is reduced by about four orders. As a result, it can be cost-effectively implemented.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216836]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216836]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216836&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216836]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>68</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Maximizing spectral efficiency with acceptable service provision in multiple antennas scenarios]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Lima, F. Rafael M.;  Bezerra, Nibia S.;  dos Santos, Ricardo B.;  Maciel, Tarcisio F.;  Freitas, Walter da C.;  Cavalcanti, F. Rodrigo P.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Wireless Telecomunnications Research Group (GTEL) - Federal University of Cear&#x00E1; - Brazil]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitting antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this article we consider the problem of maximizing the total downlink data rate subject to minimum user satisfaction constraints in a multi-antenna, multi-resource and multi-service scenario. This problem is particularly interesting to current mobile operators that have to provide a wide range of data services with different rate requirements. We formulated the considered problem and show that it can be solved by standard linear integer optimization algorithms. Due to the high complexity of obtaining the optimum solution, we present a low complexity solution that, as shown in the simulation results, is capable of performing almost optimally in the considered scenario in terms of both outage rate and total downlink data rate performance metrics.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216859]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216859]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216859&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216859]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>69</rank>

<title><![CDATA[The internet of multimedia nano-things in the Terahertz band]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Jornet, Josep Miquel;  Akyildiz, Ian F.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Broadband Wireless Networking Laboratory, School of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, 30332, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Absorption]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Internet]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multimedia communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Nanobioscience]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Nanoscale devices]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Noise]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Nanotechnology is providing the engineering community with a new set of tools to design and manufacture advanced devices which are able to generate, process and transmit multimedia content at the nanoscale. The wireless interconnection of pervasively deployed multimedia nano-devices with existing communication networks and ultimately the Internet defines a truly cyber physical system which is further referred to as the Internet of Multimedia Nano-things (IoMNT). This paper discusses the state of the art and major research challenges in the realization of this novel networking paradigm, which has innumerable applications in the biomedical, defense, environmental and industrial fields. Fundamental research challenges and future research trends are outlined in terms of multimedia data and signal processing, Terahertz channel modeling for communication among nano-things, and protocols for the Internet of Multimedia Nano-Things. These include novel medium access control techniques, addressing schemes, neighbor discovery and routing mechanisms, a novel QoS-aware cross-layer communication module, and novel security solutions for the IoMNT.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216866]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216866]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216866&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216866]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>70</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Closed-loop extended orthogonal space-time coding for cognitive wireless relay networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Qaja, W.M.;  Chambers, J.A.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Advanced Signal Processing Group, Electronic and Electrical Engineering Department, Loughborough University, Leicestershire, UK, LE11 3TU]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Cognitive radio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Encoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, closed-loop extended orthogonal space-time-frequency-block coding (CL-EO-STFBC) is proposed for use within cognitive wireless relay networks. To exploit the available spectrum opportunities within the EO-STFBC, a spectrum indicator matrix is used in the development of the relay transmission scheme. The approach has the flexibility to dynamically adapt the code matrix to the number of available relays. The performance of the scheme is evaluated in terms of end-to-end frame error rate.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216855]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216855]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216855&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216855]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>71</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Adaptive modulation and coding with hybrid-ARQ for latency-constrained networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Villa, Tania;  Merz, Ruben;  Knopp, Raymond;  Takyar, Uday]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Eurecom, France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Automatic repeat request]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Encoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Modulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Traffic generated by machine to machine (M2M) communication or online gaming will be a large and integral part of the traffic transported by LTE-advanced and beyond networks. This traffic is characterized by sporadic and low-throughput packet arrivals. It must be scheduled under a latency constraint. Sporadic traffic creates environments where the channel-quality information (CQI) is outdated or unavailable. Fast-fading, the non-stationarity of inter-cell interference and the heterogeneity of Rel-10 networks further exacerbates this issue. However, current LTE-Advanced schedulers and resource allocation schemes are not optimized for these particular scenarios. In this paper, we propose a scheduling and resource allocation mechanism for latency-constrained operation. Our solution significantly improves the spectral efficiency of delay-constrained networks by optimizing a joint hybrid-ARQ and adaptive modulation and coding (AMC) policy that changes the number of dimensions (physical resources) used in each round. With only one bit of feedback, obtained causally from hybrid-ARQ, we achieve a performance close to the ergodic capacity.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216897]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216897]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216897&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216897]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>72</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Downlink performance of multiuser multi-relay cooperative networks: A low-complexity relay-destination selection scheme]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[de Melo, Marco Antonio Beserra;  da Costa, Daniel Benevides]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Department of Teleinformatics Engineering, Federal University of Cear&#x00E1;, Fortaleza, Brazil]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Complexity theory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Joints]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[System performance]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper investigates the outage performance of multiuser multi-relay cooperative networks in which a source node communicates with one out of L destinations through the help of one out of N decode-and-forward (DF) relays. A low-complexity relay-destination selection scheme is proposed, which first selects the best destination node based on the channel quality of the direct links and then selects the best relay that yields the best path from the source to the selected destination. In our analysis, the source node may be equipped with either a single antenna or M multiple antennas. A closed-form expression for the outage probability is derived and validated by means of Monte Carlo simulations. An asymptotic analysis is carried out and reveals that, for the single-antenna source case, the diversity order reduces to L+N, whereas for the multiple-antenna source case, the diversity order equals to ML + N. Assuming two network topologies, a comparison between our scheme and the optimal joint relay-destination selection scheme is provided and it reveals that the proposed selection scheme achieves a very close outage performance to that of the joint selection scheme while reduces considerably the system complexity (in terms of channel estimations, implementation issues, and simulation time). The effects of the number of relay and destination nodes on the system performance as well as its influence on the best relay position are examined through representative numerical plots. It is noticed a tradeoff concerns to the system performance and spectral efficiency when multiple antennas are employed. More specifically, in one hand, by increasing the number of antennas at the source node, a better outage behavior is obtained. On the other hand, the system loses in terms of spectral efficiency.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216850]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216850]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216850&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216850]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>73</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Interconnection of body area networks to a communications infrastructure: An architectural study]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bui, Nicola;  Bressan, Nicola;  Zorzi, Michele]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Department of Information Engineering, University of Padova - Via Gradenigo, 6b, 35131, Italy]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Internet]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Medical services]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network topology]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Many papers in the literature advocate the use of the Internet of Things communication paradigm to connect wearable body area networks with the Internet in order to create a global communication framework for electronic health care management. In this paper we analyze some of the most typical deployment layouts by extracting them from the health care use case of the IoT-A project. In particular, we focus our investigation on the transition phase happening during network topology changes; in fact, during these events it is challenging to satisfy such functional requirements as promptness and availability. Moreover, we take into account how open standard communication protocols such as 6LoWPAN and RPL behave during device mobility and network handover; we highlight issues and propose some simple yet feasible strategies to improve the body area network performance during such events.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216833]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216833]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216833&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216833]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>74</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A model for OFDM signals with applications]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Kotzer, Igal;  Har-Nevo, Smadar;  Sodin, Sasha;  Litsyn, Simon]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[School of Electrical Engineering - Systems, Tel Aviv University, Israel]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Computational modeling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Peak to average power ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Random variables]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Simulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time domain analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vectors]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A novel model for constant energy constellation (the data is drawn from equi-energy symbols) discrete time OFDM signal is presented. Based on this model the moments of the OFDM signal's envelope maximum as well as the moments of the energy of the clipped portion of the signal are computed. It is also shown that the rate at which the expected value of the maximum scales with the length of the signal coincides with Halasz' result. Simulation are presented, which show that this model gives much better results than the conventional Gaussian model in approximation of statistical properties of an OFDM signal.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216895]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216895]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216895&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216895]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>75</rank>

<title><![CDATA[eCoMove: Cooperative ITS for green mobility]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Pandazis, Jean-Charles]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[ERTICO - ITS Europe, Brussels, Belgium]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Air pollution]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fuels]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Logistics]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Roads]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vehicles]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[eCoMove project envisions fuel consumption reduction in road transport by 20% by applying information and communication technologies, in particular Cooperative ITS communication based on latest international standards used to support innovative green mobility applications. The eCoMove communication platform is based on results from previous EU funded projects like CVIS and SAFESPOT. This paper presents an overview of eCoMove project, the systems concept and applications. At the conference the simulation setup for evaluating the expected impact will be presented, as well as: the evolution of the existing cooperative platform(s) to conform to eCoMove requirements, the Communication Stack supporting green applications developed in eCoMove, and finally the participation of eCoMove to the ETSI PLUGTEST in Helmond showing interoperability with DRIVE-C2X implementation. cooperative its; green mobility]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216886]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216886]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216886&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216886]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>76</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Network coding aided Device-to-Device communication]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Rodziewicz, Marcin]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Faculty of Electronics and Telecommunication, Poznan University of Technology, Poland]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Binary phase shift keying]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper proposes an application of Device-to-Device communication in a wireless network which exploits network coding to enhance its performance. In the proposed scheme users involved in direct Device-to-Device transmission utilize the base station as a support for their transmission. The base station does not use simulcast transmission to forward users information but it uses multicast transmission instead contrary to some relaying approaches. To achieve multicast transmission the base station utilizes network coding which allows to transmit multiple linearly independent data streams in a single stream which is most commonly a linear combination of component streams. This solution allows for reduction of used resources measured in number of transmission time slots and also possibly enhances the transmission quality, as well as the range of Device-to-Device communication. The applicability of the proposed solution is verified via computer simulations.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216828]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216828]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216828&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216828]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>77</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On achievable rate of multicarrier with practical high power amplifier]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Gutman, Igor;  Wulich, Dov]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Beer-Sheva, 84105, Israel]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[AWGN]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mutual information]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Nonlinear distortion]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper investigates the achievable rate of multicarrier systems with non-linear distortion caused by high power amplifier (HPA) at the transmitter. We derive mutual information expressions for several non-linear models of HPA. Specific results are given for different values of the input backoff. It is shown that for some cases, linearization of HPA is not the best strategy.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216891]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216891]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216891&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216891]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>78</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Cooperative load balancing for OFDMA cellular networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Lexi Xu;  Yue Chen;  Kok Keong Chai;  Tiankui Zhang;  Schormans, John;  Cuthbert, Laurie]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[School of Electronic Engineering and Computer Science, Queen Mary University of London, United Kingdom]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Educational institutions]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Load management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Load modeling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Traffic shifting based load balancing (LB) schemes reduce the load of the hot-spot base station (BS), by shifting its traffic to its less-loaded neighbouring cells, called partners. Under the condition of multiple hot-spot BSs shifting traffic to one partner, this partner becomes a public partner. In conventional LB schemes, each hot-spot BS makes its traffic shifting decision independently. This could result in the public partner becoming heavily loaded, which is defined as the &#x201C;aggravating load&#x201D; problem in this paper. The aggravating load problem increases the call blocking probability of the public partner and might lead to LB handover failure. This paper proposes a cooperative LB scheme, which is composed of a relative load response model for solving the aggravating load problem, and a relative load based traffic shifting mechanism. Simulation results show the proposed cooperative LB scheme can mitigate the aggravating load problem and keep LB handover failure rate at low level.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216810]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216810]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216810&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216810]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>79</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Evaluations and measurements of a single frequency network with DRM+]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Maier, Friederike;  Tissen, Andrej;  Waal, Albert]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Institute of Communications Technology, Leibniz University of Hanover, Germany, Hanover, Appelstrasse 9A]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antenna measurements]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radio transmitters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Standards]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents the first DRM+ (Digital Radio Mondiale, Mode E) Single Frequency Network (SFN) in the air. A field trial has been conducted to evaluate the performance in different environments. Due to it's relatively small bandwidth, flat fading in the overlapping area can become a problem. Different solutions to overcome this problem are evaluated in this paper. Adding different delays to transmitters side-by-side is a solution to overcome the flat fading. In the field trial the error rates in the overlapping area in a two TX setup with delay were significantly smaller than without delay, the probability of deep fades was becoming smaller. This paper provides parameters for applying a Single Frequency Network with DRM+.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216838]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216838]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216838&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216838]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>80</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Decode-and-forward relay placement for maximum cell spectral efficiency]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Sambale, Klaus;  Walke, Bernhard]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Communication Networks (ComNets) Research Group, Faculty 6, RWTH Aachen University, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radio frequency]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time division multiplexing]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[To meet increasing capacity demands in mobile radio networks Decode-and-Forward (DF) Relay Stations (RSs) have been proposed. In our work we investigate the potential of low power DF-RSs to increase the Cell Spectral Efficiency (CSE) under rate fair scheduling. We introduce a model based on simulated-annealing to find optimal position and antenna height for DF-RSs in a cellular network. The results show that three small-sized low power DF-RSs per cell (sector) that operate simultaneously almost doubles the CSE compared to a network without RSs.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216852]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216852]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216852&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216852]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>81</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On estimation aspects of WLAN secondary spectrum availability in ATC radar band]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Karamacoski, Jovan;  Latkoski, Pero;  Gavrilovska, Liljana]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Information Technologies, Ss. Cyril and Methodius University, Skopje, Macedonia]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Availability]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Gain]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radar]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radar antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sea measurements]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper analyzes the secondary spectrum availability in case of WiFi-like secondary system operating in air traffic control (ATC) radar band. The estimated amount of opportunistic spectrum depends on plethora of radar characteristics as well as on many assumptions made during the assessment. The paper summarizes the key requirements for a realistic estimation of WLAN secondary spectrum availability through a case study using the territory of Republic of Macedonia as an example study area. The analysis provides details of a modeling technique which gives an accurate spectrum occupancy prediction validated through field measurements. The paper also investigates the influence of the actual terrain, in terms of the geographical distribution and amount of acceptable WLAN positions allowed for spectrum re-use with regards to the radar location. The results prove that the exact knowledge of the radar position and its operating parameters are a necessity for providing an accurate estimate of secondary spectrum availability.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216911]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216911]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216911&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216911]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>82</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Joint backhaul co-scheduling and relay cell extension in LTE-advanced networks uplink performance evaluation]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Kifle, Dereje Woldemedhin;  Bulakci, Omer;  Saleh, Abdallah Bou;  Redana, Simone;  Granelli, Fabrizio]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[DISI - University of Trento, via Sommarive 14 - 38123, Italy]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[3GPP has standardized Type-1 in-band relay to be an integral part of LTE-A in order to meet the service coverage and performance requirement in a cost efficient manner. In an LTE-A relay network, users served directly by the eNodeB share resources with relay nodes communicating on the backhaul link. Besides, the end-to-end throughput of users served by RNs is determined by the achievable throughput on their access links and the available throughput on the relay backhaul link. As a consequence, the overall system performance is defined by the resource allocation strategy employed and resource balance maintained between the various links. Moreover, due to their low transmit power level in downlink, RNs have smaller cell coverage which creates unbalanced load distribution between the macro and relay cells. This further limits the performance of RN deployments. In this paper, the uplink performance of a relay enhanced LTE-A system is evaluated by utilizing a co-scheduling methodology at the donor eNodeB, where macro users are scheduled with RNs during the backhaul subframes, along with relay cell coverage extension to maintain a better load balance in the system. Furthermore, system optimization has been carried out by jointly considering uplink power control and backhaul subframe allocation. Simulation results show that the employed resource sharing strategy and cell coverage extension technique significantly improve the throughput achieved by the users in the uplink.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216848]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216848]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216848&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216848]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>83</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On-body area networks: from channel measurements to MAC layer performance evaluation]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Rosini, Ramona;  Martelli, Flavia;  Maman, Mickael;  D'Errico, Raffaele;  Buratti, Chiara;  Verdone, Roberto]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[CEA, LETI, Minatec Campus, 17 rue des Martyrs, 38054 Grenoble, France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Ear]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Heart]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.15 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multiaccess communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Performance evaluation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents the simulation results on the performance evaluation and comparison of different Medium Access Control (MAC) protocols for on-body area networks proposed in the scope of the WiserBAN project. A number of different MAC schemes, based on existing and emerging standards, were investigated to satisfy the peculiar use-cases requirements in terms of Packet Loss Rate, transmission delay, and energy consumption. A specific measurement campaign was performed to characterise the on-body propagation channel related to the WiserBAN scenarios. Channel measurements and previous channel models were employed for MAC simulation purposes, in order to investigate the channel impact on the system performance.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216831]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216831]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216831&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216831]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>84</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Investigation on transmission power control in heterogeneous network employing cell range expansion for LTE-Advanced uplink]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Morimoto, Akihito;  Miki, Nobuhiko;  Ishii, Hiroyuki;  Nishikawa, Daisuke]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[NTT DOCOMO, INC., 3-6 Hikari-no-oka, Yokosuka-shi, Kanagawa-ken, 239-8536 Japan]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Macrocell networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Propagation losses]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Shadow mapping]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In Long-Term Evolution (LTE)-Advanced, heterogeneous networks where femtocells and picocells are overlaid onto macrocells are extensively discussed in addition to traditional well-planned macrocell deployments to improve further the system throughput. In heterogeneous networks, cell range expansion (CRE), which is a technique for expanding the cell radius of picocells by biasing the handover criteria, is applied so that the UEs will more frequently select the picocells. This paper investigates the transmission power control (TPC) method in the heterogeneous networks that employ CRE and evaluates the cell-edge user throughput and cell throughput performance. Simulation results (4 picocells and 25 UEs are located within 1 macrocell and the difference in transmission power between the macrocell and picocells is 16 dB) show that almost the same cell-edge user throughput is obtained by setting the appropriate difference in the target received signal power between the macrocell and picocells according to the CRE offset value.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216901]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216901]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216901&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216901]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>85</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Challenges and improvement strategies for the physical layer in vehicular communications]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Budde, Robert;  Kays, Rudiger]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Communication Technology Institute, TU Dortmund University, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Demodulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Diversity reception]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Physical layer]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[3]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The physical layer is a key component for the overall performance of a wireless transmission system. It has to meet the specific needs and environmental conditions to which the system is exposed. IEEE 802.11p, which is the predominant standard used for vehicular communication up to now, inherits certain shortcomings from its predecessor, IEEE 802.11a. In this paper, we discuss the various environmental effects entailed with vehicle-to-vehicle communication as well as several techniques to mitigate the shortcomings of the standard. V2V communication, IEEE 802.11p, WAVE, OFDM]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216885]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216885]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216885&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216885]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>86</rank>

<title><![CDATA[In-cabin downlink cell planning with Fractional Frequency Reuse]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Valcarce, Alvaro;  Lucas, Merce;  Lopez-Perez, David]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[TriaGnoSys GmbH, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Aerospace electronics]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Aircraft]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Atmospheric modeling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Due to the growing demand for ubiquitous Internet access, airlines are seeking profitable solutions for providing wireless services for aircraft passengers. Furthermore, novel Inflight Entertainment (IFE) services targeted at mobile phones are already steering rising in-cabin wireless capacity demands. In certain deployments, one mobile cell may not provide sufficient capacity to accommodate the high capacity demand. Therefore, multi-cell schemes may have to be deployed inside of the aircraft. In this way the achievable user throughput can be increased and the spectral occupation minimized (specially when flying above foreign lands with diverse spectrum policies). In order to optimize the SINR of multi-cell deployments within aircraft, this paper proposes a wireless topology based on Fractional Frequency Reuse (FFR). It is then shown that this approach can increase the cell-edge SINR in approximately 6 dB with respect to a multi-cell deployment lacking FFR.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216903]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216903]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216903&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216903]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>87</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Modification of selected propagation models in terms of path loss estimation in container terminal]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ambroziak, Slawomir J.;  Katulski, Ryszard J.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Department of Radiocommunication Systems and Networks, Faculty of Electronics, Telecommunications and Informatics, Gdansk University of Technology, Poland]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Containers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Data models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Loss measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Propagation losses]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitting antennas]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[It is particularly important to look for any propagation model that could be useful for designing mobile radio networks in container terminal environment. Selected propagation models have been investigated. Firstly - basing on measurements results - they have been evaluated in this scope and the analysis has shown, that the adjustment is needed. This modification improved significantly the accuracy of path loss modelling. For the best adjusted model - ITU-R P. 1411 described in &#x00A7;4.2.2 - the mean error equals &#x2212;0.1 dB, the standard error of estimate equals 5 dB, and the coefficient of determination is 0.785. These results mean that the adjusted model fits very well to experimental data.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216909]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216909]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216909&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216909]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>88</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Broadband Active integrated circuits for Terahertz communication]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Kallfass, I.;  Antes, J.;  Lopez-Diaz, D.;  Wagner, S.;  Tessmann, A.;  Leuther, A.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Karlsruhe Institute of Technology, Kaiserstrasse 12, D-76131, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Gain]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MMICs]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mixers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radio frequency]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We describe active millimeter-wave monolithic integrated circuits (MMICs) dedicated to directional links serving as bit-transparent wireless bridges in fiber-optical systems. The design and performance of amplifiers, frequency converters and frequency multipliers are discussed. The 10 m transmission of a 25 Gbit/s on-off-keying signal based on multi-functional MMICs operating at an RF center frequency of 220 GHz is shown. Finally, a chip set for a broadband wireless link in the RF frequency range from 200 to 280 GHz is presented.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216865]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216865]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216865&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216865]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>89</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Physical-layer network coding based interference exploitation strategy for multi-user hierarchical wireless networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Dong Fang;  Peng Li;  Burr, Alister;  de Lamare, Rodrigo]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Department of Electronics, University of York, YO10 5DD, United Kingdom]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time division multiple access]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The hierarchical wireless network [1] (HWN) is a promising and popular network architecture which has the capability to support numerous mobile stations (MSs). In the deployment of HWN, the relay nodes (RN) serve as the switching ports for the hub base station (HBS) in the backhaul network (BH) and the MSs in access network (AC) to exchange their own information. However, the co-channel interference (CCI) severely limits the system performance when the incoming signals reach the RNs. Thus, we proposed an effective interference exploitation strategy in which by employing a DS-CDMA scheme, the proposed design can exploit the CCI to provide a diversity benefit, while the physical-layer network coding (PNC) is used to encompass the inter-channel interference (ICI). In this way any form of interference is treated as useful information. It is shown by simulation that the proposed scheme shows advantages in terms of low system complexity, high flexibility, easy deployment and good performance.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216851]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216851]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216851&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216851]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>90</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Branch canceling technique for turbo TCM decoding]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Sybis, Michal]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Wireless Communications, Poznan University of Technology, Poland]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[AWGN channels]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Complexity theory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Rayleigh channels]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Turbo codes]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A new complexity reducing technique for turbo trellis-coded modulation (TTCM) is presented. The novel technique is investigated in conjunction with Max-Log-MAP decoding algorithm and is evaluated in terms of complexity and bit error rate (BER) performance in an additive white Gaussian noise (AWGN) channel and uncorrelated, i.e. fully interleaved Rayleigh fading channel. This novel method is based on the assumption that not all of the branches in the trellis have to be taken into consideration in calculating the state metric in turbo TCM decoding. Computer simulated BER performance evaluation results and complexity comparison are reported, showing Max-Log-MAP algorithm equivalent performance as well as noticeably lower computational complexity in comparison to Max-Log-MAP.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216913]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216913]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216913&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216913]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>91</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Towards a radio channel model for off-body communications in a multipath environment]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Mackowiak, Michal;  Correia, Luis M.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Instituto de Telecomunica&#x00E7;&#x00F5;es / Instituto Superior T&#x00E9;cnico, Technical University of Lisbon, Portugal]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antenna radiation patterns]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Legged locomotion]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receiving antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Standards]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper introduces a radio channel model for off-body communications in a multipath environment. The modelling of wearable antennas in Body Area Networks has been separated into antennas in the vicinity of the body (full wave simulations), including body dynamics (taken from motion capture analysis), and street environment (clusters of scatterers). Multi-Path Components are calculated using a Geometrically Based Statistical Channel model. A street scenario is simulated, for a running or walking body, and for 4 on-body antenna placements (i.e., front of the head, left and right arm, and back). The propagation conditions are determined (i.e., LoS or NLoS) and statistics of basic radio channel parameters (i.e., received power, delay and angular spreads) are calculated. The received power depends strongly on propagation conditions, and varies a lot in the case of antenna placement on the left hand and Run scenario (standard deviation of 5.4 dB). For this antenna placement, the average delay spread is the lowest, 88 ns, but varies a lot, depending on the location in the environment and the body posture (standard deviation of 25 ns).]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216830]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216830]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216830&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216830]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>92</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Performance of relay-enhanced networks under transmission power constraints]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Gora, Jacek]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Nokia Siemens Networks - Research, Wroc&#x0142;aw, Poland]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Equations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radio link]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Standards]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper investigates performance of cellular networks facing the need to limit power consumption, e.g. in case of multi-carrier operation. It is shown that simple reduction of the transmission power spectral density of macro base stations is not a good solution, as it significantly decreases the network's performance. In the paper it is proposed to deploy relay nodes to compensate for the network's coverage and capacity loss. Both two-hop and multi-hop relaying configurations are evaluated with several levels of macro station transmission power reduction. It is shown that even though the two-hop relaying configuration fully restores the network's coverage and capacity it is not the most optimal solution. The multi-hop relaying, on the other hand, shows potential to significantly improve performance of networks facing power consumption restrictions.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216889]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216889]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216889&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216889]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>93</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Markov chain model for performance analysis of VBR voice using multiple thresholds]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Balapuwaduge, Indika A. M.;  Lei Jiao;  Li, Frank Y.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Information and Communication Technology, University of Agder (UiA), N-4898 Grimstad, Norway]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Analytical models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bit rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Codecs]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Limiting]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Numerical models]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Statistical multiplexing is a popular technique used in digital communications in order to increase utilization efficiency of system resources. Variable bit rate (VBR) voice coding is an example of such multiplexing technique and has been widely used in digital telephony. While fixed rate codec allows only a limited number of simultaneous connections, VBR encoding allows the codec to alter its bit rate dynamically, depending on the instantaneous traffic demand and resource utilization status. In this paper, we propose a scheme to increase the number of simultaneous VBR connections for a system with limited number of channels. When there are more calls, the bit rates of the ongoing connections are decreased and new connections are accommodated by the saved bandwidth. Multiple threshold levels are adopted to increase the number of high data rate connections. The system performance of the proposed scheme is analyzed through Markov chain modelling and the developed analytical model is also validated by simulations. Numerical results demonstrate that the concept of multiple thresholds leads to better performance of the system, represented by a higher percentage of high rate calls.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216816]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216816]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216816&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216816]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>94</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Energy efficient clustering using a wake-up receiver]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Blanckenstein, Johannes;  Klaue, Jirka;  Karl, Holger]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[EADS Innovation Works, Dept. IW-SI-CO, 81663 Munich, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Clustering algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transceivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We present a new energy-saving method for creating node clusters with similar sensor readings. The idea is to wake up a node/main transceiver only when data correlated to the node's own data is transmitted. This is achieved by encoding relevant parts of local data in a wake-up receiver's data pattern. Through this new protocol the building of clusters becomes highly energy-efficient, even if re-clustering is required, the energy consumed for clustering is still low. For environments where re-clustering is often necessary a clustering scheme can be used to further reduce the energy consumption. This further reduction can be achieved efficiently through the transmission of the sensor readings from only one node of the cluster to the data sink. One reading is therefore sufficient to approximate the readings of the whole cluster because all nodes within this cluster have similar sensor readings.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216879]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216879]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216879&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216879]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>95</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On the importance of loss differentiation for link adaptation in wireless LANs]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Kriara, Lito;  Pediaditaki, Sofia;  Marina, Mahesh K.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[School of Informatics, The University of Edinburgh, UK]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless LAN]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In current wireless LANs multiple kinds of losses occur (i.e., channel errors, collisions, interference). In this paper we examine the extent to which loss differentiation based physical layer transmission bit-rate and contention window adaptation aids in improving network performance. We show that loss differentiation can have a positive impact on performance, especially in low contention scenarios. Crucially, the same performance can also be achieved even without the use of loss differentiation as long as the appropriate rate and contention window adaptation mechanisms are used. Our study on the impact of loss differentiation led us to develop Themis, a novel bit-rate and contention window adaptation scheme that does not rely on loss differentiation. Themis considerably improves performance over both the standard 802.11a/b/g and SampleRate in terms of throughput and fairness by reducing hidden nodes.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216906]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216906]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216906&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216906]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>96</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Energy efficiency and capacity of heterogeneous network deployment in LTE-Advanced]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Saker, L.;  Elayoubi, S.E.;  Chahed, T.;  Gati, A.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Orange Labs, 38-40 rue du G&#x00E9;n&#x00E9;ral Leclerc, 92130 Issy-Les-Moulineaux, France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Energy efficiency]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Femtocells]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Power demand]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quality of service]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We study in this paper the impact of small cells on the capacity and energy consumption of an LTE-Advanced network in a heterogeneous setting where macro cells coexist with outdoor pico and femtocells. We analyze the Erlang-like capacity in such an environment and show the gains obtained from offloading traffic from macro cells to small ones. Energy efficiency is used throughout this study, bringing together network performance and its overall power consumption. Our results show that small cells are a good alternative to network densification as they achieve higher network capacities with good energy efficiency. In order to further improve the efficiency of the resulting heterogeneous network, we propose a sleep mode that switches off some picocells when the traffic is low and quantify the resulting increase in efficiency.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216900]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216900]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216900&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216900]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>97</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Local Area Network Dynamic (LANDY) routing protocol: A position based routing protocol for MANET]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Macintosh, A.;  Ghavami, M.;  Siyau, M. F.;  Ling, S. L.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[BiMEC, Dept. of Engineering &amp; Design, London South Bank University, Borough Road, SE1 0AA, UK]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Broadcasting]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Global Positioning System]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile ad hoc networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The issue of routing and maintaining packets between mobile nodes (MNs) in the mobile ad hoc networks (MANETs) has always been a challenge; i.e. encountering broadcast storm under high node density, geographically constrained broadcasting of a service discovery message and local maximum problem under low node density. This requires an efficient design and development of a &#x2018;light-weight&#x2019; routing algorithm which can be handled by those GPS equipped devices. Our proposed protocol, Local Area Network Dynamic routing (LANDY) uses a localized routing technique which combines an unique locomotion prediction method and velocity information of MNs to route packets, which is capable of improving the routing performance in advanced mobility scenarios by reducing the control overhead. Simulations have been carried out with randomising the mobility speed and number of nodes and the preliminary results illustrate that LANDY's performance is better compared to other position based routing protocols.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216813]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216813]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216813&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216813]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>98</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Wireless Sensor Network design for the Help4Mood european project]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Perez-Diaz de Cerio, D.;  Ruiz Boque, S.;  Rosell-Ferrer, J.;  Ramos-Castro, J.;  Castro, J.C.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Batteries]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bluetooth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decision support systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Watches]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Help4Mood is a closed loop approach supporting the control, communication and treatment management of patients with Major Depression. The first out of the three main components of the Help4Mood solution is the Personal Monitoring System (PMS), a set of different wireless sensors whose data sink is centralized on a laptop. The objective of this PMS is to monitor the activity of the patients, so several sensors have been chosen to cover the needs of different individuals. These include a wrist watch, a key ring, a waist/belt sensor, an under mattress sensor and a cellular phone. This paper describes the first prototype and the results obtained from this Wireless Sensor Network.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216834]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216834]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216834&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216834]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>99</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Cross-layer modeling of wireless systems using AMC with cooperative-ARQ error control]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ramis, Jaume;  Femenias, Guillem]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Mobile Communications Group, University of the Balearic Islands, Ctra. de Valldemossa Km. 7,5, Spain]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Markov processes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Physical layer]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Cross-layer designs combining adaptive modulation and coding (AMC) with automatic repeat request (ARQ) have recently been widely explored. In addition, cooperative communication has attracted increased research attention as a promising technique for achieving diversity gain in wireless networks. In this paper a novel cross-layer analytical framework to jointly exploit the capabilities of cooperative-ARQ and AMC is proposed. The framework is based on a multidimensional discrete-time Markov chain (DTMC) queuing model. To exploit the joint impact on quality-of-service (QoS) performance measures of both AMC and cooperative-ARQ, a formulation of a cross-layer design as a constrained optimization problem is presented. Numerical results confirm the validity of the model and reveal that the proposed cooperative-ARQ protocol consistently outperforms the non-cooperative counterpart.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216827]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216827]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216827&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216827]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>100</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Performance evaluation of cooperative spectrum sensing in multiband environments]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Pavlovska, Valentina;  Atanasovski, Vladimir;  Gavrilovska, Liljana]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Ss. Cyril and Methodius University, Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Information Technologies, Skopje, Macedonia]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Decision support systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The concept of cognitive radio networking promises a solution for the problem of spectrum underutilization. It introduces secondary cognitive network into a primary network with aim to utilize temporary vacant spectrum parts. The multiband spectrum sensing environment allows higher probability for opportunities detection and thus higher utilization of vacant spectrum parts. The cooperation among the secondary users ensures more reliable and faster spectrum opportunity detection. This paper introduces an analytical model for cooperative multiband spectrum sensing (CMSS) and demonstrates the benefits of cooperation in terms of improved throughput performance. Additionally, it illustrates a mean for quantitative determination of optimal sensing duration and appropriate number of cooperative nodes for different fusion techniques. The analytical results are confirmed with simulation results.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216874]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216874]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216874&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216874]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>101</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A hybrid cooperative design for energy-efficient surveillance in Wireless Multimedia Sensor Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Alaei, Mohammad;  Barcelo-Ordinas, Jose M.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Computer Architecture Department, Polytechnic University of Catalunya (UPC), Barcelona, Spain]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Acoustic sensors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Acoustics]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Detectors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Visualization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In Wireless Multimedia Sensor Networks (WMSNs) the lifetime of battery-operated visual nodes is limited by their energy consumption, which is proportional to the energy required for sensing, processing, and transmitting the data. Given the large amount of data generated by the visual nodes, both processing and transmitting image data are quite costly in terms of energy in comparison with other types of sensor networks. Therefore, energy efficiency is a main concern in WMSNs. In this paper an energy efficient collaborative mechanism for environment surveillance is proposed. The proposed scheme employs a mixed random deployment of acoustic and visual sensor nodes. Acoustic sensors detect and localize the occurred event/object(s) in a duty-cycled manner by sampling the received signals and then trigger the visual sensor nodes covering the objects to monitor them. Hence, visual sensors are warily scheduled to be awakened just for monitoring the object(s) detected in their domain, otherwise they save their energy.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216877]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216877]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216877&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216877]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>102</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Rotationally Invariant Coded Modulation for physical layer network coding in two-way relay fading channel]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Dong Fang;  Burr, Alister]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Department of Electronics, University of York, YO10 5DD, United Kingdom]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Demodulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Phase shift keying]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We investigate a novel coded modulation scheme for physical layer network coding (PLNC) in the two-way relay (TWR) fading channel. Using an adaptive soft demodulator and independent decoding levels, the proposed scheme can eliminate the effect of fading on the TWR channel. To reduce system complexity at the relay, we also give a low-complexity two-demodulator scheme. Based on maximizing the mutual information between received signal and network coded symbol, the adaptive selection of the two demodulators is then optimized. The proposed simplified scheme exhibits advantages in terms of flexibility, complexity and performance.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216898]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216898]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216898&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216898]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>103</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Achievable energy per bit for the multi-pair MIMO bidirectional broadcast channel]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Do, Tan Tai;  Oechtering, Tobias J.;  Skoglund, Mikael]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Royal Institute of Technology (KTH), ACCESS Linnaeus Center, SE-100 44 Stockholm, Sweden]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[AWGN]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Covariance matrix]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vectors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wideband]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents a transmit strategy for the AWGN multi-pair MIMO bidirectional broadcast channels in the wideband regime. An achievable wideband rate region and an achievable energy per bit region are provided. The transmit covariance matrix at the relay has been designed in order to maximize the wideband weighted rate sum. A closed form of the optimal matrix is derived, which shows that a single beam transmit strategy is optimal. In addition, an energy efficiency versus fairness analysis is considered. Lastly, some discussions on the minimum energy per bit are given.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216869]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216869]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216869&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216869]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>104</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Peak-to-average power ratio distribution analysis of single-carrier FDMA signals]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ochiai, Hideki]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Yokohama National University, 79-5 Tokiwadai, Hodogaya, Kanagawa 240-8501, Japan]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Discrete Fourier transforms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Frequency division multiaccess]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Peak to average power ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Phase shift keying]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quadrature amplitude modulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper investigates the distribution of the peak-to-average power ratio (PAPR) of single-carrier frequency-division multiple-access (SC-FDMA) signals. An analytical approach that can numerically calculate its approximate distribution is presented. It is shown that the simulation and analytical results match in the dynamic range region of practical interest. We also compare the SC-FDMA with the corresponding orthogonal frequency-division multiplexing (OFDM) employing clipping and filtering in terms of PAPR and resulting average mutual information.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216893]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216893]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216893&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216893]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>105</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Evaluation and improvement of VoIP capacity for LTE]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Muhleisen, Maciej;  Walke, Bernhard]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[ComNets Research Group, Faculty 6, RWTH Aachen University, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Dynamic scheduling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Scheduling algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[LTE-Advanced (LTE-A) proposed by the 3rd Generation Partnership Project (3GPP) has been accepted by the International Telecommunication Union (ITU) in 2010 as an IMT-Advanced (IMT-A) compliant 4G mobile radio system. Besides high spectral efficiency for data services, LTE-A had to prove its capability to support a large number of voice calls through Voice over IP (VoIP).]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216845]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216845]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216845&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216845]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>106</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Improving broadcast channel rate using hierarchical modulation]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Meric, Hugo;  Lacan, Jerome;  Arnal, Fabrice;  Lesthievent, Guy;  Boucheret, Marie-Laure]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[T&#x00E9;SA, Toulouse, France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Digital video broadcasting]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Encoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Modulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We investigate the design of a broadcast system where the aim is to maximise the throughput. This task is usually challenging due to the channel variability. Modern satellite communications systems such as DVB-SH and DVB-S2 mainly rely on time sharing strategy to optimize throughput. They consider hierarchical modulation but only for unequal error protection or backward compatibility purposes. We propose in this article to combine time sharing and hierarchical modulation together and show how this scheme can improve the performance in terms of available rate. We present the gain on a simple channel modeling the broadcasting area of a satellite. Our work is applied to the DVB-SH standard, which considers hierarchical modulation as an optional feature.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216821]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216821]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216821&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216821]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>107</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On the performance of LTE-Advanced MIMO: How to set and reach beyond 4G targets]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Lahetkangas, Eeva;  Pajukoski, Kari;  Tiirola, Esa;  Hamalainen, Jyri;  Zhong Zheng]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Radio Research, Nokia Siemens Networks, Oulu, Finland]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Modulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Simulation]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[European Wireless, 2012. EW. 18th European Wireless Conference]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[6216325]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2012]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Standardization of 3GPP LTE-Advanced (LTE-A), also called as 4G, is continuing strongly. Yet, in parallel the discussion on performance targets for systems beyond 4G have been initiated in industry. The aim of this paper is to investigate the link level performance of LTE-A downlink (DL) when large antenna array MIMO is employed. The link level simulation results show very high user throughputs when employing e.g. 8x8 MIMO. Yet, the comparison between simulation results and known spectral efficiency bounds show that LTE-A performance is still quite far away from theoretical limits. Results also indicate that realistic beyond 4G peak rate target on link level can be set close to 10 Gbps provided that 8x8 MIMO and 256QAM are applied, and the operation bandwidth can be doubled from current 100MHz. The spatial correlation in both transmitter and receiver ends will reduce the performance.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8008-3426-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[6216843]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[6216843]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=6216843&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=6216843]]></pdf>

</document>

</root>
