<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<root>

<totalfound>113</totalfound>

<totalsearched>3815492</totalsearched>

<document>

<rank>1</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Modelling the broadband wireless channel in rural Australia]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ratnayake, N.L.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Queensland Univ. of Technol., Brisbane, QLD, Australia]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Broadband communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Rain]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wind]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[2]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The internet infrastructure which supports high data rates has a major impact on the Australian economy and the world. However, in rural Australia, the provision of broadband services to an internet dispersed population over a large geographical area with low population densities remains both an economic and technical challenge [1]. Furthermore, the implementation of currently available technologies such as fibre-to-the-premise (FTTP), 3G, 4G and WiMAX seems to be impractical, considering the low population density that is distributed in a large area. Therefore, new paradigms and innovative telecommunication technologies need to be explored to overcome the challenges of providing faster and more reliable broadband internet services to internet dispersed rural areas. The research project implements an innovative Multi-User-Single-Antenna for MIMO (MUSA-MIMO) technology using the spectrum currently allocated to analogue TV. MUSA-MIMO technology can be considered as a special case of MIMO technology, which is beneficial when provisioning reliable and high-speed communication channels. Particularly, the abstract describes the development of a novel MUSA-MIMO channel model that takes into account temporal variations in the rural wireless environment. This can be considered as a novel approach tailor-made to rural Australia for provisioning efficient wireless broadband communications.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534973]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534973]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534973]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534973&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534973]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>2</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Opportunistically supported ubiquitous localization: Machine learning enhancements]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Papandrea, M.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[SUPSI, Univ. of Appl. Sci. of Southern Switzerland, Manno, Switzerland]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Global Positioning System]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Hidden Markov models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Machine learning]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile handsets]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Performance evaluation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Predictive models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensors]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[2]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A lot of work has already been done on the area of localization of mobile nodes, but there still exist numerous open issues. The constant progress in technology gives the opportunity to obtain efficient, in terms of cost and accuracy, localization services, and likewise it increases the number of challenges to be considered. The main problems related to the localization of mobile devices concern with the heterogeneity of visited environments and interested hardware platforms, the energy and computational constraints imposed by the devices and the choice of appropriate tracking technologies. The most important goal in the localization research area is to provide a very accurate positioning service, regardless the surrounding environment. For my PhD research I propose an innovative system for ubiquitous localization which does not rely on backend servers (each node performs a self-localization) and whose reference platform is a new generation mobile phone. This system exploits the sensors embedded on such devices to perform positioning and it is further assisted by opportunistic exchange of information among neighboring nodes. By means of this system, a node is able to classify its movements by continuously refining a self-movement-model (machine learning techniques), thus assisting the localization procedure itself. The purpose of this document is to briefly describe the state of the art in localization, and to outline my planned PhD research.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534969]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534969]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534969]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534969&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534969]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>3</rank>

<title><![CDATA[[Copyright notice]]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[1]]></epage>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534924]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534924]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534924]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534924&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534924]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>4</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Artificial ants for efficient data forwarding in wireless mesh networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bokhari, F.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Comput. Sci. & Eng., Univ. of Texas at Arlington, Arlington, TX, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Ant colony optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless mesh networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[2]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We present our initial work on the design and implementation of an efficient routing architecture for wireless mesh networks (WMNs). We have proposed two routing schemes namely AMIRA and AntMesh, which provide efficient data forwarding for improved load-balancing and reduced interference in single and multi-radio infrastructure mesh networks. Both of our proposed schemes are derived from the principle of Ant Colony Optimization (ACO) in which artificial ants (agents) perform the routing and data forwarding to stochastically solve a dynamic network optimization problem. The main focus in our work is to take advantage of the particular characteristics of ACO framework and exploit them in designing routing schemes for WMNs keeping in view the unique characteristics and requirements of these infrastructure mesh networks.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534974]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534974]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534974]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534974&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534974]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>5</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Comparing network protocols via elimination of MAC/PHY effects]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Rehunathan, Devan]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[University of St Andrews, School of Computer Science]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Local area networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Media Access Protocol]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile computing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Virtual machining]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[2]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Outside simulation, the study of mobile network protocols is not trivial and the standard approach usually involves building a testbed and populating it with the relevant entities. While this approach, provides real-life results, it is time consuming and resource intensive. We propose an alternative approach that can be used to compare mobile network protocols with a minimum amount of resources. Our solution explores the possibility of discounting physical layer effects entirely, when doing a comparative analysis of two mobile network protocols. In this paper, we document and discuss our efforts to check if this method is feasible.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534968]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534968]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534968]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534968&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534968]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>6</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Fountain codes for exploiting diversity in wireless sensor networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Apavatjrut, A.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[CITI-Lab., INSA de Lyon Domaine Sci. de la Doua, Villeurbanne, France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Broadcasting]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Encoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Maximum likelihood decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Robustness]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[2]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This extended thesis abstract provides an overview of my research on exploiting diversity in Wireless Sensor Networks using Fountain codes.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534970]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534970]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534970]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534970&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534970]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>7</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A method to compare new and traditional accelerometry data in physical activity monitoring]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[van Hees, V.T.;  Pias, M.;  Taherian, S.;  Ekelund, U.;  Brage, S.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Inst. of Metabolic Sci., Med. Res. Council (MRC), Cambridge, UK]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Acceleration]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Accelerometers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Band pass filters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Data processing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensors]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The accelerometer devices as traditionally used in the epidemiological field for physical activity monitoring (e.g. Actigraph, Actical, and RT3) provide manufacturer-dependent output values called counts that are computed by obscure and proprietary signal processing techniques. This lack of transparency poses a challenge for comparison of historical accelerometer data in counts with data collected using raw accelerometry in S.I. units &#x2014; m/s<sup>2</sup>. The purpose of this study was to develop a method that facilitates the compatibility between both methods through conversion of raw accelerometer output data collected with inertial acceleration sensors into Actigraph counts &#x2014; the most widely used (de facto standard) device brand in epidemiological studies. The basics of the conversion algorithm were captured from the technical specifications of the Actigraph GT1M. Fine-tuning of the algorithm was achieved empirically under controlled conditions using a mechanical shaker device. A pilot evaluation was carried out through physical activity monitoring in free-living scenarios of 19 adult participants (age: 47 &#x00B1; 11 yrs, BMI: 25.2 &#x00B1; 4.1 kg-m<sup>&#x2212;2</sup>) wearing both devices. The results show that Actigraph counts estimated by the proposed method explain 94.2% of the variation in Actigraph counts (p &#x003C; 0.001). The concordance correlation coefficient was 0.93 (p &#x003C; 0.05). The sensitivity for classifying intensity ranged from 93.4% for light physical activity to 70.7% for moderate physical activity.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534986]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534986]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534986]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534986&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534986]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>8</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Fair scheduling for real-time multimedia support in IEEE 802.16 wireless access networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Fallah, Y.P.;  Nasiopoulos, P.;  Sengupta, Raja]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Depts EECS & CEE, Univ. of California at Berkeley, Berkeley, CA, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.16 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quality of service]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Scheduling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Scheduling algorithm]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Successful deployment of Broadband Wireless Access Networks such as WiMAX (IEEE 802.16) will be contingent on provisions for supporting multimedia traffic. In this paper, we review the quality of service features of access networks such as the 802.16 standard, and identify algorithms and schemes that are needed for supporting multimedia traffic in such networks. The 802.16 standard only specifies the features that should be implemented and leaves the design of a quality of service solution to developers. This includes the design of a mandatory scheduling framework. We present a comprehensive multimedia support framework based on the standard features. The framework specifies the architectures for the base station and the subscriber station, and contributes a number of algorithms for different service provisioning objectives. We use the concept of virtual packets to provide fair packet based centralized scheduling of uplink and downlink packets. The presented solution also provides algorithms for temporal and throughput fair scheduling in multirate physical layer of the 802.16 networks. An important part of the presented design is a multi-class fair scheduling scheme which is proposed for providing better delay performance for real time applications, while maintaining slightly longer term fairness.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534907]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534907]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534907]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534907&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534907]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>9</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Information utility in mission-oriented networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Eswaran, S.;  Shur, D.;  Samtani, S.;  Staikos, A.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Comput. Sci. & Eng., Pennsylvania State Univ., University Park, PA, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Accuracy]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Feeds]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Joints]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Streaming media]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In recent years, utility-oriented resource allocation for wired and wireless networks has been extensively studied. A key goal of utility based analysis is to provide evaluation criteria for efficient network operation based on subjective user assessments such as usefulness and value of data. Yet the vast majority of the prior work has focused on topics like mathematical functions (concave or otherwise) of network metrics such as bandwidth, delay, packet loss, etc., or information entropy, or user-perceived quality (e.g., MOS) for interpreting utility. In this work<sup>1</sup>, we propose an alternative mission-oriented definition and metric for utility that is based on the accuracy and speed at which tasks are completed, which we believe is closer to the intent of utility-based analysis. Like previous work, our definition supports the design and engineering of networks by mapping utility metrics to the typical network design metrics (bandwidth, delay, loss, etc). Unlike previous work, it also permits simple solutions to important questions such as the joint utility or usefulness of different data streams, the impact on the utility of one data stream by another, and cross-sensory utility (e.g., the impact of a side audio channel on an image processing task, or a side video channel on an audio processing task). We present a novel experimental approach to the design of such experiments, and provide measurement results. The results quantify the effects of information encoding and the impairments incurred during transmission through imperfect networks on the information's usefulness to end-users in terms of being able to complete tasks correctly and on time.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534925]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534925]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534925]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534925&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534925]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>10</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Wyner-Ziv video coding with error-prone wireless fading channels]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Thambu, K.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Ryerson Univ., Toronto, ON, Canada]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Codecs]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Noise]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Video coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[2]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This research work explains the new video coding technique known as Wyner-Ziv video coding and its transmission over fading wireless channels. We have modeled the Wyner-Ziv codec with wireless channel. Impairments of the wireless channel (both noise and fading) are considered in the improvement of the Wyner-Ziv decoder. The cross-layer structure is introduced in the Wyner-Ziv video coding technique. We have analyzed the channel noise and the correlation noise of video frames at the decoder side. Estimation of the correlation noise between the Wyner-Ziv frame and the side information is studied thoroughly and proposed the new estimation technique which is known as the bit based correlation noise estimation. Furthermore, the performance of a multiple input multiple output (MIMO) diversity scheme is investigated to overcome the channel fading effect in the reconstructed Wyner-Ziv video frame sequence.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534976]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534976]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534976]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534976&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534976]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>11</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Rope ladder routing: Position-based multipath routing for wireless mesh networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Lessmann, Johannes;  Schoeller, Marcus;  Zdarsky, Frank]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[NEC Laboratories Europe, Heidelberg, Germany, Albert Banchs, Universidad Carlos III de Madrid, Madrid, Spain]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Maintenance engineering]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mesh networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Switches]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we present a novel multipath structure called rope-ladder which combines the advantages of path, node and link protection schemes. We also propose a position-based multipath routing protocol in order to efficiently construct rope-ladders in wireless networks. By design, the paths which are constructed by our protocol are closely together which allows to quickly switch back and forth between them in cases of node or link failures. Hence, the size of loss gaps (i.e. the number of consecutively lost packets) can be minimized. Previous works mostly confine themselves to overall packet loss comparisons. However, the loss gap size is crucial to ensure high quality for gap-sensitive traffic like voice flows. Our multipath structure can also tolerate failures of multiple consecutive nodes on the primary path, and has a superior path diversity and path lifetime compared to even perfect braids. We evaluate the performance of our protocol using analysis and simulations<sup>1</sup>.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534994]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534994]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534994]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534994&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534994]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>12</rank>

<title><![CDATA[The XO-Mesh path discovery mechanism sanity]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Carrano, R.C.;  Schara Magalhaes, L.C.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[RCT/Puro, Univ. Fed. Fluminense, Rio das Ostras, Brazil]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Indexes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Meteorology]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Proposals]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The XO-Mesh is a layer two ad hoc multlhop wireless network, developed by OLPC for its hundred-dollar educational laptop. Although based on an early version of the IEEE 802.11s draft, both proposals diverged in many aspects as they evolved in the last three years. This article focuses on the Path Discovery Mechanism introduced by OLPC, which differs from the mechanism described in the IEEE 802.11s &#x2014; the Hybrid Wireless Mesh Protocol (HWMP) &#x2014; in many aspects. We are particularly interested in explaining odd behaviors observed in the field (OLPC deployments) and test beds &#x2014; namely the forming of unexpected multihop paths. We confirm that such oddities do occur and propose methods to reduce its effects.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534999]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534999]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534999]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534999&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534999]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>13</rank>

<title><![CDATA[An application layer non-repudiation wireless system: A cross-layer approach]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Adibi, S.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[ECE Dept, Univ. of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON, Canada]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Communication system security]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Elliptic curve cryptography]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quality of service]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[2]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Non-repudiation techniques are to ensure any communication taking place between two or more parties will be undeniable. Therefore it is crucial to include digital signatures of the involving parties while the communication is taking place. In medical practices, involved parties may include patient(s) and doctor(s) who are involved in series of visits, diagnosis, prescription, possible operation, and etc. To avoid possible conflicts, adding non-repudiation techniques help immensely. This thesis considers this issue in a wireless medium and studies the Quality of Service (QoS)/Security requirements in terms of network parameters and performance metrics [1].]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534971]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534971]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534971]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534971&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534971]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>14</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Estimation and prediction for tracking trajectories in cellular networks using the recursive prediction error method]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Milocco, R.H.;  Boumerdassi, S.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[GCAyS, UNCOMA, Neuquen, Argentina]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Acceleration]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile computing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Noise]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Prediction algorithms]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[After considering the intrinsically erratic behavior of nodes in mobile networks, mobility prediction has been extensively used to improve the quality of services. Many methods have been proposed, inherited from technologies developed for signal processing and self-learning techniques and/or stochastic methods. Among the latter the Extended Kalman Filter (EKF), using the received power as a measurement, is the most used. However, because the measure is not linear with distance, the EKF loses stability under certain circumstances and must be reset. Moreover, it requires the a priori knowledge of disturbances and measurement noise covariance matrices which are difficult to obtain. In this work, from the non-linear model, we derive a stable time-variant first order auto-regressive and moving average model (ARMA), and propose a prediction mechanism based on the well-known Recursive Prediction Error Method (RPEM) to predict the mobile location and then compare it with (EKF). Simulation results show that RPEM has a lower prediction error variance in most cases and similar in others to that obtained with EKF with the additional advantages that it has guaranteed stability and does not require the a priori knowledge of disturbances and measurement noise covariance matrices as in EKF.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534918]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534918]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534918]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534918&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534918]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>15</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Achieving per-station fairness in IEEE 802.11 wireless LANs]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Wan-Seon Lim;  Young-Joo Suh]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Comput. Sci. & Eng., Pohang Univ. of Sci. & Technol. (POSTECH), Pohang, South Korea]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Media Access Protocol]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Neodymium]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless LAN]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we address the issue of per-station fairness in IEEE 802.11-based wireless local area networks (WLANs). Although the IEEE 802.11 Distributed Coordination Function (DCF) has been designed to provide a fair channel access for all competing stations, it does not guarantee fairness between uplink and downlink flows in infrastructure mode WLANs. In the literature, several solutions have been proposed, where they give a higher channel access priority to an access point (AP) in order to avoid the starvation of downlink flows. However, we found that existing solutions cannot guarantee per-station fairness when uplink and downlink flows coexist in a station. In this paper, we propose a new MAC protocol for IEEE 802.11 WLANs, which aims at providing a fair medium access for all stations regardless of the direction of flows. In the proposed protocol, stations are classified into four states according to their traffic patterns, and they access the medium in different ways according to their states. The proposed protocol is fully backward compatible with the IEEE 802.11 standard and it does not include any complex scheduling algorithm. We evaluated the performance of the proposed protocol via extensive simulations and experiments in a real test-bed. Compared to existing work, the proposed protocol shows improved fairness performance in resource sharing among WLAN stations.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534908]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534908]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534908]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534908&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534908]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>16</rank>

<title><![CDATA[StreamSocial: A P2P streaming system with social incentives]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Abboud, O.;  Zinner, T.;  Lidanski, E.;  Pussep, K.;  Steinmetz, R.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Multimedia Commun. Lab., Tech. Univ. Darmstadt, Darmstadt, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Collaboration]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Graphical user interfaces]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Media]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Social network services]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Streaming media]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[TV]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Videos]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[2]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[P2P Streaming has attracted much attention recently with promises for more revenues and better load distribution. In parallel, social networking has changed how people interact using the web. One interesting use-case for next generation IPTV is Social TV. In such a system, users are able to watch some media stream and interact with each other at the same time. While deploying P2P Social TV, one inherent problem in P2P streaming systems remains, how to incite users to contribute. In this demonstration we show how social networks can be used to build new incentive mechanisms. Rather than making social relations a mere addition, we build our streaming system on top of a user's social network. This design greatly simplifies the system and requires no further entities for management. In this demonstration we present the first version of StreamSocial that, based on a plug-in based design, allows users to stream videos while performing social interactions.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534932]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534932]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534932]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534932&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534932]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>17</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Design and evaluation of a fast authentication scheme for WiFi-based wireless networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Zhenxia Zhang;  Pazzi, R.W.;  Boukerche, A.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[PARADISE Res. Lab., Univ. of Ottawa, Ottawa, ON, Canada]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Authentication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cryptography]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile computing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Servers]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[WiFi-based wireless networks are important components in next generation mobile heterogeneous networks, as WiFi devices are widely used in laptops, PDAs and other mobile computing machines. During the movement, mobile clients have to switch their associated access points because the wireless transmission range is limited in a WiFi network. The process of switching access points is called handoff. Handoff management is a key service in mobile networks, because providing seamless roaming in wireless networks is mandatory for supporting realtime applications in a mobile environment, such as VoIP, online games, and eConference. Many solutions have been introduced to reduce MAC layer handoff latency; however, these solutions do not consider secure authentications, which would not be suitable for real scenarios. During the handoff procedure, mobile clients should pass the authentication to prevent security attacks. In this paper, we propose a fast authentication scheme for WiFi networks to reduce authentication latency during the handoff. In the meanwhile, the packet loss ratio is also minimized to support seamless roaming.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534962]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534962]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534962]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534962&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534962]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>18</rank>

<title><![CDATA[POSTECH's U-Health Smart Home for elderly monitoring and support]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Jin Kim;  Hyeok-soo Choi;  Hui Wang;  Agoulmine, N.;  Deerv, M.J.;  Hong, J.W.-K.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Grad. Sch. of Inf. Technol., POSTECH, Pohang, South Korea]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Cognition]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Computer integrated manufacturing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OWL]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Ontologies]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Semantics]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Senior citizens]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Smart homes]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[With the increase of the aging society worldwide, hospitals, medical practitioners and health insurers are now increasingly seeking ways to reduce the cost of healthcare while maitaining its quality. One solution subject to attention from gouvernement and healthcare providers is the U-Health Smart Home that aims to provide non-intrusive and non-invasive monitoring and assistance to the elderly directly in their own home. At POSTECH, the U-Health Smart Home project is focused on building a smart home along with an autonomic system to monitor the home as well as the inhabitants to provide intelligent support and assistance in any situation at anytime. This paper presents our initial results from this project. The first contribution is a general framework for the U-Health smart home and the second one is an initial semantic model that can be used in the autonomic system to provide autonomic support to the elderly.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534977]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534977]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534977]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534977&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534977]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>19</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Misbehaving router detection in link-state routing for wireless mesh networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[A&#x0301; cs, G.;  Buttyan, L.;  Do&#x0302; ra, L.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Lab. of Cryptography & Syst. Security (CrySyS), Budapest Univ. of Technol. & Econ., Budapest, Hungary]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Logic gates]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mesh networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radiation detectors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we address the problem of detecting misbehaving routers in wireless mesh networks and avoiding them when selecting routes. We assume that link-state routing is used, and we essentially propose a reputation system, where trusted gateway nodes compute Node Trust Values for the routers, which are fed back into the system and used in the route selection procedure. The computation of the Node Trust Values is based on packet counters maintained in association with each route and reported to the gateways by the routers in a regular manner. The feedback mechanism is based on limited scope flooding. The received Node Trust Values concerning a given router are aggregated, and the aggregate trust value of the router determines the probability with which that router is kept in the topology graph used for route computation. Hence, less trusted routers are excluded from the topology graph with higher probability, while the route selection still runs on a weighted graph (where the weights are determined by the announced link qualities), and it does not need to be changed. We evaluated the performance of our solution by means of simulations. The results show that our proposed mechanism can detect misbehaving routers reliably, and thanks to the feedback and the exclusion of the accused nodes from the route selection, we can decrease the number of packets dropped due to router misbehavior considerably. At the same time, our mechanism only slightly increases the average route length.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534995]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534995]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534995]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534995&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534995]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>20</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Evaluation of quality of experience for video streaming over dynamic spectrum access systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ververidis, C.N.;  Riihijarvi, J.;  Mahonen, P.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Inst. for Networked Syst., RWTH Aachen Univ., Aachen, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Availability]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multimedia communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[PSNR]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Streaming media]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we study the problem of quantifying the value of spectrum opportunities to secondary users in Dynamic Spectrum Access (DSA) systems. We especially focus on estimating the impact of key channel parameters, namely the activity patterns of the primary users on the expected quality of experience for secondary users accessing video streams over a DSA system. In our study we consider three basic types of video representing typical video content categorized according to scene change rate ranging from low-activity newscast to high-activity sports video. Through extensive simulations we show that given some information on the expected level of activity in the video, the duty cycle of the primary user alone can yield good predictors for the expected quality of experience of secondary users. Knowledge of the precise distributions of the primary user ON and OFF periods can be used to further enhance the precision of the prediction, but at least for exponential and log-normal channel access patterns the differences are rather small. Finally, we study the problem of determining the channel statistics that are needed to apply the predictor in an optimization setting. Our simulations show that high accuracy can be achieved in matter of minutes of estimation time, which is more than enough for practical deployments in typical urban environments.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534892]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534892]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534892]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534892&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534892]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>21</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Implementation of the OBAMP overlay protocol for multicast delivery in OLSR wireless community networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Proto, F.S.;  Pisa, C.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Univ. of Rome Tor Vergata, Rome, Italy]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Communities]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IP networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mesh networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[3]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The Optimized Link State Routing (OLSR) protocol is widely employed in Wireless Community Networks (WCNs), where users are connected to a wireless backbone with high bandwidth links. In these networks users can access both the Internet and internal network services. However the routers lack multicast support and users cannot exploit the high capacity of wireless links to stream and receive multimedia services. We implemented an extension to the OLSR protocol to support the delivery of multicast traffic using the Overlay Borovka-based Ad-hoc Multicast Protocol (OBAMP). We present a demo of our implementation that is devised for the GNU/Linux operating system. The implementation has been tested both on standard PCs and on embedded devices running OpenWRT and it is distributed as a plugin within the olsr.org OLSR implementation. This protocol enhancement makes possible to create a multicast distribution tree among a subset of nodes, providing the mesh users with multicast community services.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534941]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534941]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534941]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534941&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534941]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>22</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On access point association in wireless mesh networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Argento, A.;  Cesana, M.;  Malanchini, I.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dipt. di Elettron. e Inf., Politec. di Milano, Milan, Italy]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Ad hoc networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Games]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Logic gates]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless mesh networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[End users getting connectivity from wireless access networks want to choose the &#x0022;best&#x0022; access opportunity, that is, the best base station in cellular systems, and the best access point in WLANs. The metrics used to drive the association procedures are usually based on &#x0022;local&#x0022; parameters like the received signal strength, and the base station/access point's load. In case connectivity is provided through a Wireless Mesh Network the quality perceived by the user upon association depends also on &#x0022;global&#x0022; network-wide parameters. This paper studies the dynamics of network association in Wireless Mesh Networks by resorting to game theoretic tools. We show how the association problem can be formalized as a non-cooperative game in which end users selfishly play to minimize a perceived association cost which accounts for characteristics of the entire path to reach the WMN gateway. The quality of the Nash Equilibria for the proposed game are then quantitatively analyzed, and preliminary numerical results on the perceived association cost are derived for sample network topologies.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5535000]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5535000]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5535000]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5535000&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5535000]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>23</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Crowd-sourced sensing and collaboration using twitter]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Demirbas, M.;  Bayir, M.A.;  Akcora, C.G.;  Yilmaz, Y.S.;  Ferhatosmanoglu, H.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Comput. Sci. & Eng. Dept., SUNY - Univ. at Buffalo, New York, NY, USA]]></affiliations>

<controlledterms>

<term><![CDATA[groupware]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[social networking (online)]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[ubiquitous computing]]></term>

</controlledterms>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Cities and towns]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Collaboration]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Meteorology]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Smart phones]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Twitter]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Despite the availability of the sensor and smart-phone devices to fulfill the ubiquitous computing vision, the-state-of-the-art falls short of this vision. We argue that the reason for this gap is the lack of an infrastructure to task/utilize these devices for collaboration. We propose that microblogging services like Twitter can provide an &#x201C;open&#x201D; publish-subscribe infrastructure for sensors and smartphones, and pave the way for ubiquitous crowd-sourced sensing and collaboration applications. We design and implement a crowd-sourced sensing and collaboration system over Twitter, and showcase our system in the context of two applications: a crowd-sourced weather radar, and a participatory noise-mapping application. Our results from real-world Twitter experiments give insights into the feasibility of this approach and outline the research challenges in sensor/smartphone integration to Twitter.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534910]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534910]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534910]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534910&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534910]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>24</rank>

<title><![CDATA[TTN: A time-to-network approach to data reporting in mobile ad hoc networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Sitbon, P.;  Wu-chi Feng;  Bulusu, N.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Ad hoc networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Availability]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Data models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile computing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vehicles]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[For many applications in mobile wireless ad hoc networks (MANETs), forming an end-to-end data path is not always necessary; instead, the primary routing goal is often data collection or dissemination where only a data source is known. Routing algorithms must be carefully chosen in order to suit the needs of applications employing them. Our focus is on data collection applications in MANETs where limited mobility information is required to route data in a scalable manner. To address this goal, we employ the concepts of delay-tolerant networking (DTN) in which data makes progress toward a destination with high latency expectations and little knowledge of routing topology. Specifically, we present time-to-network (TTN) forwarding, a method of forwarding data generated by mobile nodes to a network endpoint in such a way that delivery latency is lowered without high networking cost. By segmenting mobility patterns into trips, we are able to apply TTN to a vehicular network using only an estimated destination arrival time for each vehicle. We evaluate TTN using mobility data from the TRANSIMS simulator for a real road network. Results show that our algorithm produces collection-to-network latencies similar to more generic algorithms but at a lower cost and with higher efficiency. Furthermore, we establish a lower bound for delivery latency in our experiments and compare it to TTN. This also helps normalize the interpretation of results specific to our mobility model.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534990]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534990]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534990]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534990&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534990]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>25</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Channel assortment strategy for reliable communication in multi-hop cognitive radio networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Rehmani, M.H.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Lip6, Univ. Pierre et Marie Curie, Paris, France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Availability]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Broadcasting]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Chromium]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cognitive radio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Spread spectrum communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[2]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Channel selection plays a vital role in efficient and reliable data dissemination. In the context of Cognitive Radio Network (CRN) [1], channel selection is more challenging due to the traffic pattern and channels' occupancy of primary radio (PR) nodes. Moreover, Cognitive Radio (CR) transmissions should not degrade the reception quality of PR nodes and should be immediately interrupted whenever a neighboring PR activity is detected [2]. Thus, it is essential and, however, extremely challenging for CR nodes to correctly select channels allowing reliable communication.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534972]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534972]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534972]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534972&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534972]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>26</rank>

<title><![CDATA[LER-MAC: A Load-independent Energy-efficient and Rate-control Integrated Asynchronous Duty Cycle MAC for Wireless Sensor Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Monowar, M.M.;  Alam, Muhammad Mahbub;  Rahman, M.O.;  Choong Seon Hong]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Comput. Eng., Kyung Hee Univ., Yongin, South Korea]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bidirectional control]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Media Access Protocol]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sleep]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Considering energy as a crucial resource, several duty cycle based MAC have already been proposed for Wireless Sensor Networks (WSNs) to gain higher energy efficiency during long idle period of the sensors, and are optimized for light traffic loads. Contrastively, considering the bandwidth constraint of WSNs, and to optimize the heavy traffic loads, another research trend is continuing in devising rate and congestion control at the MAC layer. To provide an integrated solution of both these distinct research trends at the MAC layer, in this paper, we present a Load-independent Energy-efficient and Rate-control Integrated Asynchronous Duty Cycle MAC (LER-MAC) for WSNs. Performance of LER-MAC has been evaluated using ns-2 which demonstrates that, LER-MAC conserves energy considerably during light traffic loads along with procures higher throughput and lower latency avoiding packet drops through maximum utilization of the channel during heavy traffic loads.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534901]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534901]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534901]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534901&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534901]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>27</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Optimal link scheduling for real-time traffic in wireless mesh networks in both per-flow and per-path frameworks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Cappanera, P.;  Lenzini, L.;  Lori, A.;  Steay, G.;  Vaglini, G.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dipt. di Sist. e Inf., Univ. of Florence, Firenze, Italy]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Processor scheduling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Robustness]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Schedules]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time division multiple access]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we investigate link scheduling for Wireless Mesh Networks (WMNs) carrying real-time (i.e., delay-constrained) traffic. We show that the problem of computing a conflict-free link schedule with end-to-end delay constraints can be formulated as a mixed-integer non linear problem that can be optimally solved in reasonable time (i.e., minutes) for relatively large WMNs (up to 20&#x2013;30 nodes). We use the above result to explore the schedulability region of a WMN with a given routing and input traffic, assessing whether and when aggregating flows which traverse the same path makes a given input flow set sched-ulable. Furthermore, we devise a heuristic solution strategy, which computes good suboptimal solutions within up to few seconds, thus being amenable for online admission control.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534919]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534919]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534919]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534919&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534919]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>28</rank>

<title><![CDATA[An analysis of distributed and asynchronous wireless group communication mechanisms]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Chandra, S.;  Xuwen Yu]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Availability]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Collaboration]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Portable computers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Springs]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Asynchronous group communication systems propagate updates from each group member to every other member. Contemporary users are wireless and operate from a variety of locations. Hence, we investigate the propagation performance for these users. An analysis of wireless users in academia, corporation and in a city-wide hotspot federation shows that the availability durations and the duration between sessions depends on the locale. A longer term analysis shows that the user session lengths are becoming smaller while the duration between sessions are becoming larger with significant user churn. We show that the propagation performance depends on the locale. New users incur a heavy cost in receiving updates from prior users; applications need to develop expiration mechanisms to reduce this overhead. Also, since users regularly leave the system, practical communication mechanisms need to choose their propagation periodicity in order to respond to scenarios when the user abruptly leaves the system without propagating their updates to other users.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534935]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534935]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534935]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534935&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534935]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>29</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Performance analysis of the IEEE 802.11 MAC protocol for DSRC with and without Retransmissions]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Hassan, M.I.;  Vu, H.L.;  Sakurai, T.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Centre for Adv. Internet Archit., Swinburne Univ. of Technol., Hawthorn, VIC, Australia]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Analytical models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Media Access Protocol]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Probability]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Safety]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vehicles]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We develop an accurate analytical model for a dedicated short range communication (DSRC) network that uses the IEEE 802.11 distributed coordination function (DCF) MAC protocol, as adopted by the forthcoming IEEE 802.11p specification for DSRC. The specific focus is on broadcast vehicle-to-vehicle safety messages. We derive explicit expressions for the mean of the total packet delay and the packet delivery ratio (PDR) in an unsaturated network formed by moving vehicles on a highway. Our model is validated using extensive simulations and we show that our model yields better predictive accuracy than other existing models. The model is then used to investigate the performance of a modified DCF that uses a fixed number of sequential retransmissions to improve the reliability of packet delivery. We find that with sequential retransmissions, the PDR improves at low vehicle density (i.e. low traffic load), but degrades at heavy loads where higher collisions induced by the retransmissions outweighs the benefit of repeated attempts.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534909]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534909]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534909]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534909&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534909]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>30</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Autonomic diagnosis of anomalous network traffic]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Marnerides, A.K.;  Hutchison, David;  Pezaros, D.P.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Comput. Dept., Lancaster Univ., Lancaster, UK]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Classification algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Computer architecture]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Engines]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Entropy]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Prediction algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resilience]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Network traffic abnormalities pose one of the greatest threats for networked environments. Autonomic communications offer a solution: it should be possible to design network mechanisms that behave adaptively and respond to any anomalous phenomenon that threatens normal network behaviour. In this paper we present the design of an adaptive anomaly detection component that has been built as part of an autonomic network system. We have implemented an entropy estimator to predict the onset of anomalous traffic behaviour within an autonomic resilience framework, and a Supervised Naive Bayesian classifier which synergistically empower the core properties of self-adaptation, self-learning and self-protection for next generation networks. Being part of an always-on, automated measurement and control infrastructure, such mechanism enforces the adaptive system reaction to suboptimal network operation and its subsequent restoration, while requiring minimal static (re)configuration and operator intervention.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534933]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534933]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534933]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534933&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534933]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>31</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Enable multimedia mobility with IEEE 802.21]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Guang Lu]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[InterDigital Communications]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multiaccess communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Servers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Spread spectrum communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Streaming media]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Mobile devices supporting multiple radio technologies are becoming mainstream in the market. These devices can experience vertical handovers between heterogeneous networks due to device mobility or multiple network coverage. Handover latency is critical to ensure session continuity and end user experience. This paper presents a solution using IEEE 802.21 to enable seamless mobility for data and video streaming sessions. The solution was implemented and evaluated using commercial wireless networks and mobile devices. Lab and field trial results show minimal handover delay and improved user experience.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534987]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534987]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534987]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534987&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534987]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>32</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A multiaccess network of information]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Pentikousis, K.;  Rautio, T.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Huawei Technol., Berlin, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Ethernet networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Internet]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile radio mobility management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Peer to peer computing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Streaming media]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[WiMAX]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The Network of Information (Netlnf), an information-centric approach to designing the Internet of the Future, aims at introducing the foundation concepts that allow users to create, distribute, and retrieve information using a common set of network infrastructure primitives without tying data to particular hosts. Netlnf is well suited for mobile communications and wireless content dissemination. One of the key aspects of Netlnf operation is its native capacity to take advantage of overlapping multiaccess environments and distributed in-network storage. This paper introduces Netlnf multiaccess operation taking cues from state-of-the-art peer-to-peer content distribution. In order to evaluate multiaccess operation in practice we consider the requirements and deployment environment for Netlnf, including a migration approach to adopting Netlnf concepts. We conduct measurements, specify the necessary signaling to enhance Bit Torrent operation over multiaccess, multi-domain networks and develop a prototype to explore the design space. The paper also introduces the Netlnf Notification Service. We present empirical results showing how multiaccess Netlnf can outperform current technologies.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534922]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534922]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534922]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534922&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534922]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>33</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On the side effects of packet detection sensitivity in IEEE 802.11 interference management]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Scalia, L.;  Widmer, J.;  Aad, I.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[DOCOMO Euro-Labs., Munich, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensitivity]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal detection]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless LAN]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Interference management is one of the most critical operations for CSMA/CA protocols. In this paper we investigate how specific PHY-layer operations, designed to mitigate the effect of interference, can cause the radio-receiver circuitry to over-estimate the channel occupation status, thus unnecessarily limiting the overall spatial reuse or impeding the synchronization to incoming frames. We individuated the root of this problem in the surprising effectiveness of the overall packet detection procedure of WLAN PHY, which allows for the demodulation of strongly attenuated 802.11 frames. The transmit spectrum mask for the IEEE 802.11 standard allows limited power leakage over adjacent channels. Such a low power signal from adjacent channels nowadays can be correctly recognized by recent OFDM/CCK receive circuitry, which has an important impact on WLAN performance. A receiver may miss the reception of packets destined to it, whenever a frame capture of a transmission on a partially overlapping channel occurs. A similar effect occurs in the transmit phase. In carrier sense mode, the OFDM/CCK receiver of the WLAN device is capable of synchronizing to the preamble of low SNR signals, thus unnecessarily deferring the channel access in case of transmissions on partially overlapping channels.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534963]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534963]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534963]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534963&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534963]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>34</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Path diversity gain with network coding and multipath transmission in wireless mesh networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Pappas, N.;  Siris, V.A.;  Traganitis, A.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Inst. of Comput. Sci., Found. for Res. & Technol. - Hellas (FORTH), Heraklion, Greece]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Digital signal processing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Error probability]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Redundancy]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we investigate the performance that can be achieved by exploiting path diversity through multipath forwarding together with redundancy through linear network coding, in wireless mesh networks with directional links. A key contribution of the paper is to capture the tradeoff between packet delay and throughput achieved by combining multipath forwarding and network coding, and compare this tradeoff with that of simple multipath routing where different flows follow different paths, the transmission of multiple copies of packets over multiple paths, and single path routing. The analytical framework considers the case of end-to-end retransmission for achieving reliability, and is generalized for an arbitrary number of paths and hops. We also derive the minimum and maximum number of coded packets that are needed at the receiver to retrieve all packets sent by the sender; this can be used to obtain a lower and upper bound for the delay in the case of linear network coding with multipath forwarding.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534996]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534996]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534996]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534996&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534996]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>35</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Detection of the Evil ring attack in wireless sensor networks using cross verification]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Wei Shi;  Barbeau, M.;  Corriveau, J.-P.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Fac. of Bus. & Inf. Technol., Univ. of Ontario Inst. Technol., Oshawa, ON, Canada]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Detection algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Equations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Global Positioning System]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Knowledge engineering]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In ad hoc networks and wireless sensor networks, several routing algorithms rely on the knowledge by the network nodes of their own geographic location and those of others. For cases where a node doesn't have its own positioning device (e.g., GPS), Alfaro et al. propose several algorithms that a node can run to determine its geographic position using position reports from neighbors. In this paper, we first present the evil ring attack, an attack on the geographic location algorithms of Alfaro et al. that misleads nodes about the true position of their neighbors. An attacker sends false reports with a position that sits on a circle centered at the victim's location and of a radius equal to the distance between the victim and attacker. The attack succeeds because the calculation of the distance between the victim and attacker is not affected despite this fake position. We then present and analyze an evil ring attack detection algorithm in which a position-unaware sensor node crosschecks the consistency of the information it collects from its neighbors with the information collected by other trusted neighbors. This algorithm detects the existence of neighbors running the evil ring attack. We propose a general distributed algorithm for a) localizing sensors in a wireless sensor network in the presence of some malfunctioning ones, and b) detecting such malfunctioning sensors.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534952]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534952]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534952]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534952&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534952]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>36</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Algorithm for data similarity measurements to reduce data redundancy in wireless sensor networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ghaddar, A.;  Razafindralambo, T.;  Simplot-Ryl, I.;  Tawbi, S.;  Hijazi, A.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[INRIA, Univ. Lille 1, Lille, France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Accuracy]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Data models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Kernel]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Redundancy]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Extending the lifetime of wireless sensor networks remains the most challenging and demanding requirement that impedes large-scale deployments. The basic operation in WSNs is the systematic gathering and transmission of sensed data to a base station for further processing. During data gathering, the amount of data can be large sometimes, due to redundant data combined from different sensing nodes in the neighborhood. Thus the data gathered need to be processed before being transmitted, in order to detect and remove redundancy, which can impact the communication traffic and energy consumption of the network in a negative way. In this paper, we propose an algorithm to measure similarity between the data collected toward the base station(relative to a specific event monitoring), so that an aggregator sensor sends a minimum amount of information to the base station in a way that the latter can deduce the source information of sensing neighbors nodes. Further, our experimental results demonstrate that the communication traffic and the number of bits transmitted can be minimized while preserving accuracy on the base station estimations.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534888]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534888]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534888]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534888&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534888]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>37</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks based localization for audio-source: A GCC-GA method]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bo Cheng;  Cailian Chen;  Zhezhuang Xu;  Haoran Li;  Xinping Guan]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Sch. of Electron., Inf. & Electr. Eng., Shanghai Jiao Tong Univ., Shanghai, China]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Accuracy]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Acoustics]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Complexity theory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Convergence]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Position measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[It is a very important and challenging task to localize an audio-source in wireless sensor networks (WSNs). One of efficient methods for audio-source localization is the so-called time difference of arrival (TDOA) based approach. In this paper, we propose a novel localization method based on Generalized Cross Correlation-Genetic Algorithm (GCC-GA). It utilizes GCC method to calculate the TDOA and GA to improve the localization accuracy. The proposed method is implemented in a real grid wireless sensor network. The experimental results show that the network can estimate the source location with better accuracy and lower complexity.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534950]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534950]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534950]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534950&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534950]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>38</rank>

<title><![CDATA[PCAR: A power controlled routing protocol for wireless ad hoc networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Xue Zhang;  Ming Liu;  Haigang Gong;  Sanglu Lu;  Jie Wu]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Sch. of Comput. Sci. & Eng., Univ. of Electron. Sci. & Technol. of China, Chengdu, China]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile ad hoc networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Power control]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Proposals]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Topology]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Power control and routing are two fundamental supporting techniques for wireless communications in ad hoc networks. However, most existing power control and routing proposals are not really efficient enough, due to separate considerations on them. In this paper, motivated by the observation on the necessity and feasibility of the combination of power control and routing, we propose a power controlled routing protocol PCAR (Power Controlled Ad hoc Routing). The basic idea is to develop power control on top of the distance-vector routing mechanism that is based on the classical distributed Bellman-Ford algorithm. Each node adjusts the transmission power automatically through the PIPC (Proportion-Integral Power Control) algorithm that we previously proposed. Both theoretical analysis and simulation results show that PCAR has a good performance.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534916]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534916]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534916]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534916&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534916]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>39</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A secure peer-to-peer web framework]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Koskela, J.;  Gurtov, A.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Helsinki Inst. for Inf. Technol., Aalto, Finland]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Hip]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Internet]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Peer to peer computing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Proposals]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Security]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Servers]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We present the design and evaluation of a secure peer-to-peer HTTP middleware framework that enables a multitude of web applications without relying on service providers. The framework is designed to be deployed in existing network environments, allowing ordinary users to create private services without investing in network infrastructure. Compared to previous work, scalability, NAT/firewall traversal and peer mobility is achieved without the need for maintaining dedicated servers by utilizing new network protocols and re-using existing network resources.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534942]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534942]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534942]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534942&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534942]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>40</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A feedback-based adaptive online algorithm for Multi-Gateway load-balancing in wireless mesh networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ga&#x0301; lvez, J.J.;  Ruiz, P.M.;  Skarmeta, A.F.G.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[DIIC, Univ. of Murcia, Murcia, Spain]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Internet]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Logic gates]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Switches]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We propose an adaptive online load-balancing protocol for Multi-Gateway Wireless Mesh Networks (WMNs) which, based on the current network conditions, balances load between gateways. Our protocol (GWLB) achieves two goals: (i) alleviating congestion in affected domains and (ii) balancing load to improve flow fairness across domains. As a result of applying GWLB the throughput and fairness of flows improves. The proposed scheme effectively takes into account the elastic nature of TCP traffic, and intra-flow and inter-flow interference when switching flows between domains. Through simulations, we analyze performance and compare with a number of proposed strategies, showing that GWLB outperforms them. In particular, we have observed average flow throughput gains of 104% over the nearest gateway strategy.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534914]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534914]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534914]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534914&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534914]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>41</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Game theory for channel assignment of cognitive radios]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ghosh, A.;  Hamouda, W.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Electr. & Comput. Eng., Concordia Univ., Montreal, QC, Canada]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Ad hoc networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel allocation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cognitive radio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Games]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[2]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We propose channel selection algorithm for cognitive ad-hoc radios using noncooperative game theory and present simulation results that show, the proposed algorithm distributes cognitive nodes according to the bandwidth ratio of the channels.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534939]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534939]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534939]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534939&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534939]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>42</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Channel pool management for video streaming in WLAN]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Xin Liu;  Calcev, G.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Electr. & Comput. Eng., Univ. of California, Davis, CA, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11g Standard]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Streaming media]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Switches]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless LAN]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we present a Wireless Local Area Network (WLAN) channel selection algorithm and testbed implementation for video streaming applications. We call this type of spectrum management functionality Channel Pool Management (CPM). Specifically, we designed a scheme called Shifted Mask Superposition (SMS) that harnesses the transmitter spectral mask to help predict WLAN channel quality dynamically with only passively monitored channel information. We performed extensive experiments to model the spectral mask and verified the effectiveness of our algorithm. Based on our scheme, we built a testbed that implements the main functionality within CPM and performed channel switching without disrupting the video streaming application. Experiments showed that our proposed scheme can predict the best channel for video streaming with 90% accuracy and can improve the video quality significantly compared to systems that do not implement CPM.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534958]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534958]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534958]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534958&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534958]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>43</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A context-aware framework for health care governance decision-making systems: A model based on the Brazilian Digital TV]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Oliveira, M.;  Hairon, C.;  Andrade, O.;  Moura, R.;  Sicotte, C.;  Denis, J.-L.;  Fernandes, S.;  Gensel, J.;  Bringel, J.;  Martin, H.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Fed. Inst. of Ceara, Fortaleza, Brazil]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Adaptation model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Context]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Context modeling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decision making]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Digital TV]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Medical services]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper proposes a governance decision-making framework for public health care systems. It encompasses and integrates data about family homes in a new intelligent health care information system. In order to support end-user interactions, the framework has been built on the GINGA middleware developed for the Brazilian Digital TV, whose full access will be country-wide in 2015. Based on five governance fields, namely knowledge, normative, clinical-epidemiological, administrative, and shared management, the framework relies on an Optical-WiMAX communication infrastructure (Brazilian Digital Belt), which will reach 82% of urban population in the Ceara State. In addition, we present a case study showing how the framework could be used for improving health care governance decisions.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534979]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534979]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534979]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534979&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534979]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>44</rank>

<title><![CDATA[SAMSON: Secure access for medical smart cards over networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Hembroff, G.C.;  Muftic, S.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Sch. of Technol., Michigan Technol. Univ., Houghton, MI, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Authentication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fingerprint recognition]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Medical diagnostic imaging]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Medical services]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Personnel]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Smart cards]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents several smart card security extensions to the FIPS 201 PIV standard of security and authentication of mobile health. Our contributions are designed to better protect the patient's data and to increase the functionality and interoperability of smart cards in health care. Our solution, called SAMSON, consists of two types of smart cards. The first, a security card, is issued to all personnel within any medical organization, while the second, the medical card, is issued to patients and used to securely store and retrieve health care information. These smart cards are being tested within a 14 hospital federated consortium in Michigan's Upper Peninsula.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534982]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534982]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534982]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534982&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534982]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>45</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Load-balanced routing and gateway selection in wireless mesh networks: Design, implementation and experimentation]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ancillotti, E.;  Bruno, R.;  Conti, M.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Inst. for Inf. & Telematics (IIT), Italian Nat. Res. Council (CNR), Pisa, Italy]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Internet]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Logic gates]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mesh networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Streaming media]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Traffic routing and gateway selection for Internet flows play a crucial role in determining the performance of WMNs. Optimal routing strategies have been derived under the assumption that the traffic demands are static and known a priori, or that can be accurately predicted. However, the effectiveness of most of the existing optimization-based routing solutions is still to be demonstrated in real-world deployments. In this paper we present a practical and robust framework for load-balanced routing and gateway selection in WMNs under variable traffic loads, which relies only on real-time measurements of network statistics. Then, we design, implement and evaluate two simple adaptive strategies to automatically select network paths and gateways for flows that dynamically arrive and depart, with the goal of achieving a high network utilization and improved load balancing. We have developed a full-fledged implementation of the proposed mechanisms as an extension of the OLSR protocol, and conducted an experimental study in a trial outdoor mesh network using video streaming traffic. Collected measurements show that our scheme can significantly increase the number of video sessions that can be supported with acceptable quality compared to traditional shortest path routing.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534991]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534991]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534991]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534991&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534991]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>46</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Reactive on-board regulation of cognitive radios]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Yu Zhang;  Baliga, A.;  Trappe, W.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Wireless Inf. Network Lab., Rutgers Univ., Piscataway, NJ, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Chromium]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cognitive radio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Indexes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Media Access Protocol]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multiaccess communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Orbits]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Malicious users may reprogram cognitive radios to disregard how their actions may harm other users. To cope with such threats, we propose that cognitive radios must have a trusted domain, which contains an onboard regulation mechanism (ORM) that 'regulates' the radio's behavior by monitoring the radio, and taking appropriate action. We present a scheme for monitoring the link quality, in real-time to assess the proper action to take. Our method promptly prevents misbehavior by taking action in a manner proportional to the level by which the cognitive radio deviates from normal, allowed behavior. We demonstrate a method for the ORM to collect the link state information needed to regulate its cognitive radio. Lastly, we examine the resulting algorithms and study our regulation relative to traditional CSMA and Aloha MAC protocols on the ORBIT testbed using USRP/GNU Radios.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5535003]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5535003]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5535003]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5535003&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5535003]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>47</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Synchronization impact on the performance of Data-Timed Sending (DTS) based wireless sensor networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Chomu, K.;  Gavrilovska, L.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Inst. of Telecommun., Ss. Cyril & Methodius Univ., Skopje, Macedonia]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multiaccess communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Noise]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Synchronization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Energy efficiency of Wireless Sensor Networks (WSNs) is highly affected by duration of periods when sensors transmit data. In order to reduce the amount of transmitted bits from each sensor's radio, the basic Data Timed Sending (DTS) method was recently proposed by the authors [1]. Basic DTS addresses the packet size reduction, achieved by eliminating the Data Payload from the data packets or by using the acknowledgment packets. The information about measured values is transferred by choosing appropriate moment (time slot and time window) in the time interval for performing the packet transmission. The position of every time slot corresponds to a particular node and the position of every time window corresponds to a certain value of measured phenomenon. In one time interval each node sends data from one measurement. Since the synchronization is crucial for feasibility of this method, this paper examines the impact of synchronization error. The simulation results show that for the realistic levels of noise, the Linear Regression (LR) synchronization technique offers sufficient accuracy.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534954]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534954]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534954]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534954&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534954]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>48</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Reservation-based distributed scheduling in wireless networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Vejarano, G.;  McNair, J.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Univ. of Florida, Gainesville, FL, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Frequency modulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimal scheduling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Schedules]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Scheduling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Stability analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Several distributed scheduling policies for wireless networks that achieve a provable efficiency ratio have been developed recently. These policies are characterized by the selection, at the onset of every time slot, of a subset of links according to the interference model of the network and the length of the links' queues. The selected subset of links is for the next time slot only. In this paper, we propose a new framework for the stability analysis of distributed scheduling policies that allow links to transmit data packets in any future time slots by means of slot reservations. Within this framework, we propose and analyze a reservation-based distributed scheduling policy for IEEE 802.16 mesh networks. We find sufficient conditions for the stability of the network when the traffic uses one hop. Specifically, we prove a lower bound for its efficiency ratio by evaluating the stability conditions obtained from our proposed framework. Finally, we compare this lower bound with the capacity achieved in simulation results.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534904]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534904]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534904]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534904&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534904]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>49</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Spectrum sharing between IEEE 802.16 and IEEE 802.11 based wireless networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Siddique, M.M.;  Wenning, B.;  Gorg, C.;  Muehleisen, M.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Commun. Networks, Univ. of Bremen, Bremen, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11e Standard]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.16 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Due to the high scarcity and high costs of radio spectrum, more and more radio services are occupying unlicensed bands for their operation. Due to this, there is a high risk of destructive interference which degrades the performance and fails to support Quality of Service (QoS) for systems operating in these bands. IEEE 802.11 based wireless networks are already operating in unlicensed band. A new competitor for unlicensed bands is the IEEE 802.16 based wireless metropolitan area network. Therefore, spectrum sharing between coexisting competing wireless systems like 802.11 and 802.16 is an upcoming challenge. To understand the characteristics of interference in such a heterogeneous scenario, an analysis of possible interference is presented and the performance of the legacy systems is evaluated. Then a spectrum sharing concept is proposed which can generally be applied to both systems. In this paper, the proposed concept is adapted for coexisting 802.16 and 802.11e based systems, which is an extention of 802.11. In this case, the 802.11e Hybrid Coordination Function (HCF) Controlled Channel Access (HCCA) is extended to provide a protocol for airtime sharing. Simulation results are presented showing that the proposed algorithm provides excellent improvement of system performance in the context of capacity and channel utilization compared to the case without applying any spectrum sharing method.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534964]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534964]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534964]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534964&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534964]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>50</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A distributed privacy-preserving scheme for location-based queries]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Magkos, E.;  Kotzanikolaou, P.;  Sioutas, S.;  Oikonomou, K.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Inf., Ionian Univ., Corfu, Greece]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Aggregates]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Context]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Encryption]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Privacy]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we deal with security and historical privacy in Location Based Service (LBS) applications where users submit accurate location samples to an LBS provider. Specifically we propose a distributed scheme that establishes access control while protecting the privacy of a user in both sporadic and continuous LBS queries. Our solution employs a hybrid network architecture where LBS users: (a) are able to communicate with an LBS provider through a network (e.g., cellular) operator, and (b) they are also able to create wireless ad-hoc networks with other peers in order to obtain privacy against an adversary that performs traffic analysis. Our threat model considers the network operator, the LBS provider and other peers, as potential privacy adversaries. For historical privacy we adopt the generic approach of using multiple pseudonyms that are changed frequently. In order to establish untraceability against traffic analysis attacks, a message is not sent directly to the cellular operator, but it is distributed among mobile neighbors who act like mixes and re-encrypt a message before sending it to the LBS provider via the cellular operator. As an extension, we also discuss how to aggregate independent data from different mobile peers before sending them to the LBS provider. This approach may be suitable in applications where aggregate location data are useful (e.g., traffic monitoring and control)]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534928]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534928]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534928]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534928&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534928]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>51</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A vision of cooperation tools for VANETs]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Molina-Gil, J.;  Caballero-Gil, P.;  Caballero-Gil, C.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Stat., Oper. Res. & Comput., Univ. of La Laguna, La Laguna, Spain]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Ad hoc networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Internet]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Lead]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile computing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Pediatrics]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vehicles]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A Vehicular Ad-hoc NETwork (VANET) is a special type of Movile Ad-hoc Network designed to provide communications among On-Board Units (OBUs) in nearby vehicles, and between OBUs in vehicles and Road-Side Units (RSUs) that are fixed equipment located on the road. Data packets have to be relayed hop by hop from a given OBU to a RSU or another OBU and vice-versa. This means that the mobile stations must accept to forward information for the benefit of other stations. However, these benefits would vanish if the mobile stations did not properly cooperate and forward packets for other stations. In this paper, we address this problem and propose mechanisms that encourage collaboration in packet forwarding.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5535001]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5535001]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5535001]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5535001&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5535001]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>52</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Using time-of-day and location-based mobility profiles to improve scanning during handovers]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Boone, P.;  Barbeau, M.;  Kranakis, E.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Sch. of Comput. Sci., Carleton Univ., Ottawa, ON, Canada]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Data models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Simulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time frequency analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Trajectory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[WiMAX]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In WiMAX/IEEE 802.16 with mobility support, scanning for an available channel by a mobile station, especially during a handover, must be done promptly in order to reduce delays in network access. We have shown previously that mobile stations can reduce scanning times by maintaining a most probable list of frequencies in use. In this paper, we extend this idea to further capture the mobility patterns of users. By using time-of-day and location-based mobility profiles a mobile station improves scanning performance during handovers. We show this improvement by modeling and simulating an area of WiMAX coverage with various mobility patterns and real-world mobility traces.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534959]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534959]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534959]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534959&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534959]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>53</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Detecting blackhole attacks in Disruption-Tolerant Networks through packet exchange recording]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Yanzhi Ren;  Mooi Choo Chuah;  Jie Yang;  Yingying Chen]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of ECE, Stevens Inst. of Technol., Hoboken, NJ, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Equations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[History]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Simulation]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The Disruption Tolerant Networks (DTNs) are especially useful in providing mission critical services such as in emergency networks or battlefield scenarios. However, DTNs are vulnerable to insider attacks, in which the legitimate nodes are compromised and the adversary nodes launch blackhole attacks by dropping packets in the networks. The traditional approaches of securing routing protocols can not address such insider attacks in DTNs. In this paper, we propose a method to secure the history records of packet delivery information at each contact so that other nodes can detect insider attacks by analyzing these packet delivery records. We evaluated our approach through extensive simulations using both Random Way Point and Zebranet mobility models. Our results show that our method can detect insider attacks efficiently with high detection rate and low false positive rate.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534944]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534944]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534944]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534944&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534944]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>54</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A social transitivity-based data dissemination scheme for opportunistic networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Jaesung Ku;  Yangwoo Ko;  Jisun An;  Dongman Lee]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Comput. Sci., KAIST, Daejeon, South Korea]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Artificial neural networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Communities]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Probability]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Social network services]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A social-based routing protocol for opportunistic networks considers the direct delivery as forwarding metrics. By ignoring the indirect delivery through intermediate nodes, it misses chances to find paths that are better in terms of delivery ratio and time. To overcome this limitation, we propose to incorporate transitivity, which considers the indirect delivery through intermediate nodes, as one of the forwarding metrics. We also found that some message forwards do not improve the delivery performance. To reduce the number of these useless forwards, the proposed scheme forwards messages to an encountered node when the increase of total utility value is greater than a threshold. Using a simulator with real world trace data sets, we compare the proposed scheme with the existing protocols, epidemic routing and SimBetTS. Compared with SimBetTS, the proposed scheme increases delivery ratio by 1.5 percent and decreases delay time by 2 percent while reducing overhead by 30 percent.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534912]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534912]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534912]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534912&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534912]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>55</rank>

<title><![CDATA[PDF Not Yet Available In IEEE Xplore]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[1]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The document that should appear here is not currently available.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534931]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534931]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534931]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534931&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534931]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>56</rank>

<title><![CDATA[XS-WSNet: Extreme scale wireless sensor network simulation]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Asim, A.;  Tixeuil, S.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[LRI - CNRS 8623, Univ. Paris Sud-XI, Paris, France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Load modeling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Object oriented modeling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Scalability]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Synchronization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Recent advances in wireless sensor networks show an expansion both in the size of the network and in the variety of the applications that are to be executed. In this context, wireless network simulators play a key role in the design, development and testing of new wireless sensor networks applications and protocols. Most of the currently available wireless sensor network simulators work well for small to medium sized networks yet fail to scale to really large networks, mainly due to their single desktop machine architecture and its limited resources. In this paper, we present XS-WSNet, a wireless sensor network simulator that is designed with extreme scalability as a prime objective. First, we distribute the simulated wireless sensor network nodes on a variety of actual machines that communicate through a wired network. A large-scale simulation is then emulated by several smaller scale simulations that run concurrently and collaboratively. As smaller instances of simulations running on different machines usually induce asynchrony and non-determinism in the whole system, we also propose a distributed synchronization protocol, responsible for simulation accuracy in some simulation models. Our implementation (both asynchronized and synchronized versions) of XS-WSNet is fully evaluated in various contexts using a scalable benchmark application. Against its single machine version, the distributed simulator provides sensible matching results, exhibits both scale-up and speed-up of the simulation, and performs with linear slowdown with up to ten million simulated nodes.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534898]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534898]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534898]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534898&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534898]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>57</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Efficient network selection in heterogeneous communication scenarios using arbitration]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Lahde, S.;  Wegner, M.;  Wolf, L.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Inst. of Oper. Syst. & Comput. Networks, Tech. Univ. Braunschweig, Braunschweig, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Benchmark testing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Internet]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quality of service]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Schedules]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Mobile internet has rapidly evolved in the past years with an ever increasing number of novel technologies and services. Today's mobile devices often support multiple communication technologies for accessing Internet services. However, they all do not tap the full potential of these capabilities as users often have to manually select networks and only one network is used at a time. Different approaches in the area of Always Best Connected propose strategies for user-centric network selection, but most of them focus either on application-oriented or device-centric approaches. The muXer project aims at combining both aspects and increasing the efficiency of network usage. In this paper, we introduce the muXer Global Arbitration Process (GAP) that balances application-oriented ratings of networks while optimizing the usage of communications resources and simultaneously meeting the application and user requirements. Besides deciding which single network an application should use, GAP considers network bundles as well as a proactive delaying of data transfers as additional options to reach a global optimum for all applications running on the device. We compare GAP with other network selection strategies and present benchmarks showing that these aspects bring a clear efficiency gain.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534957]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534957]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534957]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534957&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534957]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>58</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Statistical modeling of harvestable kinetic energy for wearable medical sensors]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Yarkony, N.;  Sayrafian-Pour, K.;  Possolo, A.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Acceleration]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Accelerometers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Biomedical monitoring]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Energy harvesting]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Force]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Generators]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensors]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Energy Harvesting (EH) refers to the process of capturing and storing energy from external sources or ambient environment. Kinetic energy harvested from the human body motion seems to be one of the most convenient and attractive solution for wearable wireless sensors in healthcare applications. Due to their small size, such sensors have a very limited battery power supply, which necessitates frequent recharge or even sensor replacement. Energy harvesting can prolong the battery lifetime of these sensors. This could directly impact their everyday use and significantly help their commercial applications such as remote monitoring. In this paper, our aim is to estimate the amount of harvestable energy from typical human motion. To simplify the measurement process, we focus on the amount of kinetic energy harvested from the human forearm motion. We provide statistical analysis of measurements taken from 40 test subjects over a period of 8 hours during the day. Using this information and knowing the operational architecture of the harvesting device, the distribution of harvestable energy can also be determined. Our objective is to study whether kinetic energy generated by typical human forearm motion could be a promising supplemental energy resource that prolongs the operational lifetime of wearable medical sensors.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534988]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534988]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534988]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534988&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534988]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>59</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Automatic planning of UMTS release 4.0 networks using realistic traffic]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Pasandideh, M.R.;  St-Hilaire, M.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Syst. & Comput. Eng., Carleton Univ., Ottawa, ON, Canada]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[3G mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Computer architecture]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Context]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Joining processes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Planning]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Since Universal Mobile Telecommunications System (UMTS) networks are very expensive to deploy, network optimization is an important issue for service providers to remain competitive. As a result, this paper proposes a new mathematical programming model in order to plan UMTS Release 4.0 networks. Given realistic traffic profile as input, the model simultaneously considers voice and data services as well as network signaling. More precisely, the model finds the number, the type and the location of the network elements (NE), selects the number and the type of links and interfaces and finally designs the network topology. The objective of the model is to minimize network cost. An illustrative example of the model is described and a set of randomly generated problems are solved using a commercial implementation of the branch-and-bound algorithm.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534923]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534923]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534923]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534923&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534923]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>60</rank>

<title><![CDATA[MAC layer design in cognitive radio networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bayhan, S.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Comput. Eng., Bogazici Univ., I&#x0307;stanbul, Turkey]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Chromium]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Femtocells]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Media Access Protocol]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[2]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The main focus of this thesis is to design and develop cognitive MAC protocols for various networks. Furthermore, we aim to explore the design tools, approaches and auxiliary systems that can be adapted to and applied in cognitive radio (CR) domain. In particular, we proposed a distributed spectrum access scheme for ad hoc CR networks (CRN) in which each secondary user (SU) acts in an altruistic way. The proposed access scheme improves CRN throughput compared to the selfish scheme that is mostly considered in the literature. Next, we propose a symbiotic operation of CRs and cognitive femtocells, in which SUs use the sensing outcome of the femto-BS and are charged accordingly. Addition of &#x0022;cognitive&#x0022; sensing to the femto-BS contributes to the discovery of spectrum holes and facilitates higher bandwidth at the femtocells compared to the conventional femto-BS. Currently, we focus on design and development of adaptive medium access control (MAC) protocol that considers various aspects of the operating environment (e.g. PU mobility) and the CR itself.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534967]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534967]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534967]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534967&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534967]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>61</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Design and implementation of a behavioral migraine management iPhone app for adolescents with migraine]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Chang Liu;  Holroyd, K.A.;  Qing Zhu;  Kaiyu Shen;  Wenqi Zhou]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Sch. of EECS, Ohio Univ., Athens, OH, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Internet]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Libraries]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Materials]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Medical services]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multimedia communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Training]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Our recent feasibility study of a telephone-administrated Behavioral Migraine Management (BMM) program for teens revealed that while learning and improvements in migraine were encouraging, experience for teens could be further improved with on-demand access to BMM instruction and materials. To meet this demand, an iPhone application was developed to help adolescent migraine patients and their counselors manage migraine with our behavioral migraine management approach. This application provides on-demand access to audio, video and animated instructions to guide the learning and application of behavioral migraine management skills as well as a headache diary that allows adolescents and their counselors to monitor key migraine and medication use variables. The design, implementation, current status, and future plan of this BMM iPhone App for adolescents are described in this paper.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534985]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534985]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534985]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534985&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534985]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>62</rank>

<title><![CDATA[General lower and best case upper bounds on energy optimal multicasting in wireless ad hoc and sensor networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Frey, H.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Univ. of Paderborn, Paderborn, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Energy consumption]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Joining processes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Steiner trees]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Unicast]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Upper bound]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Given a source node and a set of k destination nodes, what is the minimum total energy required for sending a message from source to destinations when multicasting along optimal placed relaying nodes is applied? In this work I will answer this question under the assumption that non-cooperative relaying is applied and that communication over a distance d requires energy proportional to d<sup>&#x03B1;</sup> &#x002B; &#x03B2; for some a &#x003E; 1 and &#x03B2; &#x003E; 0. I derive lower bound expressions for a MAC layer model which does not exploit the broadcast property of wireless communication and for a MAC layer model which exploits it. I show further, in case of optimal relay positions, how multicasts can be constructed whose energy consumption always stays below the derived lower bound plus an additive constant expression depending on &#x03B1;, &#x03B2;, k. The usefulness of the bound derived in this work is exemplified with three different example applications.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534900]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534900]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534900]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534900&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534900]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>63</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Analyzing the effective throughput in multi-hop IEEE 802.1 in networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Frohn, S.;  Gubner, S.;  Lindemann, C.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Comput. Sci., Univ. of Leipzig, Leipzig, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Analytical models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11n Standard]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we characterize the effective throughput for multi-hop paths in IEEE 802.1 In based wireless mesh networks. We derive an analytical model capturing the effects of frame aggregation and block acknowledgements, features found in the new IEEE 802.1 In standard. We describe the throughput at MAC layer as a function of bit error rate, aggregation level and path length. Using the results of our model as an upper bound, we show that current TCP implementations do not harness the bandwidth provided by the IEEE 802.1 In MAC layer. Subsequently we introduce collision induced rate control which uses cross layer feedback to effectively estimate the available bandwidth based on our analytical model. We conduct a comprehensive performance study, showing that results from our analytical model are closely matched by simulation results. Furthermore we show that the proposed protocol achieves up to 50% more goodput and up to 70% less frame collisions compared to TCP-SACK and TCP-NewReno.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534993]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534993]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534993]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534993&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534993]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>64</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On the impact of uplink power control in network MIMO systems with MMSE and SIC receivers]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Fodor, G.;  Sorrentino, S.;  Johansson, M.;  Soldati, P.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Ericsson Res., Stockholm, Sweden]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Joints]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Power control]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Silicon carbide]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Network multiple input, multiple output (MIMO) systems are built around a broadband backbone network that allows for the fast communication of channel state information (CSI) as well as user data between different base stations. Previous works have shown that multicell channel adaptive (opportunistic) power control can minimize the sum power or maximize the sum rate when the backbone is used for the exchange of CSI in network MIMO systems. In this work we investigate the gains of multicell opportunistic power control under per user fairness constraints when both CSI and user data are shared between multiple sites. We find that multicell opportunistic power control working in concert with uplink joint signal detection is an efficient means both for the capacity and the power control problems that not only minimizes sum power or maximizes overall capacity, but is also able to provide arbitrary level of fairness.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534921]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534921]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534921]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534921&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534921]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>65</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Router selfishness in community wireless mesh networks: Cross-layer benefits and harms]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Gierlowski, K.;  Konorski, J.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Fac. of Electron., Telecomm & Inf., Gdansk Univ. of Technol., Gdansk, Poland]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IP networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network topology]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In community wireless mesh (CWM) networks following the IEEE 802.11s standard, wireless nodes combine the functionality of a client application host and a transit packet router. Not being subjected to tight administrative control, CWM nodes may act selfishly by refusing to forward transit packets along (selected) established routes or to participate in the route creation process. Unlike in a mobile ad hoc network (MANET), a CWM node is typically connected to mains electricity, hence unconcerned about energy expenditure; the only rational (as distinct from malicious) motivation behind selfish behavior is then to prevent the incoming transit traffic from competing with the source traffic and thereby achieve a higher source throughput. We examine through simulation the benefits and harms of selfish behavior with a cross-layer view and relate them to the router density, selfish routers' location and details of their behavior. We find many conclusions and intuitions valid in MANET environments incorrect in CWMs.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534998]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534998]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534998]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534998&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534998]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>66</rank>

<title><![CDATA[OptiMOS: Optimal MOS-based scheduling of downlink voice flows in point-to-multipoint access networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Andreozzi, M.M.;  Steay, G.;  Sabella, D.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dipt. di Ing. dell''Inf., Univ. of Pisa, Pisa, Italy]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Codecs]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Physical layer]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Speech]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Synchronization]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We introduce OptiMOS, a method for selecting deadlines for the scheduling of downlink voice flows in a centralized-scheduling point-to-multipoint network. These include cellular networks such as LTE, UMTS HSDPA, or WiMAX, and WLANs with centralized control. OptiMOS selects the deadline of each packet so as to maximize the expected Mean Opinion Score (MOS) for the talkspurt it belongs to. It requires that absolute time is both included in RTP timestamps at the source and checked for scheduling decisions, in a cross-layer approach. OptiMOS can be employed in conjunction with any deadline-based scheduling algorithm, and does not require a specific playout buffering scheme at the receiver. Simulations of an LTE system show a performance improvement in terms of MOS for the VoIP flows, good tolerance to relatively large synchronization errors and qualitatively similar results with different playout buffers.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534961]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534961]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534961]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534961&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534961]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>67</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Tradeoffs between security and communication performance in wireless mesh networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Curtmola, R.;  Jing Dong;  Nita-Rotaru, C.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Comput. Sci., New Jersey Inst. of Technol., Newark, NJ, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Security]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In the context of wireless mesh networks (WMNs), we ask the question whether a high level of security can be achieved while providing good communication performance. To answer this question, we examine two techniques designed and shown to improve throughput performance in WMNs: high-throughput routing and network coding. Although the advantages of using these techniques hold in a benign setting, it is not clear whether they can be preserved under an adversarial setting. We analyze these techniques and reveal a wide range of security vulnerabilities. We then investigate whether alternative schemes can be designed to be secure and still preserve most of the advantages achieved in benign settings.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5535005]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5535005]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5535005]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5535005&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5535005]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>68</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Neighbor discovery in 60 GHz wireless personal area networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Xueli An;  Venkatesha Prasad, R.;  Niemegeers, I.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Fac. of Electr. Eng., Math., & Comput. Sci., Delft Univ. of Technol., Delft, Netherlands]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Analytical models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Directional antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Neodymium]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Niobium]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Performance evaluation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[60 GHz radio is a promising technology which can handle the data rate of the order of gigabits-per-second. Hence, it is an attractive candidate for wireless personal area networks (WPANs). Due to the high path loss, directional antennas are recommended for use in 60 GHz systems. To set-up directional communications, it is essential to obtain the knowledge of direction of the surrounding devices. However, a neighbor discovery process using directional antennas is nontrivial. In this paper, we provide a comprehensive investigation of using directional antenna for neighbor discovery process. We demonstrate the performance of neighbor discovery using different antenna modes combining different neighbor discovery mechanisms. Our results may aid in designing directional antennas for 60 GHz WPANs.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534989]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534989]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534989]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534989&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534989]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>69</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On the maximum performance in opportunistic routing]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Cerda&#x0300; -Alabern, L.;  Darehshoorzadeh, A.;  Pla, V.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Comput. Archit. Dept., Univ. Politec. de Catalunya, Barcelona, Spain]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Equations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Gain]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Numerical models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Propagation losses]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Upper bound]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In recent years there has been a growing interest in Opportunistic Routing as a way to increase the capacity of wireless networks by exploiting its broadcast nature. By contrast to traditional uni-path routing, in opportunistic routing the nodes overhearing neighbor's transmissions can become candidates to forward the packets towards the destination. In this paper we address the question: What is the maximum performance that can be obtained using opportunistic routing? To answer this question we use an analytical model that allows to compute the optimal position of the nodes, such that the progress towards the destination is maximized. We use this model to compute bounds to the minimum expected number of transmissions that can be achieved in a network using opportunistic routing.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534897]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534897]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534897]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534897&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534897]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>70</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Virtual smartphone over IP]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Chen, E.Y.;  Itoh, M.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Inf. Snaring Platform Labs., NTT Corp., Musashino, Japan]]></affiliations>

<controlledterms>

<term><![CDATA[IP networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[image processing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[mobile computing]]></term>

</controlledterms>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Batteries]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Prototypes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Security]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Servers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Smart phones]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The number of smartphone users and mobile application offerings are growing rapidly. A smartphone is often expected to offer PC-like functionality. In this paper, we present Virtual Smartphone over IP system that allows users to create virtual smartphone images in the mobile cloud and to customize each image to meet different needs. Users can easily and freely tap into the power of the data center by installing the desired mobile applications remotely in one of these images. Because the mobile applications are controlled remotely, they are not constrained by the limit of processing power, memory and battery life of a physical smartphone.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534992]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534992]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534992]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534992&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534992]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>71</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Cross-layer H.264 scalable video downstream delivery over WLANs]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bianchi, G.;  Detti, A.;  Loreti, P.;  Pisa, C.;  Thakolsri, S.;  Kellerer, W.;  Widmer, J.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Univ. of Tor Vergata, Rome, Italy]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[PSNR]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Scalability]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Static VAr compensators]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Streaming media]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless LAN]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Thanks to its in-network drop-based adaptation capabilities, H.264 Scalable Video Coding is perceived as an effective approach for delivering video over networks characterized by sudden large bandwidth fluctuations, such as Wireless LANs. Performance may be boosted by the adoption of application-aware/cross-layer schedulers devised to intelligently drop video data units (NALUs), so that i) decoding dependencies are preserved, and ii) the quality perceived by the end users is maximized. In this paper, we provide a theoretical formulation of a QoE utility-optimal cross-layer scheduling problem for H.264 SVC downlink delivery over WLANs. We show that, because of the unique characteristics of the WLAN MAC operation, this problem significantly differs from related approaches proposed for scheduled wireless technologies, especially when the WLAN carries background traffic in the uplink direction. From these theoretical insights, we derive, design, implement and experimentally assess a simple practical scheduling algorithm, whose performance is very close to the optimal solution.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534890]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534890]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534890]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534890&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534890]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>72</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Connectivity guarantee during wireless sensor networks deployment]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Razafindralambo, T.;  Simplot-Ryl, D.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[INRIA, Univ.-Lille 1, Villeneuve-d''Ascq, France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Force]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Partitioning algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Simulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we consider the self-deployment of wireless sensor networks. We present a mechanism which allows to preserve network connectivity during the deployment of mobile wireless sensors. Our algorithm is distributed and is based on a subset of neighbours for motion decision. Our algorithm maintains a connected topology regardless of the direction chosen by each sensor. To preserve connectivity, the distance covered by the mobile nodes is constrained by the connectivity of the node to its neighbours in a connected subgraph like the relative neighbourhood graph (RNG). We show the connectivity preservation property of our algorithm through analysis and present some simulation results for the full coverage problem.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534951]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534951]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534951]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534951&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534951]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>73</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A signal combining technique based on channel shortening for cooperative sensor networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Hussain, S.I.;  Alouini, M.-S.;  Hasna, M.O.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Texas A&M Univ. at Qatar, Doha, Qatar]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Diversity reception]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Frequency division multiplexing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multipath channels]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time division multiplexing]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The cooperative relaying process needs proper coordination among the communicating and the relaying nodes. This coordination and the required capabilities may not be available in some wireless systems, e.g. wireless sensor networks where the nodes are equipped with very basic communication hardware. In this paper, we consider a scenario where the source node transmits its signal to the destination through multiple relays in an uncoordinated fashion. The destination can capture the multiple copies of the transmitted signal through a Rake receiver. We analyze a situation where the number of Rake fingers N is less than that of the relaying nodes L. In this case, the receiver can combine N strongest signals out of L. The remaining signals will be lost and act as interference to the desired signal components. To tackle this problem, we develop a novel signal combining technique based on channel shortening. This technique proposes a processing block before the Rake reception which compresses the energy of L signal components over N branches while keeping the noise level at its minimum. The proposed scheme saves the system resources and makes the received signal compatible to the available hardware. Simulation results show that it outperforms the selection combining scheme.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534947]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534947]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534947]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534947&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534947]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>74</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Next-generation E-health communication infrastructure using converged super-broadband optical and wireless access system]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Chowdhury, A.;  Hung-Chang Chien;  Khire, S.;  Shu-Hao Fan;  Xianfeng Tang;  Jayant, N.;  Gee-Kung Chang]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Sch. of Electr. & Comput. Eng., Georgia Tech Broadband Inst., Atlanta, GA, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Biomedical optical imaging]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Broadband communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Communication system security]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Medical services]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optical fibers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Delivering affordable high-quality E-health care services requires effective telecommunication and multimedia technologies in conjunction with medical expertise. In this paper, we propose and demonstrate a telecommunication and networking architecture for implementing next generation Telemedicine and Telehealth systems. Our integrated optical-wireless based network provides super broadband, ultra low-latency connectivity for voice, video, image and data across various telemedicine modalities to facilitate real-time and near real-time communication of remote health care information.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534984]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534984]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534984]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534984&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534984]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>75</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Comparing simulation tools and experimental testbeds for wireless mesh networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Kefeng Tan;  Wu, D.;  An Chan;  Mohapatra, P.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Comput. Sci., Univ. of California, Davis, CA, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bit rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Load modeling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Portable computers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receiving antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Wireless simulators provide full control to researchers in investigating traffic flow behavior, but do not always reflect real-world scenarios. Although previous work pointed out such shortages are due to the limitation of radio propagation models in the simulators, it is still unclear how these imperfect models affect network behavior and to what degree. In this paper, we quantify network behavioral differences between simulations and real-world testbed experiments. We compare and analyze the experimental results from indoor and outdoor experiments with the results from NS-2 and Qualnet simulations. We find that in the PHY layer, the distribution of received signal strength in experiments is usually different from simulation due to the antenna diversity. However, path loss, which is regarded as a dominating factor in simulator channel modeling, can be configured to match the real-world behavior. For the MAC layer, increasing traffic load on a flow may cause significant performance degradation in experiments, but it is not the case in simulations. Interference is inadequately captured in simulations and cannot show the flow level unfairness phenomenon. In the network layer, a few dominant routes exist in testbed experiments while routes in simulations are less stable. These findings give the wireless research community an improved overview about the differences between simulations and testbed experiments. They will help researchers to choose between simulations and experiments according to their particular research requirements.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534917]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534917]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534917]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534917&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534917]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>76</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Pervasive speech API demo]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Radomski, S.;  Schnelle-Walka, D.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Telecooperation, Tech. Univ. Darmstadt, Darmstadt, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Contracts]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Microphones]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Speech]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Ubiquitous computing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[User interfaces]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[2]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Current approaches for voice based interaction do not meet the special requirements of pervasive environments. While there is an increasing trend towards distributed systems, the concept of the classical client/server paradigm still prevails. We describe a framework wherein functional components are orchestrated dynamically, taking into account the users context and the changing availability and suitability of services in pervasive environments.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534938]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534938]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534938]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534938&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534938]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>77</rank>

<title><![CDATA[SHARC: Community-based partitioning for mobile ad hoc networks using neighborhood similarity]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Herbiet, G.;  Bouvry, P.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[FSTC - CSC, Univ. du Luxembourg, Luxembourg City, Luxembourg]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Ad hoc networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Benchmark testing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Communities]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Heuristic algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network topology]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Robustness]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this contribution, we present SHARC, a Sharper Heuristic for Assignment of Robust Communities. This algorithm performs distributed network partitioning into communities using epidemic propagation of community labels and the computation of a neighborhood similarity metric. Due to its decentralized nature, SHARC is scalable and well suited for networks where no global knowledge nor node coordination exist, like ad hoc networks. Besides, SHARC is computationally efficient and does not depend on configuration parameters. We validated our approach and compared it to alternative solutions using static and dynamic networks. Results show that SHARC provides a sharper and more robust community assignment and prevents the domination of a single community in both static and dynamic networks.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534915]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534915]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534915]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534915&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534915]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>78</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Assessment of the true risks to the protection of confidential information in the wireless home and office environment]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Barbeau, M.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Sch. of Comput. Sci., Carleton Univ., Ottawa, ON, Canada]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Communication system security]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cryptography]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Malware]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Risk management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The ubiquity of wireless communications, in the home and office environment, introduces information security risks specific to WLANs and handheld devices. It is crucial to continuously monitor their evolution but every threat must be examined in terms of potential impact and likelihood. Only when both conditions are present, it does need to be mitigated. This paper shows how the problem can be addressed in a methodological manner. By conducting a proper risk assessment we can identify the threats, to the security of wireless communications, that are real and the ones that are inoffensive. Examples related to the protection of confidential information, in the wireless home and office environment, are used to illustrate the point.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534940]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534940]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534940]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534940&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534940]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>79</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Channel tracking algorithms for highly efficient wireless broadband communications in rural areas]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Atapattu, L.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Fac. of Build Environ. & Eng., Queensland Univ. of Technol., Brisbane, QLD, Australia]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Algorithm design and analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Broadband antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Broadband communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Prediction algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[2]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[High-speed broadband internet access is widely recognised as a catalyst to social and economic development, having a significant impact on global economy. Rural Australia's inherent dispersed population over a large geographical area make the delivery of efficient, well-maintained and cost-effective internet a challenging task. The novel and highly-efficient Multi-User-Single-Antenna for MIMO (MUSA-MIMO) broadband wireless communication technology can effectively be used to deliver wireless broadband access to rural areas. This research aims to develop for the first time, an efficient and accurate algorithm for the tracking and prediction of Channel State Information (CSI) at the transmitter, by characterising time variation effects of the wireless communication channel on the performance of a highly-efficient MUSA-MIMO technology particularly suited for rural communities, improving their quality of life and economic prosperity.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534978]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534978]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534978]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534978&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534978]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>80</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Least attained recent service for packet scheduling over wireless LANs]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Heusse, M.;  Urvoy-Keller, G.;  Duda, A.;  Brown, T.X.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Grenoble Inf. Lab., Grenoble, France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Scheduling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time factors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless LAN]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Wireless LANs suffer from performance problems caused by insufficient medium access opportunity given to the access point. Consequently, the downlink buffer fills up, which often leads to packet losses. We propose to address this problem by using a size-based scheduling approach, which is known to favor short flows and the start up of new ones-a very appealing property from the user's perspective as interactive applications and new flows are serviced quickly. Still, size-based scheduling policies have a well-known Achilles heel: large flows can block each other for long periods of time and low rate multimedia transfers may end up with a low priority when their accumulated transferred volume becomes large. To solve the above deficiencies, we propose a new packet scheduling scheme called Least Attained Recent Service (LARS) that applies a temporal decay to the volume of data associated with each flow. In this way, its priority depends more on what has happened recently. With this strategy, LARS can bound the impact of a new arriving flow on ongoing flows, thus limiting lock out durations. It can also efficiently protect low rate multimedia transfers irrespectively of the load conditions.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534906]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534906]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534906]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534906&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534906]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>81</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Security and privacy for mobile electronic health monitoring and recording systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Barnickel, J.;  Karahan, H.;  Meyer, U.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[UMIC Res. Center, RWTH Aachen, Aachen, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bluetooth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cryptography]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Handheld computers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Medical services]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile handsets]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we detail the security and privacy architecture and implementation of the HealthNet mobile electronic health monitoring and data collection system. HealthNet consists of a body sensor network embedded in clothing that communicates wirelessly to the wearer's mobile phone. The mobile phone is used to manage, store and transfer the data in a secure way. Data may be transferred to other parties, such as medical experts, emergency care and private parties trusted by the wearer himself, e.g. his family. The patient controls who may access his data. Only emergency physicians nearby the patient may access vital data without the patient's individual consent. We describe the unique security and privacy features of our architecture which may also be used to improve other telemonitoring solutions.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534981]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534981]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534981]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534981&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534981]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>82</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Utility-based channel assignment and topology control in wireless mesh networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Dionysiou, T.;  Siris, V.A.;  Stamatakis, G.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Inst. of Comput. Sci., Found. for Res. & Technol. Hellas (FORTH), Heraklion, Greece]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Aggregates]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Logic gates]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network topology]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Topology]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We define a utility-based framework for joint channel assignment and topology control in multi-rate multi-radio wireless mesh networks, and present a greedy algorithm for solving the corresponding optimization problem. Key features of the proposed approach are the support for different target objectives, which are expressed as utility functions of the MAC layer throughput, and the efficient utilization of wired network gateways, while guaranteeing that for every mesh node there exists a path to a gateway. Investigations show the influence of different target objectives on the channel assignment and network topology, demonstrate the proposed approach's load balancing properties in mesh networks containing multiple gateways, show the effect of 802.11a adjacent channel interference on the channel assignment, and compare the performance of the proposed procedure with a rate-based channel assignment scheme.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534902]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534902]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534902]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534902&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534902]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>83</rank>

<title><![CDATA[AGC-based RF Fingerprints in Wireless Sensor Networks for authentication]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Knox, D.A.;  Kunz, T.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Carleton Univ., Ottawa, ON, Canada]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Authentication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fingerprint recognition]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Hardware]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radio frequency]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[RF Fingerprints can be used to distinguish between distinct transmitter signals in a Wireless Sensor Network. We present implementation results for RF Fingerprints based on Automatic Gain Control circuitry, which is present on existing IEEE 802.15.4 WSN node hardware and in other radio systems. We analyze implementation constraints and their different effects on our results. Different noise sources affect RF Fingerprint measurement accuracy on a real hardware platform. We present a simple method to improve both accuracy and reliability.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534953]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534953]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534953]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534953&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534953]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>84</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Gradual adaptation of security for sensor networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Taddeo, A.V.;  Micconi, L.;  Ferrante, Alberto]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Fac. of Inf., Univ. of Lugano, Lugano, Switzerland]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Cryptography]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Degradation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Energy consumption]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks are composed of nodes with stringent constraints on resources. Some of this devices may have the possibility to recharge batteries (e.g., by means of solar panels); though, a reduced power consumption is anyway a key factor when recharge resources are not available (e.g., during the night for solar panels). In this paper we describe a method for security self-adaptation tailed for wireless sensor networks. This method allows devices to adapt security of applications gradually with the goal of guaranteeing the maximum possible level of security while satisfying power constraints. A case study, implemented on Sun SPOTs, is also presented to show how the method works in a real wireless sensor network.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534903]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534903]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534903]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534903&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534903]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>85</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Demonstration of seamless multimedia session transfer to support pervasive mobile computing]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Gazda, R.G.;  Purkayastha, D.;  Xin Feng;  Samimi, F.A.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[InterDigital, LLC, King of Prussia, PA, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Media]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multimedia communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Portable computers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Servers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Smart phones]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Streaming media]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[USA Councils]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[1]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In today's media environment, multimedia content is accessed by mobile users in a silo fashion, with content locked to individual point devices and networks. Content, available on one device or one network, may not be accessed from other devices, or over other networks. Users cannot easily share multimedia sessions across devices, such as smartphones and laptops. Media content does not adapt with user mobility. Specifically, users cannot take advantage of the multitude of media devices that they encounter as they move, in order to achieve a &#x0022;best&#x0022; possible multimedia experience. In the future, media will transition seamlessly between devices, networks, and access technologies with the user, as the user moves. Session continuity technologies, driven by global standards bodies, will make seamless media mobility possible. Media content will be optimized based on the real-time conditions of the user, including: available networks and bandwidth, available device configurations and rendering capabilities, battery consumption, memory and processing power, location, cost, etc. Our demonstration allows a user to transfer a streaming video session across a collection of laptop and smartphone devices. Specifically, the demonstration includes: a MAC Pro laptop, a MacBook Air laptop, Android Gl / G2 smartphones, and a Blackberry Bold 9000 smartphone. Each terminal device runs a small media application, which presents the user with a set of video clips for viewing. When the user selects a clip, the application server commands the media server to stream the requested video. Each video may be viewed to completion; or, the user may transfer the video session to any of the other terminal devices in the demonstration. With a click or touch of the screen, the media application presents the user with a list of available devices to engage in media transfer sessions. With another click or touch, the user may trigger a media session transfer: &#x2022; The application serv- - er dynamically configures the media server and triggers the target device to get engaged in the streaming session. &#x2022; The target device initializes its media player, which begins to buffer the video stream. During buffering time, which lasts a few seconds, an advertisement image is displayed (pre-roll canvas). &#x2022; The originating device continues to play the video, until the video session begins playing on the target device. &#x2022; The target device notifies the originating device as soon as its initialization is complete and it starts playing the video. Upon receiving the notification, the originating device tears down the video session and returns to the media application home screen.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534934]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534934]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534934]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534934&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534934]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>86</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Achievement notification in a real-world achievement system]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Triebel, T.;  Schnaufer, S.;  Effelsberg, W.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Univ. of Mannheim, Mannheim, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Computer architecture]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Context]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Databases]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radiofrequency identification]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Servers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Software]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless LAN]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[2]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We propose a global system for acquisition, maintenance and communication of achievements in the real-world. The main focus of the proposal lies on a context-aware notification service for achievements. Users of the system can browse the achievement web application and will only get notifications of users within the same context. The definition of context is based on the network infrastructure of the client accessing the system. Our server utilizes information derived from IP-routing traces to build the notification groups.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534943]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534943]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534943]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534943&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534943]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>87</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Using a backlogged queue approach for adaptive MAC frame aggregation]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bhanage, G.;  Raychaudhuri, D.;  Seskar, I.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Technol. Center, Rutgers Univ., North Brunswick, NJ, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Driver circuits]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11e Standard]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Noise]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Payloads]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless LAN]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Frame aggregation is a wireless link optimization mechanism that aims to reduce transmission overheads by sending multiple frames as the payload of a single MAC frame. Static assignment of frame aggregation parameters can result in delay penalties due to variations in traffic type or load levels. Another possible side effect is an increase in packet error rate in noisy environments due to large aggregated frame size. Adaptive aggregation methods have previously been proposed to deal with the above problems independently, but there is still a need for a unified adaptation algorithm that addresses both aspects in an integrated manner. In this study, a backlogged queue (BQ) aggregation approach is proposed that considers both these aspects, and also ensures inter-operability with other WLAN devices that are not capable of frame aggregation. Performance evaluation of the proposed algorithm on the ORBIT testbed shows throughput improvements of up to 56% in the presence of channel noise and 25% in scenarios with high contention over using a simple txop. An experimental case study shows improvement in FTP file transfer times of up to 11% while preserving performance for real time traffic.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534911]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534911]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534911]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534911&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534911]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>88</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Social similarity as a driver for selfish, cooperative and altruistic behavior]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Jaho, E.;  Karaliopoulos, M.;  Stavrakakis, I.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Inf. & Telecommun., Nat. & Kapodistrian Univ. of Athens, Athens, Greece]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Context]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Guidelines]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Heuristic algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Social network services]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper explores how the degree of similarity within a social group can be exploited in order to dictate the behavior of the individual nodes, so as to best accommodate the typically non-coinciding individual and social benefit maximization. More specifically, this paper investigates the impact of social similarity on the effectiveness of content dissemination, as implemented through three classes representing well the spectrum of behavior-shaped content storage strategies: the selfish, the self-aware cooperative and the optimally altruistic ones. This study shows that when the social group is tight (high degree of similarity), the optimally altruistic behavior yields the best performance for both the entire group (by definition) and the individual nodes (contrary to typical expectations). When the group is made up of foreigners with almost no similarity, altruism or cooperation cannot bring much benefits to either the group or the individuals and thus, a selfish behavior would make sense due to its simplicity. Finally, the self-aware cooperative behavior could be adopted as an easy to implement distributed scheme &#x2014; compared to the optimally altruistic one &#x2014; that has close to the optimal performance for tight social groups, and has the additional advantage of not allowing mistreatment to any node (i.e., the content retrieval cost become larger compared to the cost of the selfish strategy).]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534930]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534930]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534930]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534930&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534930]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>89</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Resilient Peer-to-Peer live-streaming using motifs]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Krumov, L.;  Andreeva, A.;  Strufe, T.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Tech. Univ. Darmstadt, Darmstadt, Germany]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network topology]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Peer to peer computing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resilience]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Robustness]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Topology]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[High robustness against churn and resilience towards adverse behavior are the key requirements for reliable Peer-to-Peer streaming systems. Their highly inter-dependent nature, based on the cooperative service delivery between all peers, necessitates a systematic and structural resilience, which, in their design of self-organization and decentralized control, is very challenging to assure. Reliable services, and hence a structural resilience, still are a vital prerequisite for any commercial deployment of P2P-based live streaming systems or IPTV infrastructures. We propose an entirely distributed, Motif-based topology optimization to this end. Concise comparisons show that it creates topologies almost as resilient as the current state of the art, yet causing significantly less, almost negligible overhead in both computation and messaging, and still offering even better protection of information on the overall system.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534893]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534893]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534893]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534893&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534893]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>90</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A robust flooding algorithm in multi-radio multi-channel wireless mesh networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Youndo Lee;  Kideok Cho;  Kwon, T.;  Yanghee Choi]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Sch. of Comput. Sci. & Eng., Seoul Nat. Univ., Seoul, South Korea]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Pediatrics]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Reliability]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Simulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Storms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Flooding, that is to deliver a packet from one node to all other nodes in the network, is an integral part of many wireless protocols. Flooding is often implemented by a series of broadcasts of each node and this causes some problems such as the broadcast storm and low reliability, by being engaged with the effects of radio signal propagation, e.g., multipath fading and interference. Many researchers have studied these problems over the years, however, most of these studies have been carried out assuming that all nodes in the network are equipped with a single radio interface and utilize only a single channel. This implies that most of the existing mechanisms that enhance the performance of flooding in wireless networks will not work in multi-radio multi-channel wireless mesh networks (MR-MC WMNs). Motivated by this, in this paper, we propose a flooding mechanism that works well in MR-MC WMNs. Our flooding mechanism, which can operate with an arbitrary number of radio interfaces and channels, increases the reliability of flooding while alleviates the broadcast storm problem, using only local information. Through a detailed simulation study, we demonstrate that our flooding mechanism improves both the reliability and the efficiency of flooding in MR-MC WMNs.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534955]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534955]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534955]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534955&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534955]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>91</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Conditional shortest path routing in delay tolerant networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bulut, E.;  Geyik, S.C.;  Szymanski, B.K.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Comput. Sci., Rensselaer Polytech. Inst., Troy, NY, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Government]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[History]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing protocols]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Delay tolerant networks are characterized by the sporadic connectivity between their nodes and therefore the lack of stable end-to-end paths from source to destination. Since the future node connections are mostly unknown in these networks, opportunistic forwarding is used to deliver messages. However, making effective forwarding decisions using only the network characteristics (i.e. average intermeeting time between nodes) extracted from contact history is a challenging problem. Based on the observations about human mobility traces and the findings of previous work, we introduce a new metric called conditional intermeeting time, which computes the average intermeeting time between two nodes relative to a meeting with a third node using only the local knowledge of the past contacts. We then look at the effects of the proposed metric on the shortest path based routing designed for delay tolerant networks. We propose Conditional Shortest Path Routing (CSPR) protocol that routes the messages over conditional shortest paths in which the cost of links between nodes is defined by conditional intermeeting times rather than the conventional intermeeting times. Through trace-driven simulations, we demonstrate that CSPR achieves higher delivery rate and lower end-to-end delay compared to the shortest path based routing protocols that use the conventional intermeeting time as the link metric.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534960]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534960]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534960]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534960&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534960]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>92</rank>

<title><![CDATA[WANDA B.: Weight and activity with blood pressure monitoring system for heart failure patients]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Myung-kyung Suh;  Evangelista, L.S.;  Chen, V.;  Wen-Sao Hong;  Macbeth, J.;  Nahapetian, A.;  Figueras, F.;  Sarrafzadeh, M.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Comput. Sci. Dept., Univ. of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Strontium]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Heart failure is a leading cause of death in the United States, with around 5 million Americans currently suffering from congestive heart failure. The WANDA B. wireless health technology leverages sensor technology and wireless communication to monitor heart failure patient activity and to provide tailored guidance. Patients who have cardiovascular system disorders can measure their weight, blood pressure, activity levels, and other vital signs in a real-time automated fashion. The system was developed in conjunction with the UCLA Nursing School and the UCLA Wireless Health Institute for use on actual patients. It is currently in use with real patients in a clinical trial.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534983]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534983]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534983]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534983&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534983]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>93</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Empirical studies and queuing modeling of denial of service attacks against 802.11 WLANs]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Chibiao Liu;  Yu, J.;  Brewster, G.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Coll. of Comput. & Digital Media, DePaul Univ., Chicago, IL, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Computer crime]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Computer hacking]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Data models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Queueing analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless LAN]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The growing popularity of 802.11-based wireless LANs (WLAN) also increases the risk of security attacks. Most studies of WLAN security are on the protection of data integrity, and few studies are addressing the issue of Denial of Service (DoS) attacks. This paper studies two major DoS attacks of authentication request flooding (AuthRF) and association request flooding (AssRF). Our studies show that these DoS attacks cause significant performance degradations and may disconnect the communications. A queuing model is presented to study the attacking mechanisms, and the causes of performance degradations. The analytical results of the queuing model are validated by the simulation model, and both results are consistent with the empirical data. The queuing model analysis leads to the development of four solutions: Request Authentication (RA), Reduction of Duplicate Requests (RDR), Reduction of Response Retransmissions (RRR), and Round Robin Transmission (RRT). We tested these four solutions and collected empirical data to validate the effectiveness of the solutions. A comparison of these four solutions is presented to show their strengths and weaknesses in resolving the attacks.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534920]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534920]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534920]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534920&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534920]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>94</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Distributed storage in Disruption Tolerant Network]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Jingzhe Du;  Kranakis, E.;  Nayak, A.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Sch. of Comput. Sci., Carleton Univ., Ottawa, ON, Canada]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Maintenance engineering]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Memory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile ad hoc networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Peer to peer computing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing protocols]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We describe a novel Distributed Storage protocol in Disruption (Delay) Tolerant Networks (DTN). Since DTNs can not guarantee the connectivity of the network all the time, distributed data storage and look up has to be performed in a store-and-forward way. In this work, we define local distributed location regions which are called cells to facilitate the data storage and look up process. Nodes in a cell have high probability of moving within their cells. Our protocol resorts to storing data items in cells which have hierarchical structure to reduce routing information storage at nodes. Multiple copies of a data item may be stored at nodes to counter the adverse impact of the nature of DTNs. The cells are relatively stable regions and as a result, data exchange overheads among nodes are reduced. Through experimentation, we show that the proposed distributed storage protocol achieves higher successful data storage ratios with lower delays and limited data item exchange requirements than other protocols in the literature.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534948]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534948]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534948]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534948&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534948]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>95</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Towards securing mintroute in wireless sensor networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Hegazy, I.;  Safavi-Naini, R.;  Williamson, C.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Comput. Sci., Univ. of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Simulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Topology]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In a Wireless Sensor Network (WSN), the sensor nodes rely upon a multi-hop routing protocol to relay their data to the base station. However, most WSN routing protocols are vulnerable to attacks in which a malicious node can disrupt the routes, drop, modify, or divert data away from the base station. In this paper, we use the ns-2 network simulator to demonstrate the vulnerability of the MintRoute protocol to link quality attacks by a malicious node. We then propose a novel &#x0022;sequence number gap trick&#x0022; as a lightweight means to test for and detect the presence of a malicious attacker. The simulation results show that judicious use of the sequence number gap trick provides robust detection of malicious nodes, preserving the data delivery capabilities of the WSN.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5535004]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5535004]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5535004]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5535004&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5535004]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>96</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Attribute-aware data aggregation using dynamic routing in wireless sensor networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Jiao Zhang;  Fengyuan Ren;  Tao He;  Chuang Lin]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Tsinghua Nat. Lab. for Inf. Sci. & Technol., Beijing, China]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Force]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Temperature sensors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Timing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Data aggregation has been widely recognized as an efficient method to reduce energy consumption in wireless sensor networks, which can support a wide range of applications such as monitoring temperature, humidity, level, speed etc. The data sampled by the same kind of sensors have much redundancy since the sensor nodes are usually quite dense in wireless sensor networks. To make data aggregation more efficient, the packets with the same attribute, defined as the identifier of different data sampled by different sensors such as temperature sensors, humidity sensors, etc., should be gathered together. However, to the best of our knowledge, present data aggregation mechanisms did not take packet attribute into consideration. In this paper, we take the lead in introducing packet attribute into data aggregation and propose an Attribute-aware Data Aggregation mechanism using Dynamic Routing (ADADR) which can make packets with the same attribute convergent as much as possible and therefore improve the efficiency of data aggregation. This goal cannot be achieved by present static routing schemes employed in most of data aggregation mechanisms since they construct routes before transmitting the sampled data and thus can not dynamically forward packets in response to the variation of packets at intermediate nodes. Hence, we present a potential-based dynamic routing scheme which employs the concept of potential in physics and pheromone in ant colony to achieve our goal. The results of simulations in series of scenarios show that ADADR indeed conserve energy by reducing the average number of transmissions each packet needs to reach the sink and is scalable with regard to the network size.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534896]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534896]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534896]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534896&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534896]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>97</rank>

<title><![CDATA[An estimator model for distributed estimation in heterogenous wireless sensor networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Shanying Zhu;  Cailian Chen;  Xinping Guan;  Chengnian Long]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Autom., Shanghai Jiao Tong Univ., Shanghai, China]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Computational modeling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Integrated circuits]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Markov processes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensor fusion]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we deal with distributed estimation using consensus algorithms for heterogenous wireless sensor networks (WSNs). To accommodate with the heterogeneity, we introduce a novel distributed estimator to track the weighted average of the input signals. Different from existing models, we consider a more practical scenario to take account of hierarchical processing abilities of different sensors: type-I sensors with high processing ability and type-II senors with low processing ability for distributed sensor fusion in WSNs. We investigate the properties of our model and illustrate the feasibility of the proposed estimator via a case study where we use the estimator to track the weighted average of a noisy time-varying signal based on the sensors' noisy and distorted measurements. Convergence analysis in this scenario is given as well as the effect of network topology and estimator parameters are also studied. Simulation results are provided to demonstrate the performance and effectiveness of the proposed estimator.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534946]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534946]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534946]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534946&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534946]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>98</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Streaming H.264 scalable video over data distribution service in a wireless environment]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Detti, A.;  Loreti, P.;  Blefari-Melazzi, N.;  Fedi, F.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Electron. Eng. Dept., Univ. of Rome "Tor Vergata", Rome, Italy]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Ad hoc networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Encoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Publish-subscribe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Static VAr compensators]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Streaming media]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transform coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[3]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The Data Distribution Service (DDS) middleware is enjoying a rapid adoption in high-performance, mission-critical networks. At the same time, the H.264 Scalable Video Coding (SVC) has been recently standardized and it is deemed to be an effective solution for video streaming over a channel with time-varying bandwidth, like the wireless one. In these conditions, it is critical to adapt the video bit-rate to the actual wireless capacity, and bit-rate adaptation is extremely simple for a H.264 SVC video. In this paper we devise, evaluate and demonstrate a technique for streaming H.264 SVC video over a DDS middleware. The contribution is threefold: i) we design a structure of the DDS data-unit able to carry H.264 SVC video-units; ii) we devise a receiver-driven rate-control mechanism based on our DDS data-unit and exploiting specific DDS functionality; iii) we implement and show the effectiveness of our mechanism in an 802.11 wireless scenario, comparing our proposal with other solutions.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534937]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534937]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534937]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534937&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534937]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>99</rank>

<title><![CDATA[P2P overlay topology control in MANETs]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Mawji, A.;  Hassanein, H.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Telecommun. Res. Lab., Queen''s Univ., Kingston, ON, Canada]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Ad hoc networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Games]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile computing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Nash equilibrium]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network topology]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Peer to peer computing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Topology]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[P2P applications are enormously popular on the Internet and their uses vary from file sharing to Voice-over-IP to gaming and more. Increasingly, users are moving toward wireless networked devices and wish to continue using P2P applications in these new environments. MANETs are expected to grow in use as wireless mesh and 4G networks increase in popularity. P2P and MANETs share some similarities, such as self-organization, dynamism, and resilience to failure, but it is necessary that P2P algorithms should take advantage of the realities of MANETs. In P2P networks, the overlay peers must form a topology of connections between themselves and this topology should reflect the underlying network in order to reduce delay and energy consumption. We study the results of a game-theoretic topology control algorithm which considers energy and distance between nodes in a P2P network running atop a MANET. We find that the minimum cost topologies are very highly connected and thus resilient, but in most cases the topologies do not stabilize even without peer mobility or churn.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534905]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534905]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534905]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534905&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534905]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>100</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Routing for minimum length schedule in multi-channel TDMA based wireless mesh networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bo Wang;  Guokai Zeng;  Mutka, M.;  Li Xiao]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Comput. Sci. & Eng., Michigan State Univ., East Lansing, MI, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Complexity theory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Logic gates]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Schedules]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Scheduling algorithm]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In TDMA based wireless mesh networks, routing and scheduling algorithms are essential to provide QoS support for mesh clients. In order to maximize the network throughput and minimize session delay, the routing and scheduling algorithms should produce a minimum length schedule. A linear programming formulation enables an optimal solution, however has very high computational cost. In this paper, we consider network scenarios where multiple orthogonal channels are available. With a channel assignment algorithm to eliminate secondary interference, we are able to use a scheduling algorithm that yields the minimum length schedule given a specific routing tree. We then propose a heuristic routing algorithm that aims to build the routing tree that results in the minimum length schedule. Our routing algorithm performs significantly better than simple routing algorithms, which are based on Breadth First Search or Dijkstra algorithms.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534966]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534966]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534966]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534966&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534966]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>101</rank>

<title><![CDATA[[Title page]]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[1]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Conference proceedings title page.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534929]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534929]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534929]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534929&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534929]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>102</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Experiments on autonomous mobile sensor control for target tracking]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Hongbin Li;  Fan Zhang;  Jiming Chen;  Youxian Sun]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[State Key Lab. of Ind. Control Technol., Zhejiang Univ., Hangzhou, China]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile computing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Robot sensing systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Target tracking]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Technology advancements in robotics and communication make it possible to combine mobility and static wireless sensor networks. Being able to locomote enables sensors to (1) adjust their positions for better sensing quality, (2) ensure field coverage by spreading out and (3) fill up communication gap to guarantee information sharing in wireless environment. Concerning the above three criteria, we propose a autonomous management scheme for mobile sensors, aims to achieve distributed sensor position control. Accordingly, we developed a testbed for mobile sensor network verification, with good interfaces to obtain ranging measurements and control sensor motion. Implementation details of building static and mobile sensors are given. Finally we present experiment results to verify the proposed sensor control scheme.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534891]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534891]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534891]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534891&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534891]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>103</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Optimal joint routing and scheduling in wireless mesh networks with smart antennas]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Yazdanpanah, M.;  Assi, C.;  Shayan, Y.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[ECE Dept., Concordia Univ., Montreal, QC, Canada]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Pricing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitting antennas]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We present a cross-layer optimization framework for wireless mesh networks; we assume nodes are equipped with smart antenna and techniques such as beam-forming, spatial division multiple access and spatial division multiplexing are considered. These techniques provide interference suppression, capability to communicate with several nodes simultaneously and higher transmission data rates, respectively. By integrating different constraints from MAC and network layers, a mathematical formulation of the problem is presented. It is shown that the resulted directive, multiple access and multiplexing gain combined with optimal link scheduling effectively increase both the spectrum spatial reuse and the capacity of the links and thus, enhance the achievable system throughput. Since the optimization problem is a complex combinatorial one, the optimal LP solution is approached by a Column Generation decomposition method. The numerical results for different network topologies with various node densities, transmission ranges, traffics and number of antennas are provided, in which system activation time is reduced up to 86.9% by employing smart antenna techniques.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5535002]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5535002]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5535002]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5535002&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5535002]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>104</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A RTLS/DR based localization system architecture for indoor mobile robots]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bingbing Liu;  Xiaojun Wu;  Reddy, V.;  Dee Meng Kang;  Liu, Wei]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Data Storage Inst., A*STAR, Singapore, Singapore]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile robots]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Robot sensing systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Trajectory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wheels]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, aiming for mobile robot localization in indoor environments, a loosely coupled architecture, which combines indoor Real-time Locating System (RTLS) and dead reckoning (DR) system, is proposed. Within this architecture, the DR is simple and cost effective but subjected to accumulative error; the indoor RTLS can provide absolute, consistent localization estimates, therefore is complementary to DR sensors. The most outstanding feature of this architecture is that it can easily integrate any type of existing RTLS and DR sensors. Another advantage lies in the fact that this architecture adopts a linear model, thus is exempted from the risk of linearization of non-linear models. In order to verify the proposed architecture, an example localization system consisting of an ultra-wideband (UWB) RTLS system and wheel encoders based DR, on a real robot, is implemented. Experiments have been conducted on this example system and the results have demonstrated its performance.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534949]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534949]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534949]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534949&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534949]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>105</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Generic network forensic data acquisition from household and small business wireless routers]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Zhongli Liu;  Yinjie Chen;  Wei Yu;  Xinwen Fu]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Comput. Sci., Univ. of Massachusetts Lowell, Lowell, MA, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Electronic mail]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Forensics]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IP networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Portable computers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Servers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[People are benefiting tremendously from pervasively deployed WiFi networks. However, criminals may exploit the anonymity of WiFi communication and wireless routers to access illegal content such as child porn videos. It's becoming an urgent topic as regards to how to preserve and acquire network forensic data from household and small business wireless routers in order to track down criminals. In this paper, we first survey the forensic capacity of nearly all household wireless routers which are available on market. We present our analysis for people who are willing to choose a wireless router to monitor their network. Secondly, we develop a generic network forensic data logging mechanism to monitor traffic into and out of wireless routers which support OpenWrt. Our code running in the wireless routers could log network traffic and send connection information to the administrator via email.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534945]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534945]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534945]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534945&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534945]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>106</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Proximity marketing solution tailored to user needs]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Papandrea, M.;  Giordano, S.;  Vanini, S.;  Cremonese, P.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Univ. of Appl. Sci. of Southern Switzerland, Manno, Switzerland]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Communities]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fingerprint recognition]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile handsets]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Prototypes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Servers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[3]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We present a prototype for a straightforward proximity marketing solution (PROMO) over heterogeneous smart phones tailored to the needs of individual users. The system is based on the collection of Wi-Fi fingerprints in an environment, and sends data to the users' smart phones based on their interests and their location. We believe that our system has high potential because, differently from existing similar solutions, it is highly customizable and works also in indoor environments. The market validity is further confirmed by the decision to fund the development of this prototype taken by the Swiss Innovation Promotion Agency (CTI-No 11556.1).]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534936]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534936]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534936]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534936&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534936]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>107</rank>

<title><![CDATA[The CareNet residential gateway: A conceptual overview]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Zamaere, B.;  Sjodin, P.;  Pehrson, B.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Telecommun. Syst. Lab., R. Inst. of Technol., Stockholm, Sweden]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Computer architecture]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Containers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Home automation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Logic gates]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Medical services]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Security]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents a high-level overview of the CareNet Home Extension Project that aims to provide support for home-based healthcare for the elderly and outpatients. Details of a home networking environment based on a virtualized Residential Gateway (RG) are provided. The RG architecture is modular and scalable supporting the dynamic provision of third party services. This accommodates multiple independent stakeholders representing healthcare providers, Internet Services Providers (ISPs), and home automation system builders among others. Interoperability is guaranteed through adherence to open standards. Initial mechanisms facilitating the integration and consolidation of in-home systems, whilst providing a flexible framework for autonomous management, are described. This addresses issues of management and configuration of complex environments by individuals with little or no technical expertise. Finally, details of an initial implementation, in terms of architectural descriptions and enabling technological components, are outlined.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534980]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534980]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534980]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534980&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534980]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>108</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Fast computation of schedules for dynamic traffic in wireless mesh networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Peng Wang;  Bohacek, S.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Electr. & Comput. Eng., Univ. of Delaware, Newark, DE, USA]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Dynamic scheduling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Logic gates]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimal scheduling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Schedules]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time factors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Topology]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A large number of algorithms focus on using scheduling to maximize the stability region. However, this goal does not necessarily result in good performance in terms of supporting a large number of users where users' average time to transfer a file meets a target. This paper develops several computationally efficient schemes for computing schedules for time-varying offered load. Two important findings are that when the traffic is time-varying, the computational complexity can be substantially reduced by using the previous schedule as an initial starting point of the optimization (i.e., warm start). Furthermore, very few iterations (e.g., one iteration) are needed to get a suitable schedule, that is, there is no need to wait for the optimization to converge. A second finding is that there is no need to repeatedly solve the maximum weighted independent set (MWIS) problem. Instead, the MWIS problem is only solved during initialization. Because of the computational efficiency, the schemes presented can be used to frequently update schedules, allowing schedules to quickly adapt to changes in the offered load. Consequently, as compared to other scheduling schemes, the schemes developed support a larger number of users for a given average service time.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534997]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534997]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534997]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534997&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534997]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>109</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Trade-off between exploration and reporting victim locations in USAR]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Scone, S.;  Phillips, I.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Dept. of Comput. Sci., Loughborough Univ., Loughborough, UK]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Animals]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Buildings]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile robots]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Robot kinematics]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In urban search and rescue (USAR) operations, there is a considerable amount of danger faced by rescuers. The use of mobile robots can alleviate this issue. Coordinating the search effort is made more difficult by the communication issues typically faced in these environments, such that communication is often restricted to line of sight. Since the rescue workers outside of the structure need to know the location of any victims, the task is two parted: 1) to locate the victims (Search Time), and 2) to get this data outside the structure (Delay Time). Communication with the outside is assumed to be performed by a static robot designated as the Command Station. Since it is unlikely that there will be sufficient robots to provide full communications coverage of the area, robots that discover victims are faced with the difficult decision of whether they should continue searching or return with the victim data. We investigate a variety of search techniques and see how the application of biological foraging models can help to streamline the search process, while we have also implemented an opportunistic network to ensure that data are shared whenever robots come within line of sight of each other or the Command Station. We examine this trade-off between performing a search and communicating the results.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534926]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534926]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534926]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534926&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534926]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>110</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Investigating the impact of human activity on the performance of wireless networks &#x2014; An experimental approach]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ben Hamida, E.;  Chelius, G.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[INSA Lyon, Univ. of Lyon, Lyon, France]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Humans]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radio link]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Stability analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we are interested in evaluating the performance of indoor wireless networks in LOS and NLOS conditions. We first provide a thorough analysis of received signal strength indicator (RSSI) measurements obtained in indoor experiments. We aim to better understand the temporal and spatial correlations of RSSI values. Moreover, we analyze in detail the stability of radio links over time. We show that human activity has a significant impact on the performance of wireless networks and that RSSI is not always a robust indicator for the radio link quality. Based on our results, we then propose a time-varying simulation model to reproduce the RSSI variability as observed in our experiments. We argue that this model results in more realistic and accurate RSSI values to be used in simulation.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534913]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534913]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534913]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534913&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534913]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>111</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Video quality prediction in the presence of MAC contention and wireless channel error]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Saesue, W.;  Chun Tung Chou;  Jian Zhang]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Sch. of Comput. Sci. & Eng., Univ. of New South Wales, Sydney, NSW, Australia]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Analytical models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11e Standard]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Lead]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Markov processes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Predictive models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Streaming media]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless LAN]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[10]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper proposes an integrated model to predict the quality of video, expressed in terms of mean square error (MSE) of the received video frames, in an IEEE 802.1 le wireless network. The proposed system takes into account contention at the MAC layer, wireless channel error, queueing at the MAC layer, parameters of different 802.1 le access categories (ACs), and video characteristics of different H.264 data partitions (DPs). To the best of the authors' knowledge, this is the first system that takes these network and video characteristics into consideration to predict video quality in an IEEE 802.1 le network. The proposed system consists of two components. The first component predicts the packet loss rate of each H.264 data partition by using a multi-dimensional discrete-time Markov chain (DTMC) coupled to a M/G/l queue. The second component uses these packet loss rates and the video characteristics to predict the MSE of each received video frames. We verify the accuracy of our combination system by using discrete event simulation and real H.264 coded video sequences.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534895]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534895]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534895]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534895&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534895]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>112</rank>

<title><![CDATA[DEHAR: A distributed energy harvesting aware routing algorithm for ad-hoc multi-hop wireless sensor networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Jakobsen, M.K.;  Madsen, J.;  Hansen, M.R.]]></authors>

<affiliations><![CDATA[Embedded Syst. Eng., Inf. & Math. Modelling, Tech. Univ. of Denmark, Lyngby, Denmark]]></affiliations>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Availability]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Batteries]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Capacitors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Energy harvesting]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Energy measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[One of the key design goals in Wireless Sensor Networks is long lasting or even continuous operation. Continuous operation is made possible through energy harvesting. Keeping the network operational imposes a demand to prevent network segmentation and power loss in nodes. It is therefore important that the best energy-wise route is found for each data transfer from a source node to the sink node. We present a new adaptive and distributed routing algorithm for finding energy optimised routes in a wireless sensor network with energy harvesting. The algorithm finds an energy efficient route from each source node to a single sink node, taking into account the current energy status of the network. By simulation, the algorithm is shown to be able to adapt to changes in harvested and stored energy. Simulations show that continuous operation is possible.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534899]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534899]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534899]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534899&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534899]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>113</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Polar coordinate routing for multiple paths in wireless networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Desai, M.;  Maxemchuk, N.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Joining processes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Robots]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Trajectory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[World of Wireless Mobile and Multimedia Networks (WoWMoM), 2010 IEEE International Symposium on a]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5513765]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[IEEE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2010]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We propose Polar Coordinate Routing (PCR) to create multiple paths between a source and a destination in wireless networks. Our scheme creates paths that are circular segments of different radii connecting a source and a destination. We propose a non-euclidean distance metric that allows messages to travel along these paths. Using PCR it is possible to maintain a known separation among the paths, which reduces the interference between the nodes belonging to two separate routes. Our extensive simulations show that while PCR achieves a known separation between the routes, it does so with a small increase in overall hop count. Moreover, we demonstrate that the variances of average separation and hop count are lower for the paths created using PCR compared to existing schemes, indicating a more reliable system. Existing multi-path routing schemes in wireless networks do not perform well in areas with obstacles or low node density. To overcome adverse areas in a network, we integrate PCR with simple robotic routing, which lets a message circumnavigate an obstacle and follow the trajectory to the destination as soon as the obstacle is passed.<sup>l</sup>]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-1-4244-7264-2]]></isbn>

<htmlFlag><![CDATA[1]]></htmlFlag>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5534894]]></arnumber>

<doi><![CDATA[10.1109/WOWMOM.2010.5534894]]></doi>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5534894]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5534894&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5534894]]></pdf>

</document>

</root>
