<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<root>

<totalfound>114</totalfound>

<totalsearched>3812935</totalsearched>

<document>

<rank>1</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On the performance of an IEEE 802.15.6 Wireless Body Area Network]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Martelli, Flavia;  Buratti, Chiara;  Verdone, Roberto]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Modulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Payloads]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Wireless Body Area Networks (WBANs) are becoming increasingly important for a wide range of applications, from medical to entertainment services. Since 2007, IEEE 802.15 Task Group 6 has been working on a communication standard for low power devices and operation on, in, or around the human body. We consider an IEEE 802.15.6 WBAN where wearable sensor devices are distributed on the body and have to send the measured data to a coordinator. Upon reception of a query coming from the coordinator, nodes of the WBAN compete to access the channel, using the Carrier Sense Multiple Access with Collision Avoidance algorithm defined in the standard, for transmitting their data via a direct link. We evaluate network performance in terms of packet loss rate, delay, and throughput, through simulation. Two different channel models for on-body communication are considered. A comparison with a WBAN based on the IEEE 802.15.4 standard is also provided.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898050]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898050]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898050&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898050]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>2</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Experimental results based on macro-cell metropolitian propagation measurements in Shanghai]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Li, Yingzhe;  Wang, Ping;  Gou, Tianhang;  Li, Pengpeng;  Hong, Aihua;  Sommerkom, Gerd;  Thomae, Reiner S.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Area measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bridges]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cities and towns]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Statistical distributions]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The primary goal of this paper aims at providing the first experimental results of the wave propagation channels in an Asian booming metropolitan environment with dense high-rise buildings and a modern infrastructure construction. The study has been performed to the channel parameters, including path loss and shadow fading (SF), bridge loss, cross-polarization ratio (XPR), and delay spread (OS). Both the statistical distribution and their correlation properties have been investigated, through examining a set of measurement data, gathered in the city center of Shanghai. Furthermore, the impacts of the light rail-bridge and the high way-bridge on the channel parameters have been studied in the measured area.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898041]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898041]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898041&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898041]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>3</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Area Energy Consumption in Cooperative Decode and Forward (DF) Relaying Scenarios]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ahsin, Tafzeel ur Rehman;  Slimane, Slimane Ben]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Energy consumption]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Land mobile radio cellular systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Power demand]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Energy efficiency in cellular networks has become an important design parameter in recent research works due to the global climate change and growing demand for very high data rates in future cellular systems. In our work, the main objective is to reduce the area energy consumption in a cellular network, for a given average spectral efficiency, in order to realize the green radio transmissions. The energy consumption for different transmission schemes such as direct link, decode and forward (DF) relaying with and without network coding is compared in this regard using a linear power consumption model. The impact of different parameters such as cell radius, the number and position of deployed relays and target spectral efficiency is studied for each transmission scheme. It has been concluded that DF relaying in general, provides moderate power savings as compared to the direct link transmission. Moreover, for a given outage probability, the network coding at the relay extends the cell coverage and provides higher spectral efficiency as compared to the conventional DF relaying and the direct transmission.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898010]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898010]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898010&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898010]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>4</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Design of Energy Efficient Topologies for Wireless On-Body Channel]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Joseph, Wout;  Braem, Bart;  Reusens, Elisabeth;  Latre, Benoit;  Martens, Luc;  Moerman, Ingrid;  Blondia, Chris]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antenna measurements]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Loss measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network topology]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Topology]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Torso]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Advanced applications in the area of remote health monitoring can be realized by Wireless Body Area Networks (WBANs). This paper investigates the physical propagation channel at 2.45 GHz near real humans and presents an application for cross-layer design in order to optimize the energy consumption of single-hop and multi-hop network topologies. The characterization of the physical layer is an important element in the development of a WBAN. Propagation measurements are performed on real humans in a multipath environment and propagation models are proposed. As a cross-layer application, the proposed path loss models are used to evaluate the energy efficiency of different network topologies. The paper investigates which topology is the most energy efficient in WBANs: single-hop or multi-hop communication.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898054]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898054]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898054&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898054]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>5</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Biomedical Signals In BANs: Pre-Channel Issues]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Baji?, Dragana;  Milovanovi?, Branislav]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Communication channels]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Iron]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Medical treatment]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents the problems that are inherent to biomedical signals. These problems might devastate the efforts for transmission optimization, as the signal is corrupted before entering the communication channel. A possible solution might be to include experts of different fields, in particular the end users, to make a comprehensive analysis of their needs and knowledge about the signal, and to pre-process the signal accordingly.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898069]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898069]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898069&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898069]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>6</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Implementation of a Low Power Low Complexity ASIP for various Sphere Decoding Algorithms]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Rust, Jochen;  Osewold, Christof;  Paul, Steffen]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Complexity theory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Hardware]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Pipelines]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Power demand]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal processing algorithms]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Programmability is a welcome feature to use hardware modules in different products. However, in mobile applications power consumption is an important limitation. Very complex algorithms can be found in wireless communication that require efficient processing considering computation performance as well as power consumption. For the application area of multiple input multiple output (MIMO) signal detection, Sphere Decoding is a popular method. We pick several of those algorithms with similar basic instructions and design an application specific instruction set processor (ASIP). We show the optimized microarchitecture of the data path and the defined instruction set. Further power reduction is achieved by low level power optimization methods.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898015]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898015]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898015&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898015]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>7</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Interference Coordination Based on Statistical CSI in Multi-User MISO Cellular System]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Cho, Hee-Nam;  Heo, Gil-Su;  Lee, Yong-Hwan]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Array signal processing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Eigenvalues and eigenfunctions]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Indexes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quantization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper considers an interference coordination with the use of statistical channel state information (CSI) (e. g., transmit correlation) to mitigate other-cell interference (OCI) in a multi-user multi-input single-output (MISO) cellular system. To this end, we first show that the OCI can be characterized in terms of eigenvalues and angle difference between eigenvectors of the transmit correlation matrices of the desired and OCI channel. Then, a coordinated user scheduling strategy is designed with the use of statistical beamforming to minimize the OCI in an average sense. Analytic and numerical results show that the proposed scheme can maximize the achievable sum-rate when the principal eigenvectors of the transmit correlation matrices of the desired and OCI channel are orthogonal to each other, yielding a sum-rate performance comparable to that of minimum mean-square error-based coordinated beamforming (MMSE-CBF) with the use of instantaneous CSI.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897982]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897982]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897982&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897982]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>8</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Joint Power and Interference Trade-off for Underlay Cognitive Beamforming Technique]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Hou, Jiancao;  Ma, Yi;  Tafazolli, Rahim]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Array signal processing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cognitive radio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radio transmitters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Underlay cognitive beamforming allows secondary transmitters to suppress interferences to the primary users, whilst maintain their own quality of services. This paper aims at investigating joint power and interference trade-off inherent in the underlay cognitive beamforming scheme. It is shown that the work of interests leads to a non-convex optimization problem, which can be resolved by employing the second-order cone programming. It is theoretically proved that introducing zero-interference to the primary user does not always lead to the system optimality; moreover, we exhibit two conditions, for which the interference should be treated as noise in order to maximize the sum-rate of the considered beamforming system.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898011]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898011]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898011&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898011]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>9</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Opportunistic Sampling for Random Field Estimation with M2M Capillary Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Matamoros, Javier;  Anton-Haro, Carles]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Closed-form solution]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Encoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensor phenomena and characterization]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we address the problem of the estimation of spatial random fields from the samples collected by a number of sensing devices in a capillary M2M network. In order to preserve batteries, sensors are often required to operate in a low duty-cycle regime. Hence, we ask ourselves whether opportunistically activating sensors, that is, only allowing sensors experiencing favorable conditions in the sensor-to-gateway channels participate in the estimation process, might be beneficial in terms of the resulting distortion. To answer this question, we derive closed-form expressions of the optimal encoding rate and the optimal number of sensors that, under a total bandwidth constrain and for a prescribed duty cycle, minimize the distortion in the reconstructed random field. The proposed opportunistic sampling scheme is then analyzed by means of computer simulations and its performance assessed and compared with that of other systems with random (i.e. non-opportunistic) sensor activation. The impact of the pre-defined duty cycle on delay-tolerant and delay-constrained communication strategies is analyzed, as well.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898020]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898020]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898020&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898020]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>10</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Study on the Wide-Sense Stationarity of the Underwater Acoustic Channel for Non-coherent Communication Systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Tomasi, Beatrice;  Preisig, James;  Deane, Grant B.;  Zorzi, Michele]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sea surface]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time frequency analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time series analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Underwater acoustics]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we study the wide sense stationarity of the energy of the underwater acoustic channel impulse response and we provide an estimate of the interval during which the wide sense stationarity property holds. We analyze the SPACE08 data set, which has been collected near Martha¿s Vineyard Island during October 2008. In this data set the environmental conditions such as the height of the waves and the wind direction vary significantly in time. We consider the time series recorded in four different fixed positions. This allows us to compare the results between different locations and environmental conditions.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898076]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898076]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898076&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898076]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>11</rank>

<title><![CDATA[AoA, AoD and ToA Characteristics of Scattered Multipath Clusters for THz Indoor Channel Modeling]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Priebe, Sebastian;  Jacob, Martin;  Kuerner, Thomas]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Approximation methods]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Azimuth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Computational modeling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Ray tracing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Rough surfaces]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Scattering]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Surface roughness]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[At Terahertz frequencies, commonly used indoor building materials like plaster must be considered as rough, so that rough surface scattering exerts a significant impact on ultra broadband THz propagation channels. Allowing for the modeling of scattering, the characteristics of scattered multipath components like angle and time of arrival as well as phase distributions are investigated in a small office scenario. A double directional channel model is derived in the AoA, AoD and ToA domain. The dependence of the multipath characteristics on the surface roughness is demonstrated. Exemplary channel realizations are generated according to the proposed approach and are contrasted to ray tracing simulations for the evaluation of the applicability of the model.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898060]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898060]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898060&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898060]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>12</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Extended Mappings for Wireless Network Coded Butterfly Network]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Burr, Alister;  Sykora, Jan]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Encoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Physical layer]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Upper bound]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We consider the application of wireless network coding to a &#x0022;butterfly&#x0022; wireless network, comprising two sources and two destinations sharing a single relay. We obtain upper bounds on the end to end capacity of the network in terms of the codebook cardinalities, allowing the use of an extended rather than a minimal hierarchical mapping at the relay and assuming that partial complementary side information is available at each destination directly from its complementary source. We further show that this bound may be achieved using a linear mapping at the relay. We obtain numerical results for the mutual information on the links of the network, and hence show that the extended mapping may provide increased capacity compared to the minimal for some values of channel fading parameters.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898037]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898037]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898037&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898037]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>13</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Labelling Diversity for MIMO Systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Krasicki, Maciej]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Decision support systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper is to contribute a new space-time diversity scheme, in which two different labelling maps (both with high asymptotic coding gain) are applied in adjacent space streams. Several methods, i. e. EXtrinsic Information Transfer (EXIT) Chart, Distance Spectrum, Asymptotic Coding Gain evaluation, as well as Monte Carlo simulation, display better performance of the proposed system in comparison with its ancestor, Bit-Interleaved Space-Time Coded Modulation with Iterative Decoding (BI-STCM-ID).]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898005]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898005]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898005&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898005]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>14</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Mixed CSIT DL Channel: Gains with Interference Aware Receivers]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ghaffar, Rizwan;  Salim, Umer;  Ghauri, Irfan;  Knopp, Raymond]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Complexity theory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Phase shift keying]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The broadcast channels (BC), a single transmitter transmitting data to multiple receivers, have been widely studied in literature mostly with and sometimes without the availability of channel state information at the transmitter (CSIT). We study a very practical version of the BC where the transmitter has CSIT of some users and no CSIT for other users. We look at the simplest instance of such a heterogeneous BC where a multi-antenna transmitter base-station (BS) is trying to communicate data to two single-antenna user equipments (UEs), having the perfect CSIT about UE-1 and no CSIT about UE-2. We propose a very simple transmission strategy at the BS combined with an intelligent interference-aware receiver at UE-2. We show that under the proposed transmission strategy, the sum rate can be significantly improved (unbounded in SNR) if low complexity interference-aware receiver is employed at UE-2 as compared to the case when UEs resort to suboptimal single-user detection where rates are bounded (in SNR). We then extend the proposed transmission strategy to long term evolution (LTE) scenario and show that the employment of interference aware receivers significantly improve performance in spite of the low resolution LTE precoders. It therefore underlines the necessity of intelligent receivers for modern wireless systems in the pursuit of high spectral efficiency.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898022]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898022]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898022&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898022]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>15</rank>

<title><![CDATA[DDA-COV: A Distributed Dual-based Algorithm for Sensing Range Adjustment in WSNs]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Naderan, Marjan;  Dehghan, Mehdi;  Pedram, Hossein]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Convergence]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Energy consumption]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Heuristic algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Target tracking]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we have modeled the problem of adjusting the sensing range parameter for the application of multiple target coverage in wireless sensor networks (WSNs) through the Network Utility Maximization (NUM) framework. Our problem consists of maximizing the logarithm of sensing range of each sensor node as an approximation to the number of covered targets subject to energy constraint and reduction in the number of common covered targets. We assume the placement of sensors is known and the sensing range of each node is a continuous parameter. We used the dual decomposition technique to derive a distributed price-based algorithm, DDA-COV, for each node to adjust its sensing range during iterations in which the targets are static. Simulation results show the convergence of sensing ranges and utility function towards optimal values in few iterations with near optimal energy consumption of nodes.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897984]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897984]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897984&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897984]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>16</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Multi-user Relaying with Full Frequency Reuse for Enhanced LTE-GBR Coverage]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Venkatkumar, V.;  Haustein, T.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bit rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[LTE-OFDM systems will be deployed on the next generation of cellular networks. The peak data rate capability has undergone a tremendous improvement. Yet, novel outdoor to indoor coverage solutions are needed, mainly because more users are expected to be indoors where the fading loss is high. Relaying has been considered as a promising solution. Here we provide a novel scheme for delivering guaranteed instantaneous bit rate to users via decode and forward (DF) relays, which exploit full frequency reuse indoors. We employ hierarchical OFDMA to support multiple relays and to allow multiple users to access each relay. We then suggest optimisation of channel access to base station considering that the relays are half duplex. A pertinent question then arises whether relaying is performance-effective. We find that significant coverage gain can be obtained from our solution, mainly from taking advantage of the frequency diversity and spatial diversity available at the DF relay. To obtain realistic numerical results, we use measured channels and a motivational case of 2 Mbps user bit rates.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897988]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897988]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897988&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897988]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>17</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Demonstration of an OLA-based Cooperative Routing Protocol in an Indoor Environment]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Chang, Yong Jun;  Jung, Haejoon;  Ingram, Mary Ann]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Ad hoc networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Field programmable gate arrays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Physical layer]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Synchronization]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Concurrent cooperative transmission (CCT) is a cooperative transmission (CT) technique, also known as distributed transmit diversity, where a collection of single-antenna nodes induce a signal-to-noise-ratio advantage in a receiver by transmitting multiple copies of the same message, at the same time, in multiple diversity channels. CCT has been considered in many physical layer system studies including realistic demonstrations, which presented cooperative diversity gain in terms of error rate improvement or range extension. However, there have been very few attempts to evaluate CCT-based network routing schemes on a testbed with consideration of the overheads and challenges that CCT poses to the higher layers. In this paper, we compare the OLAROAD cooperative routing protocol with the conventional Ad hoc On Demand Distance Vector (AODV) protocol, on an ad hoc network of software defined radios. OLAROAD is based on a physical layer that forms opportunistic large arrays (OLAs). We evaluate the performance of the protocols on a linear network topology in a typical office building in terms of hop count, round trip time, packet delivery ratio and route discovery time, so that the advantages and disadvantages of CCT-based routing algorithm may be observed.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898056]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898056]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898056&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898056]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>18</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Optimal Modulation for Cognitive Transmission over AWGN and Fading Channels]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Khanzadi, Mohammad Reza;  Haghighi, Kasra;  Eriksson, Thomas]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[AWGN]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Copper]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Demodulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper proposes a new modulation method for an uncoded cognitive transmission (secondary user transmission) in presence of a Primary User (PU) for AWGN and time-varying flat-fading channels. Interference symbol of the PU is assumed to be known at the transmitter of the Cognitive User (CU) beforehand. Based on this knowledge and using a symbol by symbol approach, we design a CU modulation which can fulfill the coexistence conditions of the CU and the PU. The proposed method is a low-complexity modulation approach in a single (complex-valued) dimension rather than a high dimensional coding scheme, but still it achieves good performance. The robustness of the method is also investigated in case of having an imperfect knowledge about the PU transmitted symbols. An implementation algorithm for our modulation method is presented and its performance is evaluated by experiments.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897970]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897970]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897970&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897970]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>19</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Node Switching Rates of Switch-and-Examine Relaying in Rician and Nakagami-m Fading]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Xiao, Chuzhe;  Beaulieu, Norman C.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Rayleigh channels]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Rician channels]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Silicon]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Switches]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Recently switch-and-examine relaying was proposed as a low complexity suboptimal alternative to opportunistic relaying. The main advantage of this system is its low switching rate. This can alleviate some practical implementation issues, for example, the corruption of the data signal by switching transients, as well as the switching overheads. Exact closed-form expressions for the switching rates of switch-and-examine systems operating with two or more relays under Rician and Nakagami-m fading are derived. The explicit dependence of the switching rate on the Doppler frequency of the fading is determined. The results indicate that the Rician and Nakagami-m fading cases do not show similar behaviours in their switching rates.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898070]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898070]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898070&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898070]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>20</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Code Assignment of Multilevel Coded Modulation with Iterative Decoding]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Wang, Yi;  Burr, Alister G.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Convergence]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Demodulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Iterative decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Three dimensional displays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Trajectory]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Iteration-aided multi-stage decoding (IA-MSD) of multilevel coded modulation (MLCM) has been recently developed to reduce the decoding complexity of the codes used on each level. This paper proposes two novel code assignment criteria for IA-MSD, since no complete assignment methodology has previously been defined. We invoke a set of three dimensional EXIT charts to show that the methods can guarantee almost full convergence, and that the overall constellation constrained capacity can be closely approached, using much less complex decoders than for conventional MSD. The second code assignment criterion also allows a wider choice of code types and code rates.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898033]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898033]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898033&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898033]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>21</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Performance Evaluation of the Schedule Channel Polling MAC Protocol applied to Health Monitoring in the Context of IEEE 802.15.4]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Borges, Luis M.;  Velez, Fernando J.;  Lebres, Antonio S.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Analytical models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Media Access Protocol]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Power demand]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Schedules]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Synchronization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The field of Wireless Body Area Networks (WBANs) has been growing considerably in the last years. A WBAN enables to monitor vital body signs through the placement of sensors on the human body and offers to patients more flexibility and mobility. In this paper, we examine the Quality of Service (QoS) performance metrics evaluation (single and multi-hop topology) of the Scheduled Channel Polling-MAC (SCP) protocol, whilst considering the IEEE 802.15.4 standard in the context of remote patient monitoring applications. We applied the MiXiM Framework (based on OMNeT++) in the network simulations. Our simulations results help to clarify some missing aspects in the original SCP protocol description. The IEEE 802.15.4 compliant Medium Access Control (MAC) is compared with the MAC layer in the absence of the IEEE 802.15.4, leading to similar values for the throughput in saturated conditions. The results also show that considering low duty cycles, the use of IEEE 802.15.4 leads to lower energy. For multi-hop experiments in high duty cycles, the energy consumptions are lower with the AT86RF231 transceiver, comparing with the CC1100 and CC2420. Future work includes the adaptation of the SCP protocol to the IEEE 802.15.6 standard, which has been specially developed to optimize the WBAN performance at the physical and MAC layers.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898073]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898073]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898073&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898073]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>22</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Throughput and Energy Efficiency of Cooperative Diversity with Relay Selection]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Marchenko, Nikolaj;  Bettstetter, Christian;  Bettstetter, Christian]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cooperative systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Energy efficiency]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading channels]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Markov processes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Cooperative diversity is a communication technique where a relay node provides signal diversity to the destination by retransmitting the signal received from the source. To find an optimal relay and maximize the resulting performance, a relay selection procedure is used with channel state information as a selection metric. In this paper, we model cooperative diversity with relay selection as a Markov chain, and study the impact of selection timing on throughput and energy efficiency in Rayleigh fading channels. Based on obtained results, we determine optimal relay selection schemes for various network scenarios.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898016]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898016]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898016&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898016]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>23</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Challenges for Body Area Networks Concerning Radio Aspects]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Oliveira, Carla;  Ma?kowiak, Micha?;  Correia, Luis M.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Security]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Body Area Networks engage a network of sensors either wearable or implanted into the human body, with a wide range of promising applications in medicine (health care and patient monitoring), firemen/military forces outfits, advanced sports training, personal identification, navigation or multimedia entertainment, among others. This paper gives an insight into the challenges for applications of Body Area Networks, looking forward to energy efficiency and sustainability. A cross-layer perspective is proposed foreseeing effective and efficient systems, comprising cooperation and knowledge sharing between the various system layers (e. g., from antenna design and channel modelling to physical and media access control layers). Central topics are addressed and interrelated, like services and applications, security and privacy issues, interoperability, node and network architecture (e. g., cooperative/relay, distributed schemes), data rate and bandwidth, or energy management. The paper stresses the core position of the radio channel on the overall system, prompting the strong influence of the human body and discussing strategies to overcome connectivity problems (e. g., smart deployment of relays on the body).]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898051]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898051]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898051&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898051]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>24</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Efficient Training of Kalman Algorithm for MIMO Channel Tracking]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Eitel, Emna;  Speidel, Joachim]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Kalman filters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Training]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, a Kalman algorithm is applied to track a time-varying flat fading MIMO channel. The importance of training and appropriate initialization in combination with the Kalman tracking algorithm is shown. Adopting a periodical training scheme with a given bandwidth efficiency, a trade-off between investing pilots for good initialization and training the algorithm exclusively leads to the lowest BER. We also introduce a training on request scheme, in order to overcome the error propagation encountered by the Kalman filter after a series of detection errors. For this purpose, two metrics to detect the Kalman filter divergence are developed.We show the effectiveness of the new aperiodical training scheme in reducing the channel estimation error and saving bandwidth at the same time.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897973]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897973]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897973&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897973]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>25</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Competitive Spectrum Allocation in Heterogeneous Coverage Areas]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Khamit, Saltanat M.;  Zander, Jens]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Broadband communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Macrocell networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Pricing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quality of service]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensitivity]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[It could be costly to deploy a full coverage mobile broadband service with high bandwidth for a single operator. The development of low cost radio network equipment for short range coverage could trigger off a new scenario. Some providers may invest heavily to provide coverage in a wide area, while other providers would invest considerably less to provide coverage in a &#x0022;hotspot&#x0022; (small area). There exist two business models; in the first, the providers share their networks explicitly in a cooperative manner. In the second model, the providers compete with each other for users. This paper studies the competitive case, where providers have heterogeneous (partially overlapping) coverage. We analyse which service provisioning conditions are viable to the hotspot provider. The obtained results highlight the importance of infrastructure investments that characterized by degree of competition in the market. The system performance is also affected by the choice of sensitivity towards price and QoS. The results indicate that the hotspot provider could have a profit under given spectrum access mechanism and competition setting, which both would affect the level of the its profitability.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898030]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898030]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898030&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898030]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>26</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Wideband Characterization of Backscatter Channels]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Arnitz, Daniel;  Muehlmann, Ulrich;  Witrisal, Klaus]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Approximation methods]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Backscatter]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radiofrequency identification]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The wireless channel of backscatter radio systems is a two-way pinhole channel, created by the concatenation of two standard wireless channels. Pinhole channels cause higher attenuation and deeper fades than common wireless channels. Passive ultra-high frequency radio-frequency identification (UHF RFID) is such a backscatter radio system, with the backscattering tag acting as pinhole. While the effects of this type of channel are well-known in terms of fading statistics, the impact of the pinhole channel on wideband parameters is unknown. We present a method to calculate wideband backscatter channel parameters from the parameters of the constituent channels to and from the pinhole, with a focus on characteristics that are vital for narrowband and wideband ranging. The approximations are verified by simulations and by measurements in a UHF RFID warehouse portal.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898008]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898008]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898008&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898008]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>27</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Cooperative Extended Balanced Space-Time Block Coding with Relay Selection]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ek?im, Ali]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Block codes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Diversity methods]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Original proposal of cooperative extended balanced space-time block coding (CEBSTBC) and its special subsets like cooperative balanced space-time block coding (CBSTBC) utilize all available relays to guarantee full diversity and to maximize the coding gain when a few bits of feedback from the destination to the relays are available. Due to the construction technique of the CEBSTBC, one of the channel gains does not contribute the coding gain. In addition, since all relays transmit equal power, contribution of a minimum path gain does not yield high signal-to-noise ratio at the destination. To maximize received signal-tonoise ratio at the destination with a limited feedback, a novel transmit scheme for the CEBSTBC is proposed. This scheme transmits only N-1 out of N relays and a relay which maximize the received signal-to-noise ratio at the destination doubles its transmit power. The proposed scheme improves performance of the CEBSTBC and its subsets and outperforms path selection and relay selection schemes. Another advantage of the proposed scheme is allowing minimum decoding delay for the CEBSTBC and its subsets.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897998]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897998]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897998&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897998]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>28</rank>

<title><![CDATA[SINR Prediction Versus Reverse Reporting for Soft Reuse and Interference Management]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Cierny, Michal;  Ribeiro, Cassio;  Wichman, Risto;  Tirkkonen, Olav]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We investigate inter-cell interference management based on two methods: instantaneous signal-to-interference plus noise (SINR) prediction and reverse reporting. Reverse reporting, a concept where vulnerable receivers announce themselves, is a common approach. SINR prediction is an alternative solution which brings the decision responsibility to the receiver. This has a positive effect on the system performance as receiver has more crucial information at its disposal than the transmitter. The paper proposes a protocol with both SINR prediction and reverse reporting as interference management phases implemented by sounding the channel with orthogonal sequences, but focuses mainly on situations when only one of them is active. We simulate the two approaches in WINNER based indoor scenario and compare them in terms of spectral efficiency and user fairness. SINR prediction comes out superior as it achieves significantly higher spectral efficiency for the price of only small decrease in fairness.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898012]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898012]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898012&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898012]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>29</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Linear Interference Suppression in the Frequency Domain for DS-UWB Systems Using Biased RLS Estimation with Adaptive Shrinkage Factors]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Li, Sheng;  Lamare, Rodrigo C. de;  Haardt, Martin]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Equations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Frequency domain analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference suppression]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this work, biased algorithms with adaptive shrinkage factors are introduced to the interference suppression scenario. The proposed algorithms with linear receivers improve the performance of the conventional least squares (LS) solution in terms of mean-squared error (MSE), while requiring a very modest increase in complexity. An extension of the Cramér-Rao Lower Bound (CRLB) is computed in order to serve as a performance benchmark for the MSE performance of the biased algorithms. Simulations are carried out for a single-carrier frequency domain equalization (SC-FDE) of direct-sequence ultra-wideband (DS-UWB) systems, where the LS solution is recursively computed by using the recursive least-square (RLS) algorithm. The biased technique is then employed to improve the RLS estimator in terms of MSE. It is shown that the biased algorithms can accelerate the convergence rate and bring overall performance gain in the scenarios of low signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) and short data support.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898021]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898021]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898021&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898021]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>30</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Energy Efficiency Analysis of Two-Tier Heterogeneous Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Quek, Tony Q. S.;  Cheung, Wang Chi;  Kountouris, Marios]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Geometry]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Macrocell networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[With the exponential increase in data traffic driven by a new generation of wireless devices, data is expected to overwhelm cellular network capacity in the next few years. To address this issue, heterogeneous networks have recently being considered as a comprehensive approach to provide high cellular network capacity and coverage. However, the dense and random deployment of small cells and their uncoordinated operation raise important questions about the energy efficiency implications of multi-tier networks. In this paper, we analyze the energy efficiency of downlink two-tier heterogeneous networks, i.e. a network of macrocell base stations overlaid by randomly distributed picocell base stations, where each tier serves a disjoint set of users. Using tools from stochastic geometry, we first derive analytical expressions of success probabilities for each tier when a disjoint set of subchannels is employed. In addition, we evaluate the performance of two-tier networks in terms of energy efficiency and fairness of resource allocation. Numerical results confirm that there exists an optimal pico-macro density ratio that maximizes the overall energy efficiency of such a two-tier network. This work provides essential understanding for successful deployment of green heterogeneous networks.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898061]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898061]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898061&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898061]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>31</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Distributed Interference Alignment in Cellular Systems: Analysis and Algorithms]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Schreck, Jan;  Wunder, Gerhard]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Covariance matrix]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A fading environment is assumed and the degrees of freedom of a cellular system with an arbitrary number of base stations and users is determined. The base stations and users may have multiple antennas. Algorithms, which are based on alternating the optimization of the receive filters and transmit precoders, are proposed and shown to achieve the optimal degrees of freedom under certain conditions. Simulations sustain the analytic results and demonstrate the superior performance of the proposed algorithms.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898038]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898038]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898038&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898038]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>32</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Comparison of Hybrid Localization Schemes using RSSI, TOA, and TDOA]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Laaraiedh, Mohamed;  Yu, Lei;  Avrillon, Stephane;  Uguen, Bernard]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Accuracy]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Distance measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Global Positioning System]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Maximum likelihood estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Shadow mapping]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents a simulation study of nonhybrid and hybrid localization techniques using RSSI, TOA, and TDOA location dependent parameters. Maximum likelihood and weighted least squares are considered and developed for both non-hybrid and hybrid cases. Monte-Carlo simulations using realistic radio parameters extracted from an ultra wide band measurement campaign are carried out in order to assess the performances of different techniques and to show the importance of hybrid data fusion for localization.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898074]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898074]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898074&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898074]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>33</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Constant Envelope Modulation with Hammerich Transmit Filter]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Mueller, Benjamin;  Zoelzer, Udo]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Approximation methods]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Demodulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Equalizers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Shape]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We propose the Hammerich pulse as a transmit filter for minimum shift keying (HMSK). The spectral properties of HMSK are compared to Gaussian minimum shift keying (GMSK). Furthermore, simulation for coherent demodulation by means of the Laurent approximation and Wiener equalizer are performed in order to compare the bit error rate of both modulation schemes in the AWGN channel.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897991]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897991]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897991&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897991]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>34</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Two Stage Power Control in Multi-cell Wireless Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Stefanov, Stoycho;  Feistel, Angela;  Sta?czak, S?awomir;  Sta?czak, -]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Computer numerical control]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Power control]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this work we address the concept of a two stage power allocation in a multi-cell wireless network. The first stage is the outer-loop power control (OLPC), where a central network controller (CNC) operates on a larger timescale and allocates power budgets to base stations or access points. OLPC aims at controlling the inter-cell interference (ICI) in average. The individual bandwidth and power of each user are allocated on frame-level during the second stage of the resource allocation. We solve the OLPC-problem using a max-min SINR-balancing approach. Further, we introduce different strategies for reducing the feedback between BSs and the CNC and investigate the influence of the reduced feedback on the system outage performance.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898035]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898035]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898035&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898035]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>35</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Allocation of Optimum Sequences Based on Channel Conditions in DS-CDMA]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ambekar, Abhijit K.;  Schotten, Hans D.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Gain]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Gold]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multiaccess communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We consider the problem of allocating optimum sequences to users based on their channel conditions in a single-cell synchronous DS-CDMA system. We consider two cases. In the first case we allocate Walsh-Hadamard sequences to users when the number of users is less than or equal to the processing gain. In the second case we allocate Gold sequences to users when the number of users is greater than the processing gain. In both the cases we investigate the gain achieved by allocating sequences to users based on their channel conditions. We also investigate the effects of imperfect channel estimation on the performance of the system.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897987]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897987]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897987&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897987]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>36</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A full-duplex photonic RAU for RoF systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Urz?dowska, Anna;  Yashchyshyn, Yevhen]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Diode lasers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Microwave antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Microwave photonics]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optical fibers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Photodiodes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitting antennas]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The paper presents results of designing and investigation of photonic antenna for full-duplex wireless communication systems. Presented transmitting and receiving photonic antenna is integrated into single radiator which operate on two orthogonal polarizations. The transmitting photonic antenna is based on laser diode integrated with radiator since the receiving one is based on photodiode integrated with the same radiator but in place where polarization is orthogonal. The developed antenna has been studied as Remote Antenna Unit (RAU) for full-duplex Radio over Fiber (RoF) system. RoF technique enables distributing multiple wireless services in one system by using optical links to transmit signals between one central station and several remote RAU stations. The results show, e. g. that in the range from -10 dBm to 10 dBm of input microwave signal designed photonic RAU contributed relatively low damage to transmitting signal.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898023]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898023]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898023&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898023]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>37</rank>

<title><![CDATA[WSN Implementation of the Average Consensus Algorithm]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Kenyeres, Jozef;  Kenyeres, Jozef;  Kenyeres, Martin;  Rupp, Markus;  Farkas, Peter]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Algorithm design and analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Convergence]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Hardware]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal processing algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper is motivated by the lack of distributed algorithm implementations on wireless sensor networks (WSN) in hardware. We deal exemplary with the implementation of the well-known average consensus algorithm. By formulating the algorithm into nesC, a C derivative, it is possible to enrich the knowledge of the algorithm with practical information, specific to embedded devices such as nodes. We created a simple mechanism of a time scheduled access to share the wireless channel among the nodes and guarantee a collision free environment, in which our implementation is tested. Our achieved results are consistent with theory.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897985]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897985]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897985&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897985]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>38</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Iterative Bit Flip Type-II Hybrid-ARQ Scheme for Wireless Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Rehman, Obaid Ur;  Zivic, Natasa]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Automatic repeat request]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Forward error correction]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Iterative decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[WiMAX]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Hybrid-ARQ is used as a mechanism for error control and recovery in some of the most widely used wireless network protocols e. g., IEEE 802.16. HARQ employs forward error correction and requests retransmissions under adverse channel conditions. Many improvements over the standard HARQ have been proposed. Various studies have shown that the retransmissions themselves create a bottleneck in the throughput of the communication protocol. There is a need to lower the number of retransmissions under heavy noise so that the channel can be effectively utilized. There are some well known variants of the standard HARQ e.g., the so called Type-I and Type-II HARQs. In this paper, an enhancement over the standard Type-II HARQ scheme is proposed, whereby the number of retransmissions is reduced by recovering the erroneous packets at the receiver without the need for retransmissions. The proposed enhancement reduces the retransmissions, compared to the standard Type-II HARQ, at the same SNR. In case of a decoding failure, the received data packet is not discarded, rather processed further in an iterative manner using the side information available from the Turbo Decoder in the form of L-Values. The improvement in the bit and the packet error rates as well as the increase in the rate of successful packet transmission is visible from the simulation results presented in this paper.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898006]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898006]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898006&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898006]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>39</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Iterative Successive Interference Cancellation Based on Multiple Feedback For Multiuser MIMO Systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Li, Peng;  Lamare, Rodrigo C. de;  Fa, Rui]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Complexity theory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Detectors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Integrated circuits]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Silicon carbide]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, a new low-complexity multiple feedback successive interference cancellation (MF-SIC) strategy is proposed for the uplink of multiuser multiple-input multiple-output (MU-MIMO) systems. In the proposed MF-SIC with shadow area constraints (SAC) algorithm, an enhanced multiple user interference (MUI) cancellation is achieved by introducing the feedback diversity (FD) to combat the error propagation in decision feedback loops. We also combine the MF-SIC with multi-branch (MB) processing, which achieves a higher detection diversity. For coded systems, a low-complexity soft-input soft-output (SISO) iterative (turbo) detector is proposed based on the MF interference suppression and the soft canceler followed by a MMSE scheme (SC/MMSE). The computational complexity of the proposed MF-SIC is as low as the conventional SIC algorithm with very low additional complexity added. The simulation results show that the algorithm significantly outperforms the conventional SIC schemes and approaches the single user bound performance in coded systems.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897989]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897989]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897989&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897989]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>40</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Software Channel Simulator with Time Evolution of Parameters for the IMT-Advanced System]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bakowski, Krzysztof;  Wesolowski, Krzysztof]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Decision support systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A software implementation of an IMT-Advanced channel simulator is presented which was developed at Poznan University of Technology (PUT) within the EUREKA/CELTIC WINNER+ project. The simulator is based on the model specified by ITU-R for the evaluation of IMT-Advanced radio interface technologies. A simulation methodology for time evolution of the channel model parameters is presented as well.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898057]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898057]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898057&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898057]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>41</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Capacity bounds of spectrum sharing networks with no channel state information]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Makki, Behrooz;  Eriksson, Thomas]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel capacity]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cognitive radio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Recently, substantial attention has been paid to improve the spectral efficiency of communication setups using different spectrum sharing techniques. This paper aims to study the capacity of fading spectrum sharing channels in the case where there is no channel state information available at the transmitters and receivers. The channel capacity bounds are obtained under secondary user input power, different primary user received interference power and also primary user peak and average signal-to-interference-and-noise (SINR) constraints. Simulation results show that there is considerable potential for data transmission of unlicensed users even with no fading channels state information.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897971]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897971]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897971&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897971]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>42</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On the Capacity of the Underwater Acoustic Communication Channel under Realistic Assumptions]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Passerieux, Jean-Michel;  Socheleau, Francois-Xavier;  Laot, Christophe]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[AWGN]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel capacity]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Covariance matrix]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Doppler effect]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Peak to average power ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time frequency analysis]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The capacity of the underwater acoustic communication (UAC) channel is addressed under a comprehensive set of assumptions: time-varying multi-paths channel, modeled as a doubly-spread frequency-selective Ricean channel with known statistical properties, actual realization of the channel unkown to the transmitter and receiver, constraints on transmit power (averaged and/or peak) and available frequency bandwidth. The exact channel capacity under such general assumptions is still unknown. Therefore, upper and lower bounds of this capacity are given, and then numerically assessed and discussed for a few typical shallow water UAC channels. It is shown that, as long as the theoretical channel capacity is considered, transmission with spectral efficiency higher than often now (e. g. 2 to 3 bits/sec/Hz) appears as a reasonable objective in typical UAC channels, providing SNR about 15 to 20 dB. In other respects, for a given available averaged transmit power, large peak-to-averaged-power-ratio (PAPR) is also shown to be highly desirable, since it significantly reduces the capacity loss due to the channel uncertainty.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898071]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898071]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898071&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898071]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>43</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Pilot-Based Spectrum Sensing Approach Under Unknown Timing and Frequency Offset Environments]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Lu, Zhengwei;  Ma, Yi;  Tafazolli, Rahim]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Computational efficiency]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Detectors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Frequency domain analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time domain analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Timing]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A pilot-based spectrum sensing approach in the presence of unknown timing and frequency offset is proposed in this paper. Our major idea is to utilize the second order statistics of the received samples, such as autocorrelation, to avoid the frequency offset problem. Base on the property of the pilot symbols, where the different symbol blocks usually have the same pilot symbols, some nonzero terms will appear in the frequency domain. To test the proposed approach, computer simulations are carried out for the typical Orthogonal frequency-division multiplexing (OFDM) system. It is observed that the proposed approach always outperforms the classic time domain Neyman-Pearson approach at least 4dB. Moreover, the proposed approach get the same performance as the weighted linear combination based approach when the transmitted data block size is equal to 2048, while a small computational cost is keep at the same time. Therefore, it can be said that the proposed approach can achieve a good trade-off between reliability, latency and the computational cost, when the transmitted data block size of the primary system is larger than 1000.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898042]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898042]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898042&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898042]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>44</rank>

<title><![CDATA[How Far from Kronecker can a MIMO Channel be? Does it Matter?]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Shariati, Nafiseh;  Bengtsson, Mats]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Algorithm design and analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Covariance matrix]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Numerical models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A common assumption in the design and analysis of many MIMO transmission schemes is the so-called Kronecker model. This model is often a crucial step to obtain mathematically tractable solutions, but has also been criticized for being unrealistic. In this paper, we present a numerical approach to determine a channel whose statistics is as far from being Kronecker as possible, keeping only an assumption of spatial stationarity. As a case study for the relevance of the Kronecker assumption, a numerical analysis is included of the performance of optimal pilot design for Kronecker and non-Kronecker channels. The numerical results indicate that for this particular application, the Kronecker assumption may be used in the algorithm design and provide performance that is close to optimal also for non-Kronecker channels.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898034]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898034]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898034&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898034]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>45</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Cluster-Based Scatterer Identification and Characterization in Vehicular Channels]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bernado, Laura;  Roma, Anna;  Czink, Nicolai;  Paier, Alexander;  Zemen, Thomas]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Algorithm design and analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Clustering algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Doppler effect]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Noise]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Scattering]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we present a new approach for the identification of scattering objects in the delay and Doppler domain. Until now, the identification was done visually based on the power delay profile and video material recorded in the measurement campaigns. We propose to use automatic methods based on the local scattering function (LSF), which brings the Doppler domain into play. The LSF is a multitaper estimate of the two-dimensional (2D) power spectral density in delay and Doppler. Each peak of the LSF is composed of several multipath components (MPCs) coming from the same scattering object. Our approach consists of two steps: (i) detection of the relevant peaks, and (ii) assignment of MPCs to the scattering objects using a clustering algorithm. We use a modified a modified version of the density-based clustering of applications with noise algorithm, where we use the MPC distance. We apply the method to a set of vehicular radio channel measurements and extract the time-varying cluster parameters. The clusters have ellipsoidal shape with their longer axis in the Doppler domain. The first detected cluster presents different properties than the rest of the clusters, being larger, constant in time, and more static in the delay-Doppler plane. By properly identifying only the relevant scattering objects, vehicular channel models, such as the geometry-based stochastic channel model, can be simplified significantly.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898047]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898047]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898047&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898047]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>46</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Closed-form Approximation for the Trade-Off between Energy Efficiency and Spectral Efficiency in the Uplink of Cellular Network]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Onireti, Oluwakayode;  Heliot, Fabien;  Imran, Muhammad Ali]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Approximation methods]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Attenuation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Joints]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monte Carlo methods]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal processing]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we propose a tight closed-form approximation of the Energy Efficiency vs. Spectral Efficiency (EE-SE) trade-off for the uplink of a cellular communication system. We model the uplink of the cellular system by considering the Wyner model with Raleigh fading. We first demonstrate the accuracy of our expression by comparing it with Monte-Carlo simulation and the EE-SE trade-off expression based on lowpower approximation. Results show the great tightness of our expression with Monte-Carlo simulation. We utilize our closed-form for assessing the EE performance of base station (BS) cooperation against non-cooperative system for both a theoretical power model and a realistic power model. The theoretical power model includes only the transmit power, whereas the realistic power model incorporates the backhaul and signal processing powers in addition of the transmit power. Results indicate that BS cooperation is more energy efficient than non cooperative system and the former always outperforms the latter in terms of EE-SE trade-off. This is however no more the case with the realistic power model: the EE performance is then highly dependent on the number of cooperating BSs.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898052]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898052]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898052&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898052]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>47</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Autonomous Distributed Power Control Algorithms for Interference Mitigation in Multi-Antenna Cellular Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Kasparick, Martin;  Wunder, Gerhard]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Power control]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensitivity]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Interference mitigation has a great potential for improving the performance of current usually interference limited wireless networks. Since centralized &#x0022;full&#x0022; cooperation between base stations is still prohibitively complex, distributed schemes are of great interest. In this paper we compare three distributed algorithms for autonomous power control in 4G wireless networks and evaluate their applicability for different user mobility assumptions. The algorithms are based on network utility maximization, gradually and autonomously steering the network towards a higher utility. Besides different additional feedback and messaging requirements, the algorithms mainly differ in the granularity of power control, from controlling frequency subband power via controlling the power on a per-beam basis through to only enforcing average power constraints per beam. For comparison we use extensive system-level simulations indicating high gains compared to no power control. Moreover, it turns out that higher gains can be achieved by imposing average power constraints and allowing opportunistic scheduling instantaneously, rather than controlling the power in a strict way. Finally, we investigate the deviation from global optimality of the general framework by comparing to a Branch-And-Bound solution.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898027]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898027]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898027&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898027]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>48</rank>

<title><![CDATA[OFDM-PAPR Reduction using Coded Frequency Division Binary Mask]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Yoo, Hyunseuk;  Guilloud, Frederic;  Pyndiah, Ramesh]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Erbium]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Frequency division multiplexing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Indexes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Peak to average power ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Prototypes]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[While probabilistic OFDM-PAPR reduction techniques show a good PAPR reduction performance as a distortionless technique, three important problems should be taken into consideration: low complexity design to generate multiple candidates, protection of side information, and effective PAPR reduction regardless of the channel coding model. We present low complexity design using Frequency Division binary Mask (FDM). The FDM generates more candidates than the number of IFFT computations, which improve the PAPR reduction capability, and it protects the embedded side information by using powerful channel codes. Furthermore, while conventional label method is so dependent on the type of channel coding that non-recursive channel codes should be avoided for the effective PAPR reduction, our FDM method shows good performance for both error rate and PAPR reduction even when non-recursive channel codes are used.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897974]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897974]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897974&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897974]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>49</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On Circularity of Receiver Front-end Signals Under RF Impairments]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Anttila, Lauri;  Valkama, Mikko]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Modulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Phase noise]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radio transmitters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The circularity of receiver front-end signals is analyzed under various link impairments, including transmitter in-phase/quadrature-phase (I/Q) imbalance and local oscillator (LO) leakage, power amplifier nonlinearity, time-varying channel, carrier frequency offset, receiver phase noise, and DC offsets. Expressions are derived for the complementary autocorrelation functions of signals affected by these impairments. The circularity of the received waveform is shown to hold in the presence of transmitter I/Q imbalance and other impairments under certain realistic and non-restrictive conditions, while receiver I/Q imbalance makes the signal non-circular. These findings are important for receiver I/Q imbalance compensation, since many of these algorithms rely on the circularity of the received waveform, either explicitly or implicitly. Receiver DC offsets can potentially make the signal noncircular, but the effect is shown to be insignificant under realistic RF-to-LO isolation values. The results build confidence that low-complexity blind receiver I/Q imbalance compensation is applicable even in the presence of transmitter I/Q imbalances and other system impairments.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898031]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898031]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898031&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898031]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>50</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Optimized Filter Design in LTE Systems Using Nonlinear Optimization]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Schlechter, Thomas;  Lunglmayr, Michael]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Algorithm design and analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Approximation methods]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Band pass filters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Complexity theory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Finite impulse response filter]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal resolution]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[For mobile communication systems power efficiency is a very important issue. Especially for mobile user equipments (UE) a careful management and efficient use of the limited energy resources is mandatory. In fact, though, quite an amount of energy is wasted in todays UEs, as analog and digital frontend in communication systems are designed for worst case scenarios, meaning those are overengineered concerning e.g. amplifier linearity and filter slope steepnesses for most practical communication scenarios. Capturing the environmental transmission conditions and adapting the receiver architecture to the actual needs allows to save energy during the receiving process. We present a highly efficient approach for the implementation of such an architecture. This paper gives an overview on the basic properties of those approaches and discusses the constrained interior-point method for optimizing the filter design.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897995]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897995]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897995&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897995]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>51</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Joint Interference Suppression and Group-Based Power Allocation via Alternating Optimization for DS-CDMA Networks with Multihop Relaying]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Lamare, Rodrigo C. de]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Joints]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multiaccess communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This work presents joint interference suppression and power allocation algorithms for DS-CDMA networks with multiple hops and decode-and-forward (DF) protocols. A scheme for joint allocation of power levels across the relays subject to group-based power constraints and the design of linear receivers for interference suppression is proposed. A constrained minimum mean-squared error (MMSE) design for the receive filters and the power allocation vectors is devised along with an MMSE channel estimator. In order to solve the proposed optimization efficiently, a method to form an effective group of users and an alternating optimization strategy are devised with recursive alternating least squares (RALS) algorithms for estimating the parameters of the receiver, the power allocation and the channels. Simulations show that the proposed algorithms obtain significant gains in capacity and performance over existing schemes.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898009]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898009]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898009&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898009]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>52</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Dynamic Cooperative Positioning]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Raulefs, Ronald;  Zhang, Siwei;  Mensing, Christian;  Ghali, Cesar;  Hachem, Jad]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Distance measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Global Navigation Satellite Systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Manganese]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monte Carlo methods]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Noise]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Peer to peer computing]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The indoor environment is especially of interest for cooperative methods as indoors the density of potentially cooperating devices is much higher than outdoors. Outdoors where the omnipresent coverage of satellite based positioning is the key goal to use already existing infrastructure, like GPS. Indoor could also make use of outdoor positioned mobile nodes by using or exploiting peer-2-peer (P2P) connectivity. The P2P connectivity in indoors only supports also the ubiquitous indoor positioning experience itself. In this paper we investigate dynamic cooperative positioning.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898079]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898079]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898079&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898079]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>53</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Network Resources Pre-Reservation for Multimedia Content Delivery in Heterogeneous Wireless Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Al-Hezmi, Adel;  Corici, Marius;  Fiedler, Jens;  Magedanz, Thomas]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IP networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multimedia communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quality of service]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Streaming media]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Subscriptions]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The rapid progress being made recently in fixed and wireless access technologies that are envisioned to change the way we consume multimedia content show that the evolution of IP-based networks will be largely driven by multimedia service delivery requirements. The recent growth in the demand for IP-based streaming applications has challenged mobile operators on the management of the growth of traffic in their network. The delivery of several multimedia streaming applications composing live or store multimedia content such as public events or broadcast TV are transmitted according to pre-subscription. They occupy a high level of resources for which static congestion estimation mechanisms are not working. This paper introduces a novel solution for resource prediction of multimedia content delivery based on information gathered during the service subscription process in which users interested in certain multimedia service register (subscribe to) with the service provider for multimedia content delivery. This method represents an efficient use of pre-existing information, is easy to deploy and highly cost effective in comparison to traditional monitoring system employing dedicated traffic metering hardware.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897999]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897999]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897999&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897999]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>54</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Investigation on Cell Selection Methods Associated with Inter-cell Interference Coordination in Heterogeneous Networks for LTE-Advanced Downlink]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Sangiamwong, Jaturong;  Saito, Yuya;  Miki, Nobuhiko;  Abe, Tetsushi;  Nagata, Satoshi;  Okumura, Yukihiko]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Indexes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Macrocell networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Shadow mapping]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In LTE-Advanced, a heterogeneous network where femtocells and picocells overlaid onto macrocells is extensively discussed in addition to traditional well-planned macrocell deployment to improve further the system throughput. In heterogeneous network deployment, cell selection as well as intercell interference coordination (ICIC) is very important to improve the system and cell-edge throughput. Therefore, this paper investigates three cell selection methods associated with ICIC in heterogeneous networks in the LTE-Advanced downlink: signal-to-interference plus noise power ratio (SINR)-based cell selection, reference signal received power (RSRP)-based cell selection, and reference signal received quality (RSRQ)-based cell selection. Simulation results (4 pico eNodeBs and 25 set of user equipment are uniformly located within 1 macro eNodeB) assuming full buffer model show that the downlink cell and cell-edge user throughput levels of RSRP-based cell selection are degraded by approximately 3% and 10% compared to those of SINR-based cell selection under the condition of the maximizing the cell-edge user throughput due to the impairment of the interference level. Furthermore, it is shown that the downlink cell-edge user throughput of RSRQ-based cell selection is improved approximately 5%, although the cell throughput is degraded approximately 5% compared to that for SINR-based cell selection under the condition of the maximizing the cell-edge user throughput.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898043]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898043]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898043&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898043]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>55</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Improving RSS-Based Indoor Positioning Algorithm via K-Means Clustering]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Altintas, Bulut;  Serif, Tacha]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Clustering algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fingerprint recognition]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Heuristic algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Prediction algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal processing algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless LAN]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Advances in mobile technologies and devices has changed the way users interact with devices and other users. These new interaction methods and services are offered by the help of intelligent sensing capabilities, using context, location and motion sensors. However, indoor location sensing is mostly achieved by utilizing radio signal (Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, GSM etc.) and nearest neighbor identification. The most common algorithm adopted for Received Signal Strength (RSS)-based location sensing is K Nearest Neighbor (KNN), which calculates K nearest neighboring points to mobile users (MUs). Accordingly, in this paper, we aim to improve the KNN algorithm by enhancing the neighboring point selection by applying k-means clustering approach. In the proposed method, k-means clustering algorithm groups nearest neighbors according to their distance to mobile user. Then the closest group to the mobile user is used to calculate the MU's location. The evaluation results indicate that the performance of clustered KNN is closely tied to the number of clusters, number of neighbors to be clustered and the initiation of the center points in k-mean algorithm.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898019]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898019]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898019&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898019]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>56</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Transmit Impairments Influence on the Performance of MIMO Receivers and Precoders]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Gonzalez-Coma, Jose P.;  Castro, Paula M.;  Castedo, Luis]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Cost function]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Noise]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Symmetric matrices]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This work focuses on the impact of residual transmit impairments on the performance of Multiple-Input Multiple-Output (MIMO) systems with linear and non-linear receivers and precoders. We show that transmit noise significantly affects the performance of systems using precoding. Also, we show that non-linear MIMO receivers and precoders are more sensitive to transmit noise than their respective linear counterpart. Nevertheless, performance degradation can be noticeably alleviated if transmit noise is considered into filter optimization.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898013]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898013]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898013&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898013]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>57</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Towards full-diversity joint network-channel coding for large networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Duyck, Dieter;  Daniele Capirone, -;  Heindlmaier, Michael;  Moeneclaey, Marc]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel capacity]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cooperative systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Equations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Network coding and cooperative channel coding have both proved their importance for cooperative communications in wireless networks. It has been shown that it is beneficial to perform both techniques jointly. However, no diversity analysis for this framework has been made. Furthermore, the network codes in the state of the art have weak points from a coding point of view. This paper proposes a new general technique to construct network codes as an integral part of the channel code. The diversity order of this framework is analysed. Simulation of the word error rate performance of the new proposed joint network-channel code illustrates the benefit of joint network-channel coding.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898059]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898059]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898059&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898059]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>58</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Adaptive MMSE turbo equalization with high-order modulations and spatial diversity applied to underwater acoustic communications]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Laot, Christophe;  Bidan, Raphael Le]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bit rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Equalizers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Modulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sonar equipment]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents some results on adaptive minimum mean-square error (MMSE) turbo equalization obtained from underwater experiments in the Atlantic ocean. The performance gain is evaluated as a function of the number of hydrophones at the receiver side. Single-carrier transmission with high-order modulations is considered, at a coded bit rate as high as 24 kb/s on the underwater acoustic channel. The all-digital receiver performs timing recovery, equalization, interleaving and channel decoding.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898062]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898062]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898062&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898062]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>59</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Low-Cost Reliable Blackout Sustainability of Wireless Sensor Networks with Energy Harvesting Systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Glatz, Philipp M.;  Hoermann, Leander B.;  Steger, Christian;  Weiss, Reinhold]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Current measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Global Positioning System]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Hardware]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Photovoltaic cells]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Robustness]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Voltage measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Wireless sensor network (WSN) motes are typically small and networked embedded systems. They are of limited computational power and suffer severe resource constraints - especially energy is scarce. With the advent of energy harvesting system (EHS) technology new opportunities open up for long-lived WSNs. Several prototypes of EHS-enhanced WSN platforms have recently been designed in a low-power and energy-efficient way. However, while the field starts to mature there are still a few lessons to be learned for building low-cost and robust systems. While the term low-cost may easily be defined by means of calculating what hardware and maintenance cost per end-user performance for a given business model, it is more complicated to define what is meant by the term robust. For perpetual systems one has to find a formal way of validating whether a system implementation - including all low power hardware and networking approaches - can sustain a given quality of service despite harsh environmental conditions or faulty operation. For the presented case study with the RiverMote hardware platform, we model its black-out sustainability (BOS). We can validate that with its robust low-power design and BOS of more than three weeks can be achieved. Perpetual operation with error detection, fall-back mechanisms, error reporting and self-healing of the system is possible. The system relies on more easy-to-validate system-level mechanisms than other approaches that concentrate on energy harvesting device pattern prediction and therefore have to assume robust forecasting of environmental conditions.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898040]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898040]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898040&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898040]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>60</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Unavoidable Cycles in Polynomial-Based Time-Invariant LDPC Convolutional Codes]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Zhou, Hua;  Goertz, Norbert]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Block codes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Convolutional codes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Parity check codes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Polynomials]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Low-Density Parity-Check convolutional codes (LDPCccs) are very interesting for practical error-correction coding in wireless transmission as they have excellent performance and at the same time they allow for variable block size with low complexity encoding and decoding. As for all LDPC codes that are decoded by the sub-optimal (but highly efficient) Sum Product Algorithm, the cycles in the code graph are very important for the practical performance of the coding scheme. Time-invariant LDPCccs can be defined by a polynomial syndrome former (transposed parity-check matrix in polynomial form), that can be derived from corresponding Quasi-Cyclic (QC) LDPC block codes. Given the polynomial syndrome former with certain structures, unavoidable cycles with lengths ranging from 6 to 12 will be shown to exist.We provide some rules for designing good codes with respect to the shortest cycle in the code-graph, the girth of the code, which is a crucial parameter for its decoding performance.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898001]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898001]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898001&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898001]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>61</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Expanding LTE for Devices: Requirements, Deployment Phases and Target Scenarios]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Lioumpas, A.;  Alexiou, A.;  Anton-Haro, C.;  Navaratnam, P.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Humans]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Medical services]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Navigation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Surveillance]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Traffic control]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The vast majority of wireless traffic is expected to be dominated by machines and/or devices before the end of this decade. However, wireless communication networks have been designed mainly with human users in mind. Whilst scale and type of M2M (machine-to-machine) applications are growing rapidly over today's cellular networks, they are still defined following mainly human-to-human communication requirements. To meet the requirements of M2M applications, a new kind of network is needed to serve efficiently a huge number of devices which may have rather modest communications needs. In this paper we address the requirements, challenges, and taxonomy criteria for M2M applications and use cases. Three typical target scenarios are proposed, namely traffic control with smart navigation, smart metering and monitoring, and e-healthcare, which are expected to be the basis for the technical specifications of the extension of LTE system concept for M2M communications. The requirements and challenges identified for these scenarios could serve as the common starting platform for further and detailed investigations of the technical assumptions.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898075]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898075]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898075&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898075]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>62</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Delay-Aware NUM System for Wireless Multi-Hop Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Szwabe, Andrzej;  Misiorek, Pawel;  Walkowiak, Przemyslaw]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Spread spectrum communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In order to design an effective utility-aware optimization framework for wireless multi-hop networks, it is necessary to explicitly incorporate the delay factor into the Network Utility Maximization (NUM) model. It is especially important in the case of multi-service networks aimed at serving both the file transfer and streaming media traffic. In this paper, we present a novel delay-aware NUM framework for wireless multi-hop networks. The application-layer system that has been derived from this framework consists of a delay-aware indirect flow control mechanism based on a system transporting virtual utility units and a packet forwarding component aimed at providing an approximation of Max-Weight Scheduling (MWS). To the best of the authors¿ knowledge the proposed solution is the first delay-aware NUM system interoperable with widely used protocols of the most typical wireless networking stack, such as TCP, UDP, IP, and 802.11 MAC.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897992]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897992]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897992&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897992]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>63</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Multicast Routing in Wireless Sensor Networks with Incomplete Information]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Tisza, David;  Peter Vizi, -;  Levendovszky, Janos;  Olah, Andras]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Approximation methods]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Artificial neural networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Steiner trees]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we develop a set of heuristic algorithms for the solution of the Quality of Service (QoS) constrained multicast routing problem with incomplete information in Wireless Sensor Networks (WSN). The QoS constrained multicast routing has already been analyzed and proven to be NP-complete with deterministic link measures. In this paper we investigate this problem in the case of incomplete information when, in aWireless Sensor Network due to information aggregation or randomly fluctuating traffic loads, link measures are considered to be random variables. We develop novel routing algorithms based on these random link metrics. The objective is to choose a tree which fulfills a given QoS criterion (e.g. delay) with maximum probability. We propose a set of algorithms based on Hopfield Neural Networks to solve the QoS constrained multicast routing problem with incomplete information. In this way, a fast tree selection becomes possible.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898036]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898036]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898036&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898036]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>64</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Low-Complexity Dynamic Pilot Allocation for Channel Estimation in MIMO-OFDM Systems with Spatial Multiplexing]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Li, Li (Alex);  Lamare, Rodrigo C. de;  Burr, Alister G.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Noise]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receiving antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitting antennas]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Dynamic pilot allocation for Discrete Fourier Transform (DFT)-based channel estimation in MIMO-OFDM system with spatial multiplexing has been shown to significantly improved symbol error rate (SER) performance compared to fixed pilot allocation. However the exhaustive search for optimum allocation leads to very high complexity. In this paper, we investigate a MIMO iterative pilot search (MIPS) algorithm applied with different MIMO-OFDM receivers (ZF-linear, ZF-SIC, MMSE-linear, MMSE-SIC), which significantly reduces the complexity of the search for optimum pilot patterns, and makes the dynamic algorithm more feasible for practically useful number of subcarriers and antennas. Furthermore, the mathematical derivations of the optimum pilot search are discussed briefly including the derivation of the signal to interference plus noise ratio (SINR) in the presence of channel estimation errors and approximations of error probabilities. The effectiveness of the new techniques is demonstrated by simulation of a MIMO-OFDM system. The SER performances of the algorithm based on MIPS are almost the same as the exhaustive search.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898004]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898004]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898004&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898004]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>65</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Duplexer-less RF Front-end for LTE Pico-Cell using a Dual Polarization Antenna]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bories, S.;  Dussopt, L.;  Giry, A.;  Delaveaud, C.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Computer architecture]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Energy efficiency]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Impedance]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Insertion loss]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[3]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This study aims at a global optimization of the Tx front-end with a focus on the opportunities offered at the antenna level to reduce the constraint on other components. More specifically, it deals with the improvement of the energy efficiency (EE) of the front-end in classical FDD architectures for LTE small cell applications. The key idea consists in eliminating the duplexer by using a dual polarization antenna which ensures a 30 dB isolation between Tx and Rx accesses. To reach the classical 50 dB Tx/Rx isolation level, additional filters with relaxed constraints are used. A detailled comparison between standard and proposed front-ends may provide a significant loss reduction of 1 to 3 dB on the Tx chain.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898082]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898082]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898082&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898082]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>66</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On interference management for uncoordinated LTE-Femto cell deployments]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Doppler, Klaus;  Moisio, Martti;  Valkealahti, Kimmo]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Buildings]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cost function]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Synchronization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we investigate interference management techniques for uncoordinated and dense residential LTE-Femto cell deployments implementing LTE Release-10 with closed subscriber group configuration. In particular we outline the possible interference management techniques defined in the standard. We present a distributed and centralized interference management strategy operating in the frequency domain. We evaluate the presented strategies for a dense deployment with closed subscriber groups and a scenario where multiple operators share the same band. Our results show that the distributed scheme performs similar to the centralized scheme and that both schemes outperform reuse one.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897983]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897983]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897983&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897983]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>67</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Message Fragmentation for Disrupted Links]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ginzboorg, Philip;  Niemi, Valtteri;  Ott, Joerg]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IP networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Linear approximation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quantization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Random variables]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[10]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In networks with unstable links the connection between the sender and the receiver may be cut before the entire message has been transmitted. Quantization of the message into blocks before its transmission, enables message fragments consisting of one or more such blocks to be transmitted successfully, even if the connection time is too short for transmitting the entire message. But fragmentation may also reduce the chances of delivering the entire message to its destination, due to lost or misrouted fragments. In this paper we (1) formulate the problem of in-time transmission of fragmented messages in disrupted networks; and (2) develop methods to analytically estimate the mean transmission time of fragmented message within a basic system model for the case of transmission over a single disrupted link.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898055]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898055]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898055&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898055]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>68</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Anytime Source Transmission using UEP-LT Channel Coding]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Shirazinia, Amirpasha;  Bao, Lei;  Skoglund, Mikael]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Algorithm design and analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we study the design of a causal anytime encoding and decoding scheme for transmission of real-time information over a binary symmetric channel. In particular, our scheme combines unequal-error protection (UEP) rateless codes with sequential belief propagation decoding. In order to minimize delay in decoding and reduce distortion, we formulate and solve a linear programming problem. Moreover, degree distributions of the UEP-rateless codes are optimized since the efficiency of rateless codes highly depends on the corresponding degree distribution. The performance of the proposed scheme is demonstrated by using numerical simulations, and will be compared with an existing work.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898049]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898049]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898049&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898049]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>69</rank>

<title><![CDATA[WSN Coverage &amp; Connectivity Improvement Utilizing Sensors Mobility]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Mateska, Aleksandra;  Gavrilovska, Liljana]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Algorithm design and analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Clustering algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Intelligent sensors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network topology]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Topology]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Mobility in Wireless Sensor Networks may significantly affect the network performance. This paper proposes distributed algorithm that improves the network coverage and connectivity, performing controlled reorganization of mobile sensor nodes (C2 algorithm). The algorithm initially organizes the network in a clustered topology, assuming hexagonal grid structure. The Cluster Heads are positioned in the centres of hexagonal cells designed according the nodes transmission range. The C2 reorganizes the sensor nodes between the adjacent hexagonal cells and equally distributes them within the cells, thus improving the network coverage and providing more uniform energy utilization. The algorithm chooses the optimal nodes to perform the movements, maintaining the connectivity between the sensor nodes and minimizing the energy that the nodes consume for their movement. The simulation results show the benefits of the proposed algorithm implementation for coverage and connectivity improvement in a homogeneous WSN.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898029]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898029]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898029&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898029]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>70</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Resource Sharing in Relay-enhanced 4G Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bou Saleh, Abdallah;  Bulakci, Omer;  Ren, Zhe;  Redana, Simone;  Raaf, Bernhard;  Haemaelaeinen, Jyri]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Decision support systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[XML]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Type 1 inband relay nodes and time-division transmit and receive advanced relay stations are to be supported by 3GPP LTE-Advanced and IEEE 802.16m, respectively. Both classifications support a similar relaying mode where the relay link transmission is time- division multiplexed with the access link transmission, whereas macro users share the same resources with the relays. Hence, system performance depends strongly on the resource partitioning strategy among and within the links as well as how well the competition on resources is managed at the donor eNB. In this paper, we present performance evaluation of different schemes for resource sharing among relay nodes and prioritization techniques of relay users on the relay link coupled with the corresponding scheduling on the access link. In particular, we propose a combination of resource sharing based on the number of relay users and relay link prioritization and scheduling of relay users achieving max-min fairness. A comprehensive system-level simulation campaign is carried out in 3GPP urban and suburban models considering 4 and 10 relays per cell. Results show that the proposed scheme achieves high system fairness and significant throughput gains at the low and mid throughput regime at no or negligible loss in cell throughput.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897986]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897986]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897986&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897986]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>71</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Energy Efficient Supply of WSN Nodes using Component-Aware Dynamic Voltage Scaling]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Hoermann, Leander B.;  Glatz, Philipp M.;  Steger, Christian;  Weiss, Reinhold]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Batteries]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Equations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Microcontrollers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Power demand]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Voltage control]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Energy efficiency is very important for wireless sensor networks (WSNs), because the consumable energy is limited. Each WSN node has its own power supply. The lifetime of the WSN node depends basically on its average power consumption. Therefore, an efficient supply of the WSN node can enhance the lifetime of it. Typically, the various components of a WSN node (microcontroller, transceiver, sensors) have different supply voltage ranges. To save as much energy as possible, the supply voltage of the node should be as low as possible. Therefore, a voltage converter is needed to reduce the voltage of a battery. The minimum allowed supply voltage depends on the components that are active. The active components and consequently the minimum allowed supply voltage vary over time. Componentaware dynamic voltage scaling (CADVS) can be used to adapt the supply voltage of the node. This work presents the possible energy savings using four different voltage conversion techniques. It has been shown that CADVS can be used to save up to 31.5% of the energy compared to a constant voltage supply using the introduced scenario while achieving the same end-user performance.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898007]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898007]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898007&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898007]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>72</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Coherent Detection of Physical Network Coding in the Presence of Phase Offsets]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Marchand, Philippe;  Yongacoglu, Abbas]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Coherence]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Constellation diagram]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Phase shift keying]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Physical-Layer Network Coding (PNC) has the potential to greatly increase the throughput of wireless networks. When BPSK signals are transmitted by the sources, employing coherent detection at the relay poses no difficulty. However, when QPSK is used, the performance strongly depends on the phase difference between the carrier phases of the two sources. For a range of phase offset values, the performance of QPSK can be unacceptably poor. To overcome this phase misalignment problem, we propose to use Offset-QPSK at the sources and maximum-likelihood sequence detection by the receivers. The resulting spread in bit error rate performance for a range of phase offset PNC signals is less than 2dB at moderate SNR for transmissions at a rate of 2 bits/symbol. Our results confirm that the proposed solution is able to resolve the problems incurred by phase asynchrony.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897990]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897990]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897990&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897990]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>73</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Upper Bound to Interference Coordination with Channel State Information Outdating]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Brunner, Hans H.;  Ivrlac, Michel T.;  Nossek, Josef A.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Array signal processing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference channels]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Noise measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Upper bound]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We consider the network sum rate maximization in the downlink of a cellular system based on the spatial channel model of the 3GPP MIMO urban macro cell with multiple antenna base stations and single antenna mobile devices. We formulate an upper bound to the kind of cooperation, where each mobile device is served by only one base station, but base stations try to control the interference they produce. The benefits of higher possible data rates through interference mitigation are traded-off against a minimum overhead needed for realizing the required cooperation. The outdating of the channel state information is used to calculate an upper bound to the efficiency of the system. We show, that an increase in cooperation above a boundary does not lead to an increase in possible data rates.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897981]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897981]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897981&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897981]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>74</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On the Autocorrelation Ergodic Properties of Sum-of-Cisoids Rayleigh Fading Channel Simulators]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Gutierrez, Carlos A.;  Melendez, Anely;  Sandoval, Arturo;  Rodriguez, Hermes]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Analytical models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Random processes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Stochastic processes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[System-on-a-chip]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we analyze the autocorrelation properties of seven fundamental classes of stochastic sum-of-cisoids (SOC) simulation models for narrowband mobile Rayleigh fading channels. The purpose of this analysis is to determine which classes of SOC models are autocorrelation ergodic (AE), i. e., for which classes of simulation models the time autocorrelation function (TACF) equals the autocorrelation function (ACF) of the ensemble. This information is of practical relevance, since an AE channel simulator allows to accurately emulate the channel's ACF in a single realization, making it possible to bypass the time-consuming computation of the ensemble average. The obtained results conclusively demonstrate that only the class of SOC models defined by cisoids with constant gains, constant frequencies, and random phases possesses the desired AE property. The findings presented in this paper can be used as guidelines for the design of efficient SOC channel simulators that generate Rayleigh fading waveforms with specified autocorrelation properties in each simulation run.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898058]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898058]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898058&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898058]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>75</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Interference management using one bit feedback]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Makki, Behrooz;  Eriksson, Thomas]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Cognitive radio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Data communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper studies the performance of quasi-static spectrum sharing networks utilizing one bit interference indicator feedback. Assuming no channel state information at the transmitters, the channel average rate is obtained under different power allocation strategies. Simulation results show that interference indicator feedback leads to considerable rate increment even with no transmitter channel state information.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897972]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897972]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897972&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897972]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>76</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Multi-Interface DTN-like Communication System]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Jaervinen, Risto;  Maeaettae, Juho;  Luostarinen, Riku;  Liuhto, Lauri;  Manner, Jukka;  Taira, Taneli;  Luoma, Marko]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Graphical user interfaces]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IP networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Microwave integrated circuits]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network interfaces]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Software]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The networking industry is quickly adopting IP as the technology to run all the communication applications people need. Yet, there exists a lot of use cases and deployments, where end-to-end IP is not available. This is the domain Delay Tolerant Networking (DTN) is targeting. The Multi Interface Communications Software (MICS) is a robust DTN-like messaging platform for heterogeneous communications equipment. MICS can provide message delivery in networks that lack essentials required by traditional TCP/IP-solutions, like end-to-end connectivity or compatible addressing methods. MICS abstracts the used communications medium, that is the network and link layer, from applications. Applications and network interfaces connect to MICS core using well known and standardized APIs. Familiar email addresses and APIs are used to interface applications with the MICS system. The high-level operation of MICS resembles DTN since we make use of store-and-forward message delivery and multipath message routing together with flooding. This paper concentrates on the overall concept of the MICS system, software architecture, IPC methods, details design choices, message routing and discusses real world deployment scenarios.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898072]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898072]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898072&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898072]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>77</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Alamouti based Cooperative Communications with a Relay Node using Network Coding: A Diversity-Multiplexing Tradeoff Perspective]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Menghwar, Gordhan Das]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Diversity methods]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multiplexing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we study the diversity-multiplexing tradeoff perspective of our proposed scheme called cooperative communication using Alamouti scheme with network coding. In this scheme, two cooperating users based on Alamouti scheme are aided by a single relay node. This relay node is used to forward network coded bits, of the information received from the cooperating users to the destination. The derived results on diversity-multiplexing tradeoff indicate that the proposed scheme offers higher diversity gain than the cooperative communication using Alamouti scheme only. The compromise made in terms of multiplexing gain is also derived and discussed.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898046]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898046]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898046&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898046]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>78</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Mutual Coupling Evaluation of Dual-Miniaturized PIFA Antenna Array for MIMO Terminals]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Al-Nuaimi, Mustafa K. Taher]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antenna arrays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Arrays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mutual coupling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Because of rapidly increasing demand for high capacity communication services, compact antennas have become center of research interest nowadays and this reduction of size becomes much more important especially when we want to use the Multiple-Input Multiple-Output (MIMO) technology to increase channel capacity, in modern compact devices. In this paper, a design of dual-elements compact Planar Inverted-F Antenna (PIFA) array for handheld MIMO terminal on a ground plane of size 100 mm x 50 mm x 0.8 mm which is compatible with modern stick type mobile phones is presented. PIFA miniaturization techniques is based on the incorporating of meander structure in the main antenna body in order to increase the path of the eclectic current and hence reduce the operating frequency of the PIFA. Overall size is compact than small MIMO antennas available in the literature. The mutual coupling, which is the main factor effects the channel matrix and MIMO system capacity, is investigated in detail for various placements (both position and orientation). The optimal position and orientation for the PIFA antennas inside the MIMO terminal with low mutual coupling which leads to good diversity performance is addressed. Computer aided design (CAD) was carried out by using the Computer Simulation Technology (CST) Microwave Studio package, which utilizes the finite integral technique (FIT) for electromagnetic computation.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897977]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897977]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897977&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897977]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>79</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Demodulation of Underwater OFDM Transmissions by Time Reversal and Basis Pursuit Methods]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Gomes, Joao;  Berger, Christian R.;  Silva, Antonio]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Arrays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Convolution]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Probes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[9]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we discuss a channel shortening approach based on passive time reversal (PTR) for underwater acoustic communication using OFDM. PTR exploits the physics of acoustic propagation to mitigate intersymbol interference in a simple and robust way, reducing the need for long OFDM symbols and prefixes. We adopt recent basis pursuit methods for identification of sparse responses from PTR channel probes. This effectively discards unstable or insignificant estimated channel coefficients, improving the performance relative to PTR with directly observed channel responses. We present results for data collected during the CALCOM¿10 sea trial with 4.5 kHz bandwidth, 4.1-6.4 kbit/s raw data rates (2-3.2 kbit/s before convolutional coding), and 3 km communication range. Channel responses are sparse, with delay spreads of 20-30 ms that PTR reduces to 5-10 ms. Subsequent OFDM demodulation attains good results in much of the signal bandwidth, although some seemingly source-related issues remain that lead to overall higher error rates than using plain OFDM with multichannel combining.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898078]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898078]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898078&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898078]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>80</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On the Capacity of the 2-user Gaussian MAC Interfering with a P2P Link]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Chaaban, Anas;  Sezgin, Aydin]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Integrated circuits]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Noise measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Upper bound]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A multiple access channel and a point-to-point channel sharing the same medium for communications are considered. We obtain an outer bound for the capacity region of this setup, and we show that this outer bound is achievable in some cases. These cases are mainly when interference is strong or very strong. In the low interference regime, a simple strategy using Gaussian codes and treating interference as noise is considered. An upper bound on the sum capacity is derived and shown to be tight (but not coinciding) with the sum-rate achievable using this scheme.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897976]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897976]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897976&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897976]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>81</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Network Coded Rate Scheduling for Two-way Relay Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Kim, Dong Min;  Kim, Seong-Lyun]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Minimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Network coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimal scheduling]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We investigate a scheduling scheme incorporating network coding and channel varying information for the twoway relay networks. Our scheduler aims at minimizing the time span needed to send all the data of each source of the network. We consider three channel models, time invariant channels, time varying channels with finite states and time varying Rayleigh fading channels. We formulate the problem into a manageable optimization problem, and get a closed form scheduler under time invariant channels and time varying channel with finite channel states. For Rayleigh fading channels, we focus on the relay node operation and propose heuristic power allocation algorithm resemblant to water filling algorithm. By simulations, we find that even if the channel fluctuates randomly, the average time span is minimized when the relay node transmits/schedules network coded data as much as possible.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898026]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898026]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898026&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898026]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>82</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Three-Dimensional Localization Algorithm for Wireless Sensor Networks Based on the BFGS Optimization]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Chai, -;  Dong, Enqing]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Accuracy]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Ad hoc networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Algorithm design and analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Conferences]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Distance measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless sensor networks]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A three-dimensional localization algorithm for wireless sensor networks based on the BFGS (Broyden, Fletcher, Goldfarb, Shanno) optimization is proposed. By defining an objective function for three-dimensional localization, the localization work is transformed into an unconstrained optimization problem. The BFGS algorithm, which is a classical algorithm for the unconstrained optimization problem, is adopted for localization for wireless sensor networks, and avoids the inverse matrix calculation in the least square algorithm. The effects of the amount and the distribution of the beacon nodes are analyzed, and the experimental results show that the localization accuracy under the marginal distribution of the beacon nodes is better than the one under the random distribution of the beacon nodes. The final simulation results indicate that the BFGS algorithm has a higher accuracy and less calculation, and is less affected by the non-line-of-sight error than the least square algorithm.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897994]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897994]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897994&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897994]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>83</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Cognitive Radio Spectrum E volution Prediction using A rtificial Neural Networks based Multivariate T ime Series Modelling]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Taj, M. I.;  Akil, M.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Artificial neural networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Neurons]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Prediction algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Predictive models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radio frequency]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time series analysis]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Cognitive Radio (CR) is an efficient answer to spectrum scarcity as it can sense the spectrum steadily based on previous information about the spectrum evolution in time, thus predicting the future occupancy status. Framed within this statement, this paper proposes a new methodology for spectrum prediction by modelling licensed signal Radio F requency (RF) features as a multivariate chaotic time series, which is then given as input to Artificial Neural Network (ANN), that predicts the evolution of RF time series to decide if the unlicensed user can exploit the spectrum band. We exploit the inherent cyclostationarity in primary signals for Non-linear Autoregressive Exogenous T ime Series Modelling of RF features, which is an extremely challenging task due to interdependence of different R F features. Experimental results show a similar trend between predicted and observed values. We target this work at cognition incorporation in our designed Software Defined Radio (SDR) waveform.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898018]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898018]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898018&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898018]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>84</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A MAC Protocol for Body Area Networks using Out-of-Band Radio]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ameen, Moshaddique Al;  Ullah, Niamat;  Chowdhury, M. Sanaullah;  Kwak, Kyungsup]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Biomedical monitoring]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Energy consumption]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Media Access Protocol]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Time division multiple access]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transceivers]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Applications of wearable and implanted wireless sensor devices are hot research area. A specialized field called the Body Area Networks (BAN) has emerged to support this area. Energy consumption and delay are major concern for Medium Access Control (MAC) protocols in a BAN. Low cost wake up radio module attached with sensor devices can help to reduce energy consumption and prolong the network lifetime by reducing idle state energy consumption and increasing sleep time of a BAN node. In this paper, we propose a new MAC protocol for body area network using an out-of-band wake up radio. We have used an on-demand scheduling procedure for communication through a centralized and coordinated external wake up mechanism. We compared our method with some existing MAC protocols and is found to outperform them in terms of energy consumption and delay. Use of wake up radio improved the overall performance of the proposed on-demand MAC.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897997]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897997]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897997&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897997]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>85</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Lattice Reduction-Aided Preprocessing and Detection Techniques for MU-MIMO in Broadcast Channel]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Zu, Keke;  Lamare, Rodrigo C. de]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bit error rate]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Complexity theory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Detectors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Lattices]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Block diagonalization (BD) is one of the most effective preprocessing techniques for multiuser multi-input multi-output (MU-MIMO) systems. By using BD the MU-MIMO broadcast channel can be decomposed into multiple parallel independent SU-MIMO channels through two singular value decomposition (SVD) operations. Complex lattice reduction (CLR) is another technique that aims to enforce orthogonality between the columns of the channel matrix and reduce its size as well. In this paper, only the first SVD is adopted to obtain parallel SU-MIMO channels with zero interference, the orthogonalization and size-reduction work are left for the CLR algorithm so that a modification of the channel matrix is carried out, resulting in a better precoding and detection performances. Simulation results show that the proposed algorithm greatly outperforms conventional BD detection and linear precoding techniques.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898003]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898003]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898003&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898003]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>86</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Utility-based Decision-making for Symbiotic Cooperative Relaying in Cognitive Radio Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Thumar, Vinay;  Nadkar, Taskeen;  Desai, U. B.;  Merchant, S. N.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Cognitive radio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cooperative systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decision making]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quality of service]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[A recent paradigm in the research surrounding Cognitive Radio (CR), is a Symbiotic Cooperative Relaying architecture, which improves the efficiency of spectrum usage and reliability of the transmission links. The incumbent Primary User (PU) of the spectrum, with a weak transmission link, seeks cooperation from the cognitive Secondary User (SU) nodes in its vicinity, and in return rewards them with a fraction of time for their own communication, as an incentive time. The utility functions for both the entities of the CR network, i. e. the PU and SU, are formulated with two important considerations: the PU is the priority user and has a soft rate demand to be satisfied; and the SU's net utility involves a cost for relaying the PU¿s traffic. Maximizing the utilities of the PU and SU are conflicting objectives. After intensive analysis of the equilibrium point, we use a utility-based decision-making process to allocate that fraction of time to the PU and SU, which achieves optimum user satisfaction for both.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898039]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898039]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898039&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898039]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>87</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Low Complexity Selection Cooperation Techniques Using Information Accumulation in Dual-Hop Relaying Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Nikjah, Reza;  Beaulieu, Norman C.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Approximation methods]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Strontium]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Three low complexity, single-parameter, selection cooperation protocols, called P-n, P-gamma, and P-t, are introduced for dual-hop relaying networks. The protocols are based on information accumulation, and can potentially be implemented using rateless codes. The protocols have low complexity in terms of the relatively small number of signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) measurements, not requiring global channel gain information, not involving simultaneous multiple transmissions, and using a single design parameter. The expected transmission time for the three protocols is analyzed for block fading channels. As a baseline for performance comparison, a rate optimal protocol, called P-o, is proposed. In the single-relay case, all the protocols, if used with their optimized parameter, coincide with P-o. Large SNR approximations to the optimal parameters, which have good accuracy in large SNR regimes, and satisfactory accuracy for smaller values of SNR, are obtained. The dependence of the optimal parameters on the network parameters is numerically studied for Rayleigh fading. The average rate performances of the schemes are compared with other comparable previous relaying schemes through numerical examples. It is observed that the suboptimal schemes exhibit near-optimal rate performances.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898064]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898064]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898064&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898064]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>88</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Ghost Femtocells: an Energy-Efficient Radio Resource Management Scheme for Two-Tier Cellular Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Domenico, Antonio De;  Domenico, Antonio De;  Strinati, Emilio Calvanese;  Duda, Andrzej]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Copper]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Femtocells]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Macrocell networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quality of service]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The femtocell deployment in 3GPP/LTE sets new challenges to energy efficiency and Radio Resource Management (RRM). Traditional schemes are mainly designed for classical cellular networks while the ad hoc nature of femtocells notably limits the complexity of possible algorithms. Thus, efficient RRM schemes are essential for limiting the interference impact on end-user performance. The goal of this paper is to achieve effective spectral reuse between neighbour cells and reduce the femtocell downlink power consumption while guaranteeing the QoS of users served by both macro and femto base stations. We discuss the effectiveness of two resource management schemes that limit the overall interference per Resource Block (RB) generated outside the coverage range of a femtocell while reducing the transmission power in each RB. Our simulation results show that the proposed RRM schemes enhance the energy efficiency of the overall cellular network while improving both macrocell and femtocell throughput.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898081]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898081]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898081&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898081]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>89</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Location Assisted Handover Optimization for Heterogeneous Wireless Networks]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Nielsen, Jimmy Jessen;  Madsen, Tatiana K.;  Schwefel, Hans-Peter;  Schwefel, Hans-Peter]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Heuristic algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[IEEE 802.11 Standards]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Land mobile radio cellular systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Prediction algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Mobile users typically experience better connectivity if their mobile device performs handover to an available WiFi network rather than using a cellular network. For a moving user the window of opportunity is limited and the timing of the handover is therefore crucial. In this work we propose two location-based look-ahead handover prediction algorithms that are based on the assumption that a database of expected throughput for a given location of all networks is available. The first algorithm uses an analytical formulation of the handover problem to determine the optimal sequence of handovers within a time window, which is computationally feasible for up to 3-4 handovers within the window. The second algorithm is a heuristic algorithm, which is computationally feasible for any reasonable number of handovers within the window. We have used simulations to obtain the achieved throughput of these algorithms for a mobile user in an urban scenario with ubiquitous cellular coverage and 250 WiFi APs/km2, and compared the results to a hysteresis-based greedy algorithm and the case of &#x0022;always cellular-connected&#x0022;. Our results show that the proposed look-ahead algorithms outperform the hysteresis-based and &#x0022;always cellular-connected&#x0022;, but also show that the look-ahead algorithms are highly dependent on accurate movement tracking and movement prediction systems. The heuristic algorithm is also shown to achieve the highest throughput for large look-ahead windows.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898048]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898048]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898048&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898048]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>90</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Spatial Diversity and Eigenspectra]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Schulze, Henrik]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Arrays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Eigenvalues and eigenfunctions]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading channels]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multipath channels]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We analyse the spatial diversity of a multipath fading process for a general geometrical base of a dense antenna array in the plane and characterise it by the eigenvalue spectrum of the spatial autocorrelation kernel. We show how this diversity spectrum can be calculated for any spatial fading statistics represented by the power azimuth spectrum (PAS). Numerically calculated diversity spectra help to optimise the geometry of the antenna array. They demonstrate that the diversity gain of a onedimensional uniform linear array may be very small for a PAS with small angular spread. Circular arrays turn out to be more robust. For a channel coded system, diversity spectra give useful hints to design the time interleaving depth which is necessary to exploit the diversity gain of the code.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897980]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897980]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897980&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897980]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>91</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On Spectrum Heterogeneity and Non-Sequential Spectrum Scanning]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Subramani, Siva;  Fan, Zhong;  Armour, Simon;  Kaleshi, Dritan]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cognitive radio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[GSM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Sensors]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wideband]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[One of the fundamental working principles of distributed cognitive radio networks is based on the ability of a cognitive radio to scan and estimate the spectrum bands available for transmission. The spectrum holes or white spaces that would be potentially available are envisaged to be noncontiguous frequency bands of different width distributed over a wide range of spectrum. The distinct characteristics of frequency bands - spectrum heterogeneity - should be included in the spectrum sensing and scanning process. This paper presents a set of non-sequential scanning techniques viz. the bidirectional, dual band and pseudorandom scanning methods to scan the wide spectrum bands. Performance analysis of the scanning techniques is extended to test in heterogeneous and diverse channel occupancy scenarios. The simulation results indicate that non-sequential scanning performs well even in heterogeneous spectrum conditions.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898997]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898997]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898997&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898997]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>92</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Storage-Aware Routing Protocol for the MobilityFirst Network Architecture]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Bhanage, Gautam;  Chanda, Abhishek;  Li, Jun;  Raychaudhuri, Dipankar]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Computer architecture]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Internet]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Routing protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Storage area networks]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents an overview of the storage-aware routing protocol proposed for the MobilityFirst network architecture being developed as a part of the NSF Future Internet Architecture (FIA) project. The storage-aware routing method described here is a generalized form of delay-tolerant network (DTN) intended to work seamlessly across both wired and wireless networks. An adaptive storage-aware routing algorithm (ASTAR) which uses a combination of short and long-term path quality metrics along with available buffer storage to make store vs. forward decisions at routers is described. Selected experimental trace-driven validation results are given for an example hybrid network incorporating wired backbones and heterogeneous radio access technologies. The proposed storage-aware routing algorithm under consideration is shown to provide significant capacity and performance gains for the mobile/wireless usage scenarios considered. It is further demonstrated that the ASTAR adaptation algorithm provides a unified mechanism for adjusting store/forward decisions in response to variations in path quality, available router storage and traffic levels, achieving up to 20% capacity improvement over baseline non-adaptive schemes.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898053]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898053]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898053&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898053]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>93</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Throughput maximization in cognitive radio with limited feedback in the interference-limited regime]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[He, YuanYuan;  Dey, Subhrakanti]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Base stations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quantization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radio transmitters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We consider a spectrum sharing scenario in a cognitive radio network where a secondary user (SU) shares a narrowband channel with N primary users (PU). We consider the problem of SU ergodic capacity maximization under individual peak interference constraints at the PU receivers, in the interference limited regime so that the SU transmit power constraint is not active. The novelty in this paper lies in considering quantized channel information at the SU transmitter, as opposed to the full channel state information (especially for the SU transmitter to PU receiver channels) assumption which is prevalent in the existing literature. To this end, we assume the existence of a central controller (termed as the cognitive radio (CR) network manager) which can obtain the full channel information about the SU transmitter to PU receivers (the interference channels g0i, i = 1, 2, . . . , N) from the PU base station and the SU transmitter to SU receiver channel information (g1) from the SU base station if necessary, via (possibly) fibre-optic links. We consider two different schemes: (1) Quantized Power Allocation (QPA) where the SU transmission power is quantized and (2) Quantized Rate Allocation (QRA) where the ratio g1/(maxi g0i) is quantized. The designed power or rate codebooks are then communicated a priori to SU transmitter and receivers. In real time, based on the full channel information of g0i (QPA) and g1, g0i (QRA) at the CR network manager, it forwards the corresponding quantization index to the SU transmitter via a finite-rate feedback link, which is then used to select the transmission power or rate. Approximate expressions for quantization thresholds and SU ergodic capacity with quantized feedback are developed as N -&#x003E; ? or L -&#x003E; ?. Numerical results are presented to show that only 4-6 bits of feedback can make the SU ergodic capacity with limited feedback approach the capacity with full channel information at SU transmitter.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898045]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898045]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898045&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898045]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>94</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Blind Compensation of I/Q Filter Imbalance in the LTE Downlink]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Petit, Michael;  Haselmayr, Werner;  Springer, Andreas]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Bandwidth]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Cutoff frequency]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Digital signal processing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Smoothing methods]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In direct conversion receivers differences of the analog components in the I- and the Q-branch lead to I/Q mismatch. Digital signal processing can be used to reduce the specification for the RF circuitry. In this paper we focus on the compensation of frequency dependent I/Q mismatch due to different cut-off frequencies of the lowpass filters. This mismatch, which is an issue due to the wide bandwidth used e. g. in LTE systems, is compensated with a second order statistic-based approach. The blind adaptive algorithm recovers a property of complex signals, called properness which is disturbed by the I/Q mismatch. The algorithm achieves a very good performance even with a mismatched upconversion stage. It is able to compensate cut-off differences higher than 10% and is independent of special pilot structures and Rayleigh fading channels.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898028]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898028]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898028&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898028]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>95</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Wireless M2M Communication Networks for Smart Grid Applications]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Wietfeld, C.;  Georg, H.;  Groening, S.;  Lewandowski, C.;  Mueller, C.;  Schmutzler, J.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[3G mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Antenna measurements]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Communication system security]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Logic gates]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Power system planning]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Smart grids]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Future Smart Grid applications rely on highly reliable and secure connectivity between various infrastructure components from utilities, grid operators and households in order to cover requirements on communications for smart metering and decentralized energy management including electric mobility. Therefore several approaches for communication infrastructures are currently discussed based on different architectural concepts including wired and wireless access and inhouse communication technologies. In this paper we provide an overview on wireless-enabled networking architectures and discuss two exemplary network planning approaches. On one hand, network planning algorithms for the neighbourhood area network (NAN) are introduced. On the other hand, we present results for an integrated, wireless network coverage-aware planning of public and private charge point locations. In addition we address in the paper the design and implementation of embedded, wirelessWeb Services to enable the efficient and reliable data exchange within distributed energy systems. The paper concludes with the comparison of two approaches for the optimal coding of energy-management-related SOAP messages.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898077]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898077]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898077&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898077]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>96</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Performance Analysis of a Framework for Multi-Interfaced Service Level Agreements on Mobile Devices]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Aijaz, Fahad;  Shaikh, Shuja Jamil;  Walke, Bernhard]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Computer architecture]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile handsets]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Performance analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Silicon]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Simple object access protocol]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Today, the service computing research is focusing on the ubiquitous and on-the-move availability of Internet applications as cloud services. As a result, the mobility is rapidly becoming an important requirement of the future. In addition to that, the integration of mobile and service computing domains enables the existing mobile devices to offer their resources as mobile Web Services (WS). For this reason, these mobile WS are expected to become ubiquitous, as they may be offered by any connected device. Previously, we presented a concept of protecting such mobile WS by using Service Level Agreements (SLA) on mobile devices, where we explained the four primary architectural components of the SLA framework and classified their functions into four fundamental life cycles. In continuation of that, here, we present the detailed performance analysis of the SLA framework, while taking into account the SOAP and REST service access interfaces. Our processing analysis shows the percentage increase due to the SLA overhead compared to the normal unprotected mobile WS. These results are used to evaluate several parameters within the performance metric of the synchronous and asynchronous mobile WS architectures.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897975]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897975]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897975&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897975]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>97</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Dynamic Relay Selection and Resource Allocation in Cooperative Networks Based on OFDM]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Javidbakht, Omid;  Alizadeh, Navid Naderi;  Razavizadeh, S. Mohammad]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Optimization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Relays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we are planning to introduce a new method for relay selection and resource allocation in OFDM-based cooperative networks. Up to now, there have been relatively few works clearly concentrating on the combination of relay selection and resource allocation in such networks. In our work, a network with a single transmitter, a single receiver and a group of relays is considered. Relays work on Amplify and Forward (AF) method and there is no direct link between the transmitter and the receiver. The optimization problem is to maximize the throughput of the receiver with constraints on the amounts of the power of the transmitter and relays, and subcarriers. We will introduce an algorithm to select the best relay for each subcarrier. Eventually, we will compare our results to the optimum results and see how our proposed scheme, while being simple, performs very close to the optimum one.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898025]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898025]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898025&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898025]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>98</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Normalized covariance matrix quantization for MIMO broadcast systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Schober, Karol;  Maeaettaenen, Helka-Liina;  Tirkkonen, Olav;  Wichman, Risto]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Array signal processing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Covariance matrix]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Eigenvalues and eigenfunctions]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Quantization]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receivers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[We propose Eigen quantization as an alternative to normalized channel covariance matrix Direct quantization. The normalized covariance matrix is decomposed into the eigenspace and the eigenvalues that are quantized separately. We provide theoretical cumulative density function of normalized ordered eigenvalues for case of two eigenvalues. In addition, we propose an improved method of cumulative density function (CDF) quantization. We show that with Generalized Eigenvector (GE) precoding and Nt = Nr = 2, Improved Direct quantization performs slightly better than Eigen quantization. Contrary, when Nt = 4,Nr = 2 Eigen quantization is superior.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897993]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897993]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897993&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897993]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>99</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Virtual Soft Handover Method Based on Base Station Cooperation with Fountain Codes]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Liao, Qi;  Liao, Qi;  Kaliszan, Micha?;  Sta?czak, S?awomir;  Sta?czak, S?awomir]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Encoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Modulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Switches]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper we propose a virtual soft handover method in uplink based on a coding scheme that combines BS cooperation with fountain codes to achieve the seamless handover. Two protocols are investigated and their performances of average throughput are compared: (I) conventional Automatic Repeat reQuest (ARQ) protocol with Threshold-Based Adaptive Modulation and Coding (TB-AMC) scheme, (II) BS Cooperation with Fountain Codes (BCFC) protocol with fixed Modulation and Coding (MC) mode. Theoretical analysis and numerical results show that, there exists a region near the cell edge, where Protocol II outperforms Protocol I by offering more stable QoS of throughput. Defining the beneficial region as Virtual Soft Handover (VSHO) region, we calculate the bound of VSHO region characterized by average received SINR. An algorithm is designed by switching the system to Protocol II once the users enter the VSHO region and switching back to Protocol I when they leave the region. The parameters which affect the performance improvement in VSHO region include average received SINR and MC modes characterized by error performance estimation parameters.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898032]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898032]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898032&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898032]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>100</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Upper Bound Cell Spectral Efficiency of IMT-Advanced Scenarios]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Sambale, Klaus;  Walke, Bernhard]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Numerical models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Upper bound]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The International Telecommunication Union - Radio Group (ITU-R) has established a set of requirements to be met by candidate systems to be accepted as International Mobile Telecommunications - Advanced (IMT-A) compliant and has set up evaluation guidelines to asses compliance. In this paper, a numerical model following these guidelines is introduced to determine the upper bound cell spectral efficiency of Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiple Access (OFDMA) systems. In the model rate fair scheduling of concurrent Mobile Stations (MSs) and constant transmit power is assumed. The numerical results when compared to the IMT-A requirements show that the requirements can be met in general only by using Multiple Input Multiple Output (MIMO) transmission and a high degree of coordination between adjacent cells.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898017]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898017]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898017&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898017]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>101</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Implementation Aspects of Channel Estimation for 3GPP LTE Terminals]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Simko, Michal;  Wu, Di;  Mehlfuehrer, Christian;  Eilert, Johan;  Liu, Dake]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Complexity theory]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Hardware]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, hardware implementation aspects of the channel estimator in 3GPP LTE terminals are investigated. A channel estimation ASIC, which handles the real-time channel estimation, is presented. Compared to traditional correlator-based channel estimators, the channel estimator presented boosts the throughput at feasible silicon cost by adopting a recently proposed estimation method named Approximate Linear Minimum Mean Square Error (ALMMSE). In this paper, both the architecture and VLSI implementation of the estimator are elaborated. Implemented using a 65nm CMOS process, the channel estimator supports the full 20MHz bandwidth of 3GPP LTE and consumes only 49 kgates.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897996]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897996]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897996&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897996]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>102</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Cognitive Beam Design and Transmit Power Control for Cognitive Radio Networks in Time-varying Channels]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Yu, Heejung;  Lee, Sok-kyu]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Cognitive beamforming is an attractive method for a secondary system to share the spectrum which originally allocated to a primary system with a constraint of interference temperature. If the perfect information about an interfering channel from a secondary transmitter to a primary receiver is available, the secondary interference at a primary receiver can be perfectly pre-nullified by choosing a transmit beam spanning in the null space of an interfering channel matrix. In practice, the perfect channel state information (CSI) is not available due to estimation error and temporal variation of channel. Especially, time-varying channel makes interference increasing monotonically ,with the transmission time. In this paper, the interference power which is a function of fading rate and transmission time is analyzed based on the Gauss-Markov channel model. By using this analysis, a transmit power control scheme for a secondary transmitter employing cognitive beamforming is proposed. Through numerical results, the analysis and performance of the proposed scheme are verified and evaluated.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898002]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898002]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898002&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898002]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>103</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Energy Efficiency Evaluation of State of the Art Packet Scheduling algorithms for LTE]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Sabella, Dario;  Caretti, Marco;  Fantini, Roberto]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Algorithm design and analysis]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Energy efficiency]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Measurement]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Radio frequency]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Round robin]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[4]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this contribution, the performance of LTE system with various scheduling algorithm taken from the literature are considered. In order to assess the performance of state of the art schedulers a dynamic system level simulator is used that models in details all the features of the downlink of an LTE system in a multi-cell environment. The simulator will be used to analyze the impact of different scheduling policies from an energy efficiency point of view, considering different traffic models. In particular the first step involves analyzing the performances of SOTA algorithms, because up to now these schedulers have been compared from a more traditional point of view (e. g. SE, spectral efficiency) and not for the energy efficiency (EE) evaluation.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898063]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898063]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898063&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898063]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>104</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Cooperative Indoor Position Location Using Reflected Estimations]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Thompson, Benton;  Buehrer, R. Michael]]></authors>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Indoor positioning has become a hot research topic due to a plethora of interesting applications ranging from emergency responder tracking to location-based services. In this work we focus on the problem of network localization, sometimes called collaborative localization, where a network of nodes is to be localized using both connections to anchors (when they exist) and connections between unlocalized nodes. The fast and efficient IPPM algorithm developed in T. Jia, R. Buehrer, &#x0022;A set-theoretic approach to collaborative position location for wireless networks&#x0022;, performs well in most situations. However, it suffers from the existence of local, non-global minima which cause large localization error. In this work, we propose a technique for identifying and mitigating local minima errors, and we show that both non-collaborative and collaborative position location estimates can be greatly improved using our method.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898080]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898080]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898080&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898080]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>105</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Analytical Evaluation of an IMT-Advanced Compliant LTE System Level Simulator]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Muehleisen, Maciej;  Bueltmann, Daniel;  Schoenen, Rainer;  Walke, Bernhard]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Analytical models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Simulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[LTE-Advanced (LTE-A) proposed by the 3rd Generation Partnership Project (3GPP) has been accepted by the International Telecommunication Union (ITU) in 2010 as an IMT-Advanced (IMT-A) compliant 4G mobile radio system. As part of this application 3GPP has provided LTE-A system level simulation results for cell spectral efficiency and cell edge user spectral efficiency. In this work we analytically derive the spectral efficiency, throughput distribution, and cell edge user spectral efficiency for LTE-A in an IMT-A scenario and validate it by comparison to system level simulation results gained from the openWNS simulator. The method used can also be applied to estimate performance gains of protocol improvements.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898000]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898000]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898000&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898000]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>106</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A clustering technique for blind equalization of MIMO frequency selective channels]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ammari, Mohamed L.;  Belkacem, Oussama B.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Adaptive equalizers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Blind equalizers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Clustering algorithms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Convergence]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decision feedback equalizers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we propose a blind equalizer for the MIMO frequency selective channels. The proposed equalizer, called the Least Mean Squares soft decision-directed equalizer, consists of a blind clustering algorithm piloted by the soft decisions at its output. The equalizer taps are updated by maximizing the a posteriori probability density function of the equalized signal. The performances of the proposed equalizer are compared to those of the modified Constant Modulus algorithm and to those of the dual-mode modified Constant Modulus algorithm MCMA+DD-MIMO. Simulation results show that the proposed equalizer has a lower residual MSE than the other simulated algorithms.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897979]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897979]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897979&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897979]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>107</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Disruption Tolerant Connectivity Service for ITS Applications Using IEEE 802.11p]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Paulin, Thomas;  Bessler, Sandford]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Antenna measurements]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Containers]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Delay]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Payloads]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Peer to peer computing]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Protocols]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Vehicles]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[7]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This work addresses the intermittent connectivity observed in a vehicular ad hoc network and proposes a Disruption Tolerant Network (DTN) service that is shown to degrade gracefully in case of bad channel conditions or load increase, if compared to plain datagram transmission case. The considered infrastructure is a mesh network of road side units (RSUs) forming an overlay in which data can be stored, replicated and disseminated. The vehicles arriving in a RSU range open communication dialogs, using IEEE 802.11p WAVE Short Messages, however these dialogs may be interrupted by packet losses due to channel condition or mobility. The resulted intermittent connectivity lasts from seconds to several minutes. This paper gives an insight into the design of a seamless and efficient disruption tolerance mechanism and discusses the trade-offs in managing storage and processing resources in the infrastructure nodes. The performance of DTN and non-DTN operation is compared. In order to evaluate the performance of the DTN system in terms of successful transactions, we use real-world traces from a field trial performed on the Austrian highway and feed them into the DTN system. The results are promising showing high cumulative throughput, good delay behavior and efficient use of storage resources.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898068]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898068]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898068&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898068]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>108</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Mobility Control for Machine-to-Machine LTE Systems]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Lee, Beom Hee;  Kim, Seong-Lyun]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Batteries]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Downlink]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Interference]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mobile communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[OFDM]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[5]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we propose an efficient mobility control algorithm in the downlink multi-cell orthogonal frequency division multiple access (OFDMA) system for co-channel interference reduction. Our scheme divides each cell into several areas. The mobile nodes in each area find their own optimal position according to their present location. Both the signal to interference plus noise ratio (SINR) and the capacity for each node are increased by the proposed mobility control algorithm. Simulation results say that, even when the frequency reuse factor (FRF) is equal to 1, the average capacity is improved after applying the mobility control algorithm, compared to existing partial frequency reuse (PFR) scheme.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898044]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898044]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898044&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898044]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>109</rank>

<title><![CDATA[LTE Rate Matching Performance with Code Block Balancing]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Ikuno, Josep Colom;  Schwarz, Stefan;  Michal Simko, -]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Channel coding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Decoding]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Degradation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Modulation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multiaccess communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[3]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, we compare the performance of the LTE rate matcher for different code rates when segmentation occurs. We present that, for certain cases of segmentation where the different segments are of dissimilar size, the rate applied to each segment may be different and thus degraded overall performance may occur. We show how a simple method which balances the code rate on a per-segment basis can improve the overall block error ratio performance. The whole simulation environment together with the results of this paper are made available for download at our homepage.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898024]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898024]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898024&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898024]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>110</rank>

<title><![CDATA[A Simple Multiuser MIMO-SDMA System in the Downlink Using Statistical Precoding]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Wang, Jue;  Jin, Shi;  Gao, Xiqi;  Wong, Kai-Kit]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Arrays]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Correlation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Discrete Fourier transforms]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[MIMO]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Multiaccess communication]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Throughput]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[This paper proposes a new space-division multiple-access (SDMA) approach for multiuser multiple-input multiple-output downlink systems using statistical precoding. The proposed scheme makes use of rotated discrete Fourier transform (DFT) matrices to realize spatial divisions, each of which defines a cluster within which users have their transmit-side eigenmodes aligning closely with a common rotated DFT matrix. Users inside a cluster are divided into groups, and users exhibiting orthogonal eigen-directions are put in the same group realizing SDMA. It is shown that the proposed scheme can greatly enhance the average system throughput if compared with time-division multiple-access, especially when transmit-side correlation is high. Meanwhile, the proposed scheme outperformances traditional linear precoding schemes such as zero forcing when the feedback bits for the channel state information are limited.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5897978]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5897978]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5897978&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5897978]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>111</rank>

<title><![CDATA[On the Role of the Scattering Environment and the Antenna Parameters on the Quality of MIMO Channel Prediction]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Primak, Serguei L.]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Equations]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Estimation]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Mathematical model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Receiving antennas]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Scattering]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[The main objective of this paper is to investigate the effect of the number of antennas and scattering geometry on the predictability of multiple-input multiple-output (MIMO) channels. It is shown that the number of transmit and receive antennas has opposite effect on the predictability. It is also demonstrated, that the angular size of scattering clusters has a significant effect on the quality of the one step prediction.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898067]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898067]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898067&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898067]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>112</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Information Transmission over a Finite-Lifetime Channel under Energy-Constraints]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Goertz, Norbert;  Gonter, Johannes]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Adaptation model]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Channel models]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Fading]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Random processes]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Resource management]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Signal to noise ratio]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Transmitters]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[In this work we investigate the limits on information-transmission in the finite-lifetime channel. We derive an upper bound for the information that can be transmitted, and we introduce an optimum acausal scheme for power-allocation. Furthermore, we introduce more practical but nevertheless efficient schemes for allocating power, and we compare their performance with the optimum scheme in a vehicle-to-vehicle communication scenario.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898014]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898014]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898014&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898014]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>113</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Improved Animal Tracking Algorithms Using Distributed Kalman-based Filters]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Dopico, Nelson I.;  Bejar, Benjamin;  Macua, Sergio Valcarcel;  Belanovic, Pavle;  Zazo, Santiago]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Animals]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Global Positioning System]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Hardware]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Joints]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Kalman filters]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Noise]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Target tracking]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[8]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Animal tracking has been addressed by different initiatives over the last two decades. Most of them rely on satellite connectivity on every single node and lack of energy-saving strategies. This paper presents several new contributions on the tracking of dynamic heterogeneous asynchronous networks (primary nodes with GPS and secondary nodes with a kinetic generator) motivated by the animal tracking paradigm with random transmissions. A simple approach based on connectivity and coverage intersection is compared with more sophisticated algorithms based on ad-hoc implementations of distributed Kalman-based filters that integrate measurement information using Consensus principles in order to provide enhanced accuracy. Several simulations varying the coverage range, the random behavior of the kinetic generator (modeled as a Poisson Process) and the periodic activation of GPS are included. In addition, this study is enhanced with HW developments and implementations on commercial off-the-shelf equipment which show the feasibility for performing these proposals on real hardware.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898066]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898066]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898066&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898066]]></pdf>

</document>

<document>

<rank>114</rank>

<title><![CDATA[Latency for Real-Time Machine-to-Machine Communication in LTE-Based System Architecture]]></title>

<authors><![CDATA[Nikaein, Navid;  Krea, Srdjan]]></authors>

<thesaurusterms>

<term><![CDATA[Decision support systems]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Europe]]></term>

<term><![CDATA[Wireless communication]]></term>

</thesaurusterms>

<pubtitle><![CDATA[Wireless Conference 2011 - Sustainable Wireless Technologies (European Wireless), 11th European]]></pubtitle>

<punumber><![CDATA[5897968]]></punumber>

<pubtype><![CDATA[Conference Publications]]></pubtype>

<publisher><![CDATA[VDE]]></publisher>

<py><![CDATA[2011]]></py>

<spage><![CDATA[1]]></spage>

<epage><![CDATA[6]]></epage>

<abstract><![CDATA[Machine-to-machine communication has attracted a lot of interest in the mobile communication industry and is under standardization process in 3GPP. Of particular interest is LTE-Advanced support for various M2M service requirements and efficient management and handling of a huge number of machines as mobile subscribers. In addition to the higher throughput, one of the main advantages of LTE/LTE-A in comparison with the previous cellular networks is the reduced transmission latency, which makes this type of networks very attractive for real-time mobile M2M communication scenarios. This paper presents a M2M system architecture based on LTE/LTE-A and highlights the delays associated with each part of the system. Three real-time M2M applications are analyzed and the main latency bottlenecks are identified. Proposals on how the latency can be further reduced are described.]]></abstract>

<isbn><![CDATA[978-3-8007-3343-9]]></isbn>

<arnumber><![CDATA[5898065]]></arnumber>

<publicationId><![CDATA[5898065]]></publicationId>

<mdurl><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&arnumber=5898065&contentType=Conference+Publications]]></mdurl>

<pdf><![CDATA[http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=5898065]]></pdf>

</document>

</root>
